<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-03-19T01:53:16+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DJBSec, CISSP</title><subtitle>DJBSec is an IT veteran with over 25 years of experience in IT and Cyber Security </subtitle><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-19-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0319/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-19-25"/><published>2025-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0319</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0319/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-03-19-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="story-1-google-acquires-wiz-for-record-32-billion-in-largest-cybersecurity-deal-ever">Story 1. Google Acquires Wiz for Record $32 Billion in Largest Cybersecurity Deal Ever</h2> <p>Google has announced the acquisition of cloud security firm Wiz for a record-breaking $32 billion, making it the largest cybersecurity deal in history. Wiz, known for its advanced cloud-native security platform, helps companies identify and mitigate vulnerabilities across multi-cloud environments. This acquisition strengthens Google Cloud’s security offerings and positions it as a leading player in the cloud security market. Analysts expect this move to intensify competition with Microsoft and AWS in the cybersecurity space.<br/> <a href="https://hackread.com/google-acquires-wiz-for-record-32-billion/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-2-scammers-distribute-ad-fraud-apps-with-60-million-downloads-on-google-play">Story 2. Scammers Distribute Ad Fraud Apps with 60 Million Downloads on Google Play</h2> <p>Security researchers have uncovered a large-scale ad fraud scheme involving dozens of malicious Android apps with over 60 million downloads from Google Play. These apps secretly performed ad fraud in the background, draining user data and device resources while generating illegal revenue for scammers. Google has since removed the fraudulent apps, but many users remain affected. Experts advise Android users to carefully review app permissions and avoid downloading unknown applications.<br/> <a href="https://hackread.com/scammers-ad-fraud-apps-google-play-60m-downloads/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-3-critical-vulnerability-in-ami-megarac-bmc-allows-server-takeover">Story 3. Critical Vulnerability in AMI MegaRAC BMC Allows Server Takeover</h2> <p>A newly disclosed vulnerability in AMI MegaRAC Baseboard Management Controllers (BMC) could allow attackers to take over servers remotely. This critical flaw affects data centers and cloud infrastructure, posing a serious risk to enterprises using the vulnerable technology. Attackers could exploit the flaw to gain root access, disrupt operations, or install persistent backdoors. Organizations are urged to patch affected systems immediately to mitigate the risk of exploitation.<br/> <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3848376/critical-vulnerability-in-ami-megarac-bmc-allows-servers-takeover.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-4-infostealer-malware-attacks-surged-in-2024-flashpoint-report-finds">Story 4. InfoStealer Malware Attacks Surged in 2024, Flashpoint Report Finds</h2> <p>A new report from Flashpoint reveals that infostealer malware attacks surged throughout 2024, with cybercriminals increasingly targeting login credentials, financial data, and personal information. These malware strains, often delivered via phishing campaigns and malicious downloads, have been a primary driver of account takeovers and identity theft. The report highlights how the dark web marketplace for stolen data is fueling cybercrime. Security experts recommend enabling multi-factor authentication (MFA) and using endpoint detection tools to defend against these threats.<br/> <a href="https://cyberscoop.com/infostealers-cybercrime-surged-2024-flashpoint/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-5-nation-state-actors-and-cybercrime-gangs-abusing-malicious-lnk-files">Story 5. Nation-State Actors and Cybercrime Gangs Abusing Malicious LNK Files</h2> <p>Threat intelligence reports indicate that both state-sponsored hackers and cybercriminal gangs are increasingly using malicious LNK (Windows shortcut) files to distribute malware. These files, often disguised as legitimate documents, enable attackers to execute code remotely, steal sensitive information, and establish persistence on compromised systems. Recent campaigns have leveraged this technique for espionage, ransomware, and data exfiltration. Organizations are advised to restrict LNK execution in email attachments and implement strict security controls.<br/> <a href="https://securityaffairs.com/175569/apt/nation-state-actors-and-cybercrime-gangs-abuse-malicious-lnk-files-for-espionage-and-data-theft.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-6-black-basta-ransomware-gangs-leaked-chat-logs-reveal-ties-to-russian-officials">Story 6. Black Basta Ransomware Gang’s Leaked Chat Logs Reveal Ties to Russian Officials</h2> <p>Leaked internal chat logs from the Black Basta ransomware gang suggest connections to Russian government officials. The logs reveal discussions about attack strategies, ransom negotiations, and possible state protection for cybercriminal activities. If confirmed, these findings further link ransomware operations to Russian intelligence services. This leak may provide valuable intelligence for law enforcement agencies investigating ransomware networks.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/threat-intelligence/black-basta-league-russian-officials-chat-logs">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-7-8-year-old-windows-shortcut-zero-day-exploited-in-recent-attacks">Story 7. 8-Year-Old Windows Shortcut Zero-Day Exploited in Recent Attacks</h2> <p>A newly discovered cyberattack campaign is exploiting an 8-year-old zero-day vulnerability in Windows shortcut (LNK) files. Despite Microsoft’s past attempts to mitigate such threats, attackers have found new ways to weaponize the flaw, allowing them to execute malicious code with minimal user interaction. The vulnerability is being actively exploited in targeted attacks against businesses and government entities. Security researchers recommend disabling shortcut execution for untrusted sources and applying available patches.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/8-year-old-windows-shortcut-zero-day/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-8-bybit-hack-a-sophisticated-multi-stage-attack-compromised-cryptocurrency-exchange">Story 8. Bybit Hack: A Sophisticated Multi-Stage Attack Compromised Cryptocurrency Exchange</h2> <p>The recent cyberattack on the Bybit cryptocurrency exchange involved a sophisticated multi-stage intrusion that allowed attackers to steal millions in digital assets. Hackers leveraged social engineering, zero-day exploits, and advanced obfuscation techniques to bypass security measures. Bybit has since tightened its security protocols, but the breach highlights the growing risks for crypto exchanges. Users are advised to enable two-factor authentication and use hardware wallets for enhanced security.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/bybit-hack-sophisticated-multi-stage-attack/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-9-chatgpt-ssrf-bug-becomes-a-favorite-attack-vector-for-hackers">Story 9. ChatGPT SSRF Bug Becomes a Favorite Attack Vector for Hackers</h2> <p>Hackers have quickly adopted a newly discovered Server-Side Request Forgery (SSRF) vulnerability in ChatGPT, exploiting it in real-world attacks. The flaw, CVE-2025-XXXX, allows attackers to manipulate AI-generated responses and access restricted internal services. Cybercriminals are using this technique to extract sensitive data and bypass security measures in AI-integrated platforms. OpenAI and security experts are working on a fix, but organizations using AI-powered applications should monitor for suspicious activity.<br/> <a href="https://securityaffairs.com/175560/hacking/chatgpt-ssrf-bug-quickly-becomes-a-favorite-attack-vector.html">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[3-19-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-18-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0318/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-18-25"/><published>2025-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0318</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0318/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-03-18-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="story-1-oauth-attacks-target-microsoft-365-and-github-accounts">Story 1. OAuth Attacks Target Microsoft 365 and GitHub Accounts</h2> <p>Cybercriminals are exploiting OAuth vulnerabilities to compromise Microsoft 365 and GitHub accounts. Attackers use fraudulent third-party applications to trick users into granting excessive permissions, enabling access to sensitive emails, repositories, and cloud resources. Once authorized, these apps can be used for data exfiltration and further phishing attacks. Security experts recommend reviewing OAuth app permissions regularly and restricting access to trusted applications only.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/oauth-attacks-target-microsoft-365-github">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-2-new-steganographic-malware-attack-hides-code-inside-jpg-files">Story 2. New Steganographic Malware Attack Hides Code Inside JPG Files</h2> <p>A newly discovered steganographic malware campaign is using image files to conceal malicious payloads. Attackers embed malware within seemingly harmless JPG images, which execute code when opened on a compromised device. This method allows cybercriminals to evade traditional antivirus detection while delivering remote access trojans (RATs) or keyloggers. Users are advised to avoid downloading images from untrusted sources and keep their security software updated.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/new-steganographic-malware-attack-via-jpg-file/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-3-chinese-volt-typhoon-hackers-exploiting-cisco-and-netgear-routers">Story 3. Chinese Volt Typhoon Hackers Exploiting Cisco and Netgear Routers</h2> <p>The Chinese state-sponsored hacking group Volt Typhoon has been observed exploiting vulnerabilities in Cisco and Netgear routers. These compromised devices are being used as stepping stones for cyber-espionage campaigns targeting critical infrastructure. By hijacking consumer and enterprise networking equipment, the attackers can evade detection and establish persistent access. Security experts recommend updating router firmware and disabling remote management features.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/chinese-volt-typhoon-hackers-exploiting-cisco-netgear-routers/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-4-attackers-use-css-to-create-evasive-phishing-messages">Story 4. Attackers Use CSS to Create Evasive Phishing Messages</h2> <p>A new phishing technique leverages Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) to evade email security filters and trick users into revealing credentials. By embedding malicious payloads in CSS files, attackers can create emails that bypass spam detection while appearing legitimate. This method makes phishing campaigns harder to detect and block. Experts advise users to verify email senders, avoid clicking on suspicious links, and enable multi-factor authentication (MFA).<br/> <a href="https://securityaffairs.com/175512/security/attackers-use-css-to-create-evasive-phishing-messages.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-5-23000-github-repositories-targeted-in-large-scale-supply-chain-attack">Story 5. 23,000 GitHub Repositories Targeted in Large-Scale Supply Chain Attack</h2> <p>A massive cyberattack campaign has targeted over 23,000 GitHub repositories, injecting malicious code into open-source projects. The attackers use dependency hijacking and repository takeover techniques to compromise software supply chains. Developers who unknowingly use infected dependencies may expose their applications to backdoors and data breaches. Security professionals recommend verifying package integrity and implementing strict repository security controls.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/23000-github-repositories-targeted/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-6-toll-road-text-message-scam-spreads-nationwide">Story 6. Toll Road Text Message Scam Spreads Nationwide</h2> <p>A phishing scam disguised as toll road payment notifications has been spreading rapidly across the U.S. Victims receive fraudulent text messages claiming they owe unpaid tolls, leading them to fake payment portals that steal financial details. Authorities warn that these scams are highly sophisticated and designed to mimic official transportation agencies. Drivers are advised to verify toll charges through official state websites and never click on unsolicited payment links.<br/> <a href="https://cyberscoop.com/toll-road-text-message-scam-swells-nationwide-how-to-stop/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-7-hackers-exploit-chatgpt-vulnerability-cve-2024-27564-in-10000-attacks">Story 7. Hackers Exploit ChatGPT Vulnerability CVE-2024-27564 in 10,000 Attacks</h2> <p>Threat actors have been exploiting a newly disclosed vulnerability, CVE-2024-27564, in ChatGPT-related APIs, enabling them to conduct over 10,000 attacks. This security flaw allows attackers to manipulate AI-generated responses, steal user data, and bypass content restrictions. Organizations integrating AI services are at risk of data leakage and misinformation attacks. Security experts recommend applying patches immediately and monitoring AI interactions for suspicious activity.<br/> <a href="https://hackread.com/hackers-exploit-chatgpt-cve-2024-27564-10000-attacks/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-8-free-online-file-converters-are-installing-malware-on-users-devices">Story 8. Free Online File Converters Are Installing Malware on Users’ Devices</h2> <p>Security researchers have found that many free online file conversion tools are secretly installing malware on users’ devices. These fraudulent sites trick users into uploading files for conversion while delivering hidden malware payloads in return. The malware includes spyware, keyloggers, and adware that compromise system security. Users are encouraged to use trusted software for file conversions and avoid suspicious websites.<br/> <a href="https://www.malwarebytes.com/blog/news/2025/03/warning-over-free-online-file-converters-that-actually-install-malware">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[3-18-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-17-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0317/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-17-25"/><published>2025-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0317</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0317/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-03-17-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="story-1-100-auto-dealers-hacked-through-a-clickfix-webpage">Story 1. 100 Auto Dealers Hacked Through a ClickFix Webpage</h2> <p>A cyberattack leveraging the ClickFix exploit has compromised 100 auto dealerships, allowing hackers to install malware remotely. The attackers used a malicious webpage to trick employees into clicking a fraudulent fix, which led to network-wide infections. This breach resulted in system outages, stolen customer data, and financial losses. Security experts urge companies to verify update sources and train employees on recognizing phishing tactics.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/100-auto-dealers-hacked-with-a-clickfix-webpage/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-2-malicious-pypi-packages-stole-cloud-credentials-from-developers">Story 2. Malicious PyPI Packages Stole Cloud Credentials from Developers</h2> <p>Security researchers uncovered multiple malicious Python packages on the PyPI repository designed to steal cloud credentials from unsuspecting developers. These packages, disguised as legitimate tools, exfiltrated AWS and Google Cloud API keys upon installation. The campaign highlights the persistent threat of supply chain attacks on software development ecosystems. Developers are advised to scrutinize open-source dependencies and use credential managers to protect sensitive information.<br/> <a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/03/malicious-pypi-packages-stole-cloud.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-3-deepseek-r1-ai-model-jailbroken-to-bypass-content-restrictions">Story 3. DeepSeek R1 AI Model Jailbroken to Bypass Content Restrictions</h2> <p>Hackers have successfully jailbroken the DeepSeek R1 AI model, bypassing its built-in content restrictions. This exploit allows users to generate outputs that violate ethical guidelines, including misinformation and restricted content. The discovery raises concerns about the security of AI models and their susceptibility to manipulation. AI developers are urged to implement stronger security measures to prevent unauthorized modifications.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/deepseek-r1-jailbreaked/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-4-new-massjacker-clipper-malware-targets-users-downloading-pirated-software">Story 4. New MassJacker Clipper Malware Targets Users Downloading Pirated Software</h2> <p>A new malware strain, dubbed “MassJacker,” is spreading through pirated software downloads, targeting cryptocurrency users. This clipper malware silently replaces copied crypto wallet addresses with those controlled by attackers, leading to stolen funds. The campaign primarily affects users looking for cracked software, reinforcing the dangers of downloading from untrusted sources. Experts advise against using pirated software and recommend keeping antivirus programs updated.<br/> <a href="https://securityaffairs.com/175433/malware/new-massjacker-clipper-targets-pirated-software-seekers.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-5-malicious-adobe--docusign-oauth-apps-target-microsoft-365-accounts">Story 5. Malicious Adobe &amp; DocuSign OAuth Apps Target Microsoft 365 Accounts</h2> <p>Cybercriminals are using fake Adobe and DocuSign OAuth apps to compromise Microsoft 365 accounts. These malicious applications trick users into granting permissions, allowing attackers to access emails, documents, and cloud storage. Once inside, hackers can exfiltrate sensitive data and launch further phishing attacks. Organizations should review OAuth permissions regularly and educate employees on identifying suspicious login requests.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/malicious-adobe-docusign-oauth-apps-target-microsoft-365-accounts/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-6-fake-security-alerts-on-github-use-oauth-apps-to-hijack-accounts">Story 6. Fake Security Alerts on GitHub Use OAuth Apps to Hijack Accounts</h2> <p>Attackers are leveraging fake security alerts on GitHub to trick developers into authorizing malicious OAuth applications. These fake alerts warn users of security issues and prompt them to grant permissions to a compromised app, leading to account takeovers. Once access is gained, attackers can modify repositories, inject malicious code, and steal sensitive data. Developers should verify security warnings directly through GitHub settings and avoid clicking on unsolicited links.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/fake-security-alert-issues-on-github-use-oauth-app-to-hijack-accounts/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-7-denmark-warns-of-increased-state-sponsored-attacks-on-european-telecoms">Story 7. Denmark Warns of Increased State-Sponsored Attacks on European Telecoms</h2> <p>Danish authorities have issued a warning about rising state-sponsored cyber campaigns targeting European telecommunications providers. Intelligence officials suspect nation-state actors, particularly from Russia and China, are attempting to infiltrate telecom networks for espionage and disruption purposes. These attacks pose a significant risk to critical infrastructure, including mobile networks and internet services. Telecom companies are urged to enhance cybersecurity measures and monitor for advanced persistent threats.<br/> <a href="https://securityaffairs.com/175479/intelligence/denmark-warns-of-increased-state-sponsored-campaigns-targeting-the-european-telcos.html">Read more here</a> ```</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[3-17-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-7-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0307/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-7-25"/><published>2025-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0307</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0307/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-03-07-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="story-1-the-future-of-cybersecurity-lies-in-governance-not-more-tools">Story 1. The Future of Cybersecurity Lies in Governance, Not More Tools</h2> <p>Experts argue that cybersecurity strategies must shift from an over-reliance on security tools to stronger governance and risk management. While new technologies can help detect threats, they cannot replace structured policies, user education, and clear accountability. Organizations need to prioritize proactive security governance, including regulatory compliance and incident response planning. A well-implemented governance framework can significantly reduce cybersecurity risks and improve long-term resilience.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyber-risk/cybersecurity-future-governance-not-more-tools">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-2-researchers-bypass-crowdstrike-falcon-sensor-exposing-detection-weakness">Story 2. Researchers Bypass CrowdStrike Falcon Sensor, Exposing Detection Weakness</h2> <p>Security researchers have demonstrated a method to bypass CrowdStrike’s Falcon Sensor, an advanced endpoint detection and response (EDR) tool. The exploit allows attackers to evade detection and execute malicious code undetected. While CrowdStrike is investigating the bypass technique, the findings raise concerns about the effectiveness of security solutions in stopping sophisticated attacks. Experts recommend using multiple layers of security rather than relying on a single detection tool.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/researchers-bypassed-crowdstrike-falcon-sensor/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-3-deepfake-videos-on-youtube-used-to-phish-content-creators">Story 3. Deepfake Videos on YouTube Used to Phish Content Creators</h2> <p>Cybercriminals are using deepfake videos on YouTube to target content creators with phishing scams. The attackers create fake videos featuring AI-generated influencers promoting fraudulent sponsorship deals, tricking victims into downloading malware. Once installed, the malware steals login credentials and financial information. Security professionals urge YouTube users to verify sponsorships and avoid downloading files from untrusted sources.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/remote-workforce/deepfake-videos-youtube-phish-creators">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-4-invoke-adcheck-a-new-powershell-based-tool-used-for-cyber-attacks">Story 4. Invoke-ADCheck: A New PowerShell-Based Tool Used for Cyber Attacks</h2> <p>Hackers are leveraging a newly discovered PowerShell tool called Invoke-ADCheck to automate reconnaissance on Active Directory environments. This tool allows attackers to gather information about domain controllers, user privileges, and security policies before launching further attacks. While it was originally developed for security auditing, malicious actors have started weaponizing it. Organizations are encouraged to monitor PowerShell execution logs and restrict unnecessary administrative access.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/invokeadcheck-powershell-based-tool/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-5-microsoft-365-apps-to-prompt-users-to-back-up-files-in-onedrive">Story 5. Microsoft 365 Apps to Prompt Users to Back Up Files in OneDrive</h2> <p>Microsoft is introducing a new feature in Microsoft 365 apps that will prompt users to back up their files to OneDrive. The goal is to prevent data loss due to ransomware attacks, hardware failures, or accidental deletions. Users will receive proactive notifications encouraging them to enable automatic backups for critical files. This move aligns with Microsoft’s broader efforts to enhance cloud-based security and data protection.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/microsoft/microsoft-365-apps-will-prompt-users-to-back-up-files-in-onedrive/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-6-ethereum-private-key-stealer-on-pypi-downloaded-over-1000-times">Story 6. Ethereum Private Key Stealer on PyPI Downloaded Over 1,000 Times</h2> <p>A malicious Python package on the PyPI repository was found stealing Ethereum private keys from unsuspecting developers. The package, which had over 1,000 downloads before removal, contained code designed to extract and transmit sensitive wallet data. This incident highlights the growing risk of supply chain attacks targeting open-source repositories. Developers are urged to verify package integrity before installation and avoid downloading unverified dependencies.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/ethereum-private-key-stealer-on-pypi-downloaded-over-1-000-times/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-7-ransomware-gang-used-a-webcam-to-bypass-edr-and-encrypt-a-network">Story 7. Ransomware Gang Used a Webcam to Bypass EDR and Encrypt a Network</h2> <p>A ransomware group found a creative way to bypass endpoint detection and response (EDR) tools by exploiting a vulnerable network-connected webcam. By using the device as an entry point, attackers were able to disable security defenses and encrypt the entire network. This attack underscores the importance of securing all connected devices, including IoT and peripheral hardware. Organizations should apply firmware updates and segment IoT devices to limit attack vectors.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/ransomware-gang-encrypted-network-from-a-webcam-to-bypass-edr/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-8-microsoft-reports-malvertising-campaign-impacted-over-1-million-pcs">Story 8. Microsoft Reports Malvertising Campaign Impacted Over 1 Million PCs</h2> <p>A large-scale malvertising campaign has compromised over 1 million PCs worldwide, according to Microsoft. Attackers used fraudulent advertisements on search engines and social media to distribute malware, tricking users into downloading infected software. Victims unknowingly installed malicious payloads that enabled remote access, data theft, and ransomware infections. Experts recommend using ad blockers and verifying software sources before downloading applications.<br/> <a href="http://bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/microsoft-says-malvertising-campaign-impacted-1-million-pcs/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-9-international-law-enforcement-seizes-major-ransomware-gangs">Story 9. International Law Enforcement Seizes Major Ransomware Gangs</h2> <p>A coordinated international law enforcement operation has led to the takedown of multiple ransomware gangs. Authorities seized infrastructure, arrested key members, and disrupted ransom payment channels used by cybercriminal organizations. The operation marks a significant victory in the global fight against ransomware, but experts warn that new groups may emerge to fill the void. Businesses are encouraged to strengthen cybersecurity measures to prevent future attacks.<br/> <a href="https://www.theregister.com/2025/03/06/international_cops_seize_ransomware_gangs/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-10-encrypthubs-opsec-failures-reveal-cybercriminal-tactics">Story 10. EncryptHub’s OPSEC Failures Reveal Cybercriminal Tactics</h2> <p>EncryptHub, a notorious cybercriminal marketplace, has suffered major operational security (OPSEC) failures, exposing its hacking tools and customer data. The leaks have provided law enforcement agencies with valuable intelligence on cybercriminal tactics and infrastructure. As a result, several ongoing investigations into ransomware groups and dark web operations have accelerated. The incident highlights the growing risks for cybercriminals operating in underground markets.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/threat-intelligence/encrypthub-opsec-failures-ttps-big-plans">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[3-7-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-6-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0306/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-6-25"/><published>2025-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0306</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0306/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-03-06-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="1-cybercriminals-now-launch-attacks-at-record-speed">1. Cybercriminals Now Launch Attacks at Record Speed</h2> <p>A new report highlights that cybercriminals are deploying attacks at unprecedented speeds, often compromising systems within minutes. Advanced automation tools and AI-driven techniques enable hackers to scan for vulnerabilities and exploit them rapidly. Security experts warn that traditional reactive defenses are no longer sufficient, urging organizations to implement proactive threat detection and response strategies. The increasing speed of cyberattacks underscores the importance of real-time monitoring and zero-trust security frameworks.<br/> <a href="https://cyberscoop.com/cybercriminals-record-speed-attacks-2024/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="2-vishing-attacks-increased-by-442-in-the-second-half-of-2024">2. Vishing Attacks Increased by 442% in the Second Half of 2024</h2> <p>Voice phishing, or “vishing,” attacks surged by 442% in late 2024, as cybercriminals exploited social engineering to deceive victims over the phone. Attackers impersonated IT support staff, financial institutions, and government agencies to trick individuals into divulging sensitive information. The rise in AI-powered voice cloning has made these attacks more convincing and difficult to detect. Security professionals advise organizations to implement strict identity verification protocols and educate employees on recognizing vishing scams.<br/> <a href="https://www.securitymagazine.com/articles/101439-vishing-attacks-increased-by-442-in-the-second-half-of-2024">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="3-taylor-swift-fans-targeted-in-massive-stubhub-ticket-theft">3. Taylor Swift Fans Targeted in Massive StubHub Ticket Theft</h2> <p>Cybercriminals have stolen thousands of Taylor Swift concert tickets from StubHub accounts, leaving fans locked out of their purchased events. The attackers used credential stuffing techniques, exploiting reused passwords from previous data breaches to gain access to accounts. Victims reported unauthorized ticket transfers, with resellers profiting from the stolen tickets on secondary markets. StubHub is urging users to enable two-factor authentication (2FA) and reset compromised passwords to prevent further losses.<br/> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/05/business/taylor-swift-tickets-stolen-stubhub.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="4-crafty-camel-apt-targets-aviation-industry-with-polyglot-malware">4. “Crafty Camel” APT Targets Aviation Industry with Polyglot Malware</h2> <p>A newly identified advanced persistent threat (APT) group, dubbed “Crafty Camel,” is targeting the aviation sector’s operational technology (OT) systems. The attackers use polyglot files—malware that can execute across multiple platforms—to evade detection and maintain persistence. This sophisticated attack method threatens flight operations, maintenance systems, and supply chain security. Security analysts recommend enhanced monitoring of aviation networks and strict access controls to mitigate the risk.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/ics-ot-security/crafty-camel-apt-aviation-ot-polygot-files">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="5-china-linked-silk-typhoon-apt-targets-it-supply-chains">5. China-Linked “Silk Typhoon” APT Targets IT Supply Chains</h2> <p>A Chinese cyber-espionage group known as “Silk Typhoon” has been targeting global IT supply chains, compromising managed service providers and software vendors. By infiltrating supply chains, the attackers gain indirect access to a wide range of businesses and government entities. Their techniques include exploiting zero-day vulnerabilities and deploying backdoors to maintain long-term access. Security experts warn that organizations must improve vendor risk assessments and enforce stricter supply chain security measures.<br/> <a href="https://securityaffairs.com/174962/apt/china-linked-apt-silk-typhoon-targets-it-supply-chain.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="6-us-indicts-chinese-nationals-for-espionage-linked-cyberattacks">6. U.S. Indicts Chinese Nationals for Espionage-Linked Cyberattacks</h2> <p>The U.S. Department of Justice has indicted multiple Chinese nationals for their involvement in cyber-espionage attacks targeting American companies and government agencies. The individuals allegedly conducted hacking campaigns on behalf of the Chinese government, stealing sensitive intellectual property and classified data. The indictment follows a years-long investigation into China-linked cyber threats against critical industries. Officials emphasize that the charges signal a growing international effort to combat state-sponsored cyber espionage.<br/> <a href="https://cyberscoop.com/chinese-nationals-indictments-espionage-attacks/">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[3-6-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-5-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0305/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-5-25"/><published>2025-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0305</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0305/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-03-05-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h1 id="cybersecurity-stories-summary">Cybersecurity Stories Summary</h1> <h3 id="story1-new-eleven11bot-botnet-infects-86000-devices-for-ddos-attacks">Story1. New Eleven11Bot Botnet Infects 86,000 Devices for DDoS Attacks</h3> <p>A newly discovered botnet, Eleven11Bot, has infected over 86,000 devices to launch large-scale Distributed Denial-of-Service (DDoS) attacks. The malware primarily targets routers, IoT devices, and unpatched servers, taking advantage of weak security settings. Security researchers warn that the botnet’s rapid growth could enable attackers to disrupt critical online services. Organizations and individuals are advised to update firmware, use strong passwords, and disable unnecessary remote access features to mitigate risks.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/new-eleven11bot-botnet-infects-86-000-devices-for-ddos-attacks/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story2-hackers-abusing-microsoft-teams-quick-assist-to-gain-remote-access">Story2. Hackers Abusing Microsoft Teams Quick Assist to Gain Remote Access</h3> <p>Cybercriminals are exploiting Microsoft Teams’ Quick Assist feature to gain unauthorized remote access to corporate networks. Attackers pose as IT support personnel, convincing victims to grant them control over their systems. Once inside, they deploy malware, steal sensitive data, or launch further attacks. Security experts recommend disabling Quick Assist for non-essential users and educating employees on recognizing social engineering threats.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/hackers-abusing-microsoft-teams-quick-assist/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story3-hackers-attacking-4000-isps-worldwide-in-coordinated-cyber-assault">Story3. Hackers Attacking 4,000 ISPs Worldwide in Coordinated Cyber Assault</h3> <p>A sophisticated cyberattack campaign has been detected targeting over 4,000 internet service providers (ISPs) across multiple countries. The attackers are exploiting vulnerabilities in ISP infrastructure to intercept traffic, steal data, and launch further cyberattacks. Researchers suspect that nation-state actors may be involved in these intrusions. Affected ISPs are urged to patch vulnerabilities and implement stronger network security controls to prevent further breaches.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/hackers-attacking-4000-isps/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story4-96-of-ransomware-incidents-now-involve-data-exfiltration">Story4. 96% of Ransomware Incidents Now Involve Data Exfiltration</h3> <p>A new study reveals that 96% of ransomware attacks now include data exfiltration, meaning cybercriminals steal sensitive data before encrypting files. This tactic increases pressure on victims to pay ransom, as attackers threaten to leak stolen data if demands are not met. The shift in ransomware tactics highlights the need for organizations to strengthen both data protection and incident response strategies. Security experts recommend regular backups, network segmentation, and endpoint detection solutions.<br/> <a href="https://www.securitymagazine.com/articles/101435-96-of-ransomware-incidents-involve-data-exfiltration">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story5-us-seizes-31-million-stolen-in-cryptocurrency-cybercrime-operations">Story5. U.S. Seizes $31 Million Stolen in Cryptocurrency Cybercrime Operations</h3> <p>The U.S. government has successfully recovered $31 million in stolen cryptocurrency linked to cybercriminal activities. The funds were originally stolen through sophisticated phishing scams and ransomware operations targeting individuals and businesses. Authorities worked with blockchain analysis firms to track and seize the assets. The seizure is part of a broader effort to crack down on illicit cryptocurrency transactions.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/u-s-seizes-31-million-funds-drained/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story6-vmware-security-flaws-exploited-in-active-cyberattacks">Story6. VMware Security Flaws Exploited in Active Cyberattacks</h3> <p>Security researchers have identified multiple VMware vulnerabilities that are being actively exploited in cyberattacks. These flaws allow attackers to gain remote access, execute arbitrary code, and compromise virtualized environments. Organizations using VMware products are strongly urged to apply patches and implement security best practices. The incident underscores the critical need for timely software updates to prevent exploitation.<br/> <a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/03/vmware-security-flaws-exploited-in.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story7-hackers-deliver-xworm-malware-via-malicious-windows-registry-files">Story7. Hackers Deliver XWorm Malware via Malicious Windows Registry Files</h3> <p>A new cyberattack campaign is using malicious Windows registry files to distribute the XWorm malware. This sophisticated technique allows attackers to execute the malware without triggering traditional antivirus alerts. Once deployed, XWorm can steal credentials, exfiltrate sensitive data, and enable remote access for further exploitation. Users are advised to avoid running untrusted registry files and implement endpoint security solutions.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/hackers-deliver-xworm-via-malicious-registry-files/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story8-threat-actor-javaghost-targets-aws-environments-with-phishing-scheme">Story8. Threat Actor “JavaGhost” Targets AWS Environments with Phishing Scheme</h3> <p>A newly identified cyber threat, dubbed “JavaGhost,” is targeting AWS cloud environments through sophisticated phishing campaigns. Attackers trick victims into installing malicious Java-based payloads that allow unauthorized access to cloud resources. The malware enables credential theft, privilege escalation, and data exfiltration. Security professionals recommend implementing multi-factor authentication (MFA) and regularly reviewing cloud security policies to defend against such attacks.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cloud-security/threat-actor-javaghost-targets-aws-environments-phishing-scheme">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story9-microsoft-teams-being-used-to-deploy-black-basta-and-cactus-ransomware">Story9. Microsoft Teams Being Used to Deploy Black Basta and Cactus Ransomware</h3> <p>Cybercriminals are using Microsoft Teams as a delivery mechanism to spread the Black Basta and Cactus ransomware strains. Attackers infiltrate Teams environments and send malicious files to unsuspecting users, leading to system encryption and data theft. The technique bypasses traditional email security controls, making it a highly effective attack vector. Organizations are urged to restrict external file-sharing in Teams and educate employees on recognizing suspicious messages.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/microsoft-teams-tactics-malware-connect-black-basta-cactus-ransomware/">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[3-5-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-4-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0304/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-4-25"/><published>2025-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0304</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0304/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-03-04-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h3 id="story-1-fake-it-support-calls-target-microsoft-teams-users-to-install-ransomware">Story 1. Fake IT Support Calls Target Microsoft Teams Users to Install Ransomware</h3> <p>Cybercriminals are impersonating IT support staff in Microsoft Teams calls to trick employees into installing ransomware. This social engineering tactic involves attackers gaining access to Teams accounts and calling users under the pretense of troubleshooting issues. Once trust is established, victims are directed to download and run malware disguised as a legitimate update. Security experts recommend organizations enforce strict authentication policies and educate employees on verifying IT support requests.<br/> <a href="https://hackread.com/fake-it-support-calls-microsoft-teams-users-install-ransomware/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story-2-cisos-urged-to-prioritize-identity-management-says-crowdstrike-executive">Story 2. CISOs Urged to Prioritize Identity Management, Says CrowdStrike Executive</h3> <p>A top executive at CrowdStrike has warned CISOs to urgently address identity management as a critical component of cybersecurity. Weak identity controls continue to be a primary attack vector for cybercriminals, enabling account takeovers and privilege escalation attacks. The increasing adoption of cloud services and remote work has amplified these risks, making zero-trust policies and robust identity verification essential. Organizations are encouraged to implement multi-factor authentication (MFA) and continuous monitoring to mitigate threats.<br/> <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3836917/cisos-should-address-identity-management-as-fast-as-they-can-says-crowdstrike-exec.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story-3-cisa-adds-multiple-cisco-microsoft-and-progress-software-vulnerabilities-to-known-exploited-list">Story 3. CISA Adds Multiple Cisco, Microsoft, and Progress Software Vulnerabilities to Known Exploited List</h3> <p>The U.S. Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) has added several vulnerabilities to its Known Exploited Vulnerabilities (KEV) catalog. The list includes flaws in Cisco Small Business RV series routers, Microsoft Windows Win32k, Hitachi Vantara’s Pentaho BA Server, and Progress WhatsUp Gold. These vulnerabilities are actively being exploited by attackers, posing significant security risks. Organizations using these products should apply patches immediately to prevent potential breaches.<br/> <a href="https://securityaffairs.com/174853/security/u-s-cisa-adds-multiple-cisco-small-business-rv-series-routers-hitachi-vantara-pentaho-ba-server-microsoft-windows-win32k-and-progress-whatsup-gold-flaws-to-its-known-exploited-vulnerabilities.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story-4-north-korean-it-workers-using-astrill-vpn-to-evade-sanctions">Story 4. North Korean IT Workers Using Astrill VPN to Evade Sanctions</h3> <p>A new report reveals that North Korean IT workers are using Astrill VPN to disguise their identities and secure remote jobs at foreign companies. These workers pose as legitimate software developers while funneling earnings back to the North Korean government. Their tactics include using stolen identities and falsified credentials to bypass background checks. Businesses hiring remote IT talent are advised to implement rigorous identity verification and monitoring to detect fraudulent applicants.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/north-korean-it-workers-using-astrill-vpn/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story-5-microsoft-links-recent-microsoft-365-outage-to-buggy-update">Story 5. Microsoft Links Recent Microsoft 365 Outage to Buggy Update</h3> <p>Microsoft has confirmed that a buggy update caused a widespread Microsoft 365 outage, disrupting access to services like Outlook, Teams, and OneDrive. The issue, introduced in a recent software update, led to authentication failures and connectivity problems for thousands of users. Microsoft has since rolled back the faulty update and implemented additional safeguards to prevent similar incidents in the future. The outage highlights the risks of untested updates affecting cloud-based services.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/microsoft/microsoft-links-recent-microsoft-365-outage-to-buggy-update/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story-6-nearly-12000-api-keys-and-passwords-found-in-ai-training-dataset">Story 6. Nearly 12,000 API Keys and Passwords Found in AI Training Dataset</h3> <p>Researchers have discovered nearly 12,000 exposed API keys and passwords within a publicly accessible AI training dataset. These sensitive credentials, likely included unintentionally, could allow attackers to access databases, cloud environments, and payment systems. The incident raises concerns over data sanitization practices in AI model training. Experts emphasize the need for strict data handling protocols to prevent security leaks in machine learning projects.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/nearly-12-000-api-keys-and-passwords-found-in-ai-training-dataset/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story-7-hackers-use-clickfix-trick-to-deploy-malware-via-fake-software-updates">Story 7. Hackers Use “ClickFix” Trick to Deploy Malware via Fake Software Updates</h3> <p>Cybercriminals are using a new technique called “ClickFix” to deliver malware through fake software updates. This attack method tricks users into believing they are fixing a software issue, only to install malicious payloads instead. The malware can steal sensitive data, deploy ransomware, or establish persistent access for further exploitation. Users are urged to verify update sources and avoid clicking on unsolicited fix prompts.<br/> <a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/03/hackers-use-clickfix-trick-to-deploy.html">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[3-4-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2-28-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0228/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2-28-25"/><published>2025-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0228</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0228/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-02-28-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h3 id="story-1-critical-microsoft-partner-center-vulnerability-under-attack-cisa-warns">Story 1. Critical Microsoft Partner Center Vulnerability Under Attack, CISA Warns</h3> <p>A critical vulnerability in Microsoft’s Partner Center is actively being exploited, prompting an urgent warning from CISA. The flaw, tracked as CVE-2024-1234, allows attackers to gain unauthorized access to accounts, potentially leading to data theft and privilege escalation. Microsoft has released a patch, but many organizations remain at risk if they have not applied the update. Security experts advise immediate mitigation to prevent compromise.<br/> <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3834674/critical-microsoft-partner-center-vulnerability-under-attack-cisa-warns.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story-2-hackers-behind-90-data-leaks-worldwide-identified">Story 2. Hackers Behind 90 Data Leaks Worldwide Identified</h3> <p>Cybersecurity researchers have linked a hacking group to over 90 data breaches worldwide, targeting various industries, including healthcare, finance, and government sectors. The threat actors used a combination of phishing, credential stuffing, and ransomware attacks to steal and expose sensitive information. Their operations have caused millions of dollars in damages and led to widespread identity theft. Authorities are working to track down and dismantle the group’s infrastructure.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/hackers-behind-90-data-leaks-worldwide/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story-3-hackers-can-crack-car-cameras-in-minutes-researchers-warn">Story 3. Hackers Can Crack Car Cameras in Minutes, Researchers Warn</h3> <p>Security researchers have discovered vulnerabilities in automotive camera systems that allow hackers to access and manipulate video feeds in minutes. These flaws could enable cybercriminals to disable security cameras, track vehicle movements, or inject fake footage. The vulnerabilities affect multiple brands and models, with some manufacturers already working on patches. Experts recommend that car owners and fleet managers update their systems as soon as fixes become available.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/vulnerabilities-threats/hackers-can-crack-car-cameras-minutes">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story-4-openssf-introduces-minimum-security-baselines-for-open-source-projects">Story 4. OpenSSF Introduces Minimum Security Baselines for Open-Source Projects</h3> <p>The Open Source Security Foundation (OpenSSF) has launched a set of minimum security baselines aimed at improving the security of open-source software projects. These guidelines focus on key areas such as secure coding practices, vulnerability management, and supply chain security. The initiative aims to reduce the growing risks associated with open-source software dependencies. Developers are encouraged to adopt these baselines to enhance the security of their projects.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/openssf-minimum-security-baselines-open-source-projects">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story-5-chinese-apt-exploiting-vpn-bug-to-target-ot-organizations-worldwide">Story 5. Chinese APT Exploiting VPN Bug to Target OT Organizations Worldwide</h3> <p>A Chinese advanced persistent threat (APT) group has been exploiting a critical VPN vulnerability to infiltrate operational technology (OT) networks worldwide. The attack campaign, ongoing since 2023, enables hackers to bypass authentication and gain persistent access to sensitive infrastructure. Affected organizations include energy, manufacturing, and transportation sectors. Security experts recommend applying patches and monitoring network activity for signs of compromise.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/ics-ot-security/chinese-apt-vpn-bug-worldwide-ot-orgs">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story-6-googles-safetycore-app-secretly-scanning-android-devices-for-security-threats">Story 6. Google’s SafetyCore App Secretly Scanning Android Devices for Security Threats</h3> <p>Google’s SafetyCore app, recently discovered running in the background on Android devices, has raised privacy concerns due to its undisclosed security scanning capabilities. The app appears to be monitoring for malware and system vulnerabilities, but its lack of transparency has drawn criticism. While Google claims the feature is meant to enhance user security, some privacy advocates worry about potential misuse. Android users are calling for more control over SafetyCore’s functionality.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/googles-safetycore-app-secretly-scans/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story-7-hackers-exploited-xss-vulnerability-in-popular-web-framework">Story 7. Hackers Exploited XSS Vulnerability in Popular Web Framework</h3> <p>A newly disclosed cross-site scripting (XSS) vulnerability in a widely used web development framework has been actively exploited by hackers. The flaw allows attackers to inject malicious scripts, leading to data theft, session hijacking, and further compromise of affected web applications. Several high-profile websites were impacted before a patch was released. Developers are urged to update their applications immediately to prevent further exploitation.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/hackers-exploited-xss-vulnerability-framework/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story-8-mitre-caldera-security-advisory-warns-of-maximum-severity-flaw">Story 8. MITRE Caldera Security Advisory Warns of Maximum Severity Flaw</h3> <p>A maximum severity vulnerability in MITRE Caldera, an open-source adversary emulation tool, has been disclosed, putting cybersecurity teams at risk. The flaw allows remote attackers to execute arbitrary code without authentication, potentially leading to full system compromise. Security researchers have urged immediate patching to prevent exploitation by threat actors. This incident highlights the risks associated with red-team tools falling into the wrong hands.<br/> <a href="https://www.securitymagazine.com/articles/101428-mitre-caldera-security-advisory-warns-of-maximum-severity-flaw">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story-9-microsofts-generative-ai-in-azure-allegedly-used-for-hacking-for-hire-operations">Story 9. Microsoft’s Generative AI in Azure Allegedly Used for Hacking-for-Hire Operations</h3> <p>Microsoft is facing allegations that its generative AI tools on Azure have been misused by hacking-for-hire groups to develop sophisticated cyberattacks. A recently amended legal complaint accuses the tech giant of failing to prevent malicious actors from leveraging its AI models to enhance phishing, malware development, and social engineering tactics. Microsoft has stated that it actively monitors AI misuse and is working to prevent further exploitation. The case underscores growing concerns about AI-driven cybercrime.<br/> <a href="https://cyberscoop.com/microsoft-generative-ai-azure-hacking-for-hire-amended-complaint/">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[2-28-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2-27-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0227/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2-27-25"/><published>2025-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0227</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0227/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-02-27-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="1-rsync-vulnerabilities-allow-full-server-control">1. Rsync Vulnerabilities Allow Full Server Control</h2> <p>Critical vulnerabilities have been discovered in the Rsync file synchronization tool, affecting versions 3.2.7 and earlier. These flaws enable attackers to execute arbitrary code on vulnerable servers, exfiltrate sensitive data, and bypass security controls. Proof-of-concept exploits have demonstrated remote code execution capabilities, emphasizing the need for immediate updates to version 3.4.0. Administrators are advised to audit server configurations and disable anonymous access to mitigate potential threats.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/rsync-vulnerabilities-full-control-servers/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="2-australian-ivf-giant-genea-breached-by-termite-ransomware-gang">2. Australian IVF Giant Genea Breached by Termite Ransomware Gang</h2> <p>Genea, one of Australia’s leading fertility service providers, has suffered a data breach orchestrated by the Termite ransomware gang. The attackers infiltrated Genea’s network, stealing sensitive patient data, which was subsequently published online. In response, Genea obtained a court-ordered injunction to prevent further dissemination of the leaked information and is collaborating with the Australian Cyber Security Centre to investigate the incident. Patients are being offered support to safeguard their personal information.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/australian-ivf-giant-genea-breached-by-termite-ransomware-gang/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="3-new-phishing-attack-targeting-amazon-prime-users">3. New Phishing Attack Targeting Amazon Prime Users</h2> <p>A sophisticated phishing campaign has emerged, targeting Amazon Prime users with counterfeit renewal notifications. These deceptive emails prompt recipients to update their payment information, leading them to fake Amazon security portals designed to harvest login credentials, payment details, and personal data. The attackers employ advanced social engineering tactics, including the use of Google Docs redirects and QR code-based payloads, to bypass security filters. Users are advised to verify communications directly through Amazon’s official website and avoid clicking on suspicious links.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/new-phishing-attack-targeting-amazon-prime-users/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="4-microsoft-entra-id-dns-resolution-failures-result-in-authentication-issues">4. Microsoft Entra ID DNS Resolution Failures Result in Authentication Issues</h2> <p>A critical DNS misconfiguration in Microsoft Entra ID (formerly Azure Active Directory) led to global authentication disruptions for nearly 90 minutes on February 25, 2025. The issue originated from an IPv6 infrastructure cleanup that inadvertently removed essential CNAME records, causing failures in Kerberos ticket validation. Services relying on Seamless Single Sign-On and Entra Connect Sync were particularly affected. Microsoft has since reverted the changes and is conducting a post-incident review to prevent future occurrences.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/microsoft-entra-id-dns-resolution-failures-results/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="5-grub2-vulnerabilities-expose-millions-of-linux-systems-to-cyber-attacks">5. GRUB2 Vulnerabilities Expose Millions of Linux Systems to Cyber Attacks</h2> <p>A set of 20 critical vulnerabilities has been identified in GRUB2, the bootloader used by most Linux distributions and Unix-like systems. These flaws expose millions of devices to potential secure boot bypasses, remote code execution, and persistent firmware-level attacks. The vulnerabilities affect various components, including filesystem drivers and cryptographic modules. Users are urged to apply the latest patches and updates to mitigate these security risks.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/grub2-vulnerabilities-exposes-millions-of-linux-systems/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="6-99-of-organizations-faced-api-security-issues-within-past-12-months">6. 99% of Organizations Faced API Security Issues Within Past 12 Months</h2> <p>A recent report reveals that 99% of organizations encountered API security issues over the past year. Common challenges include vulnerabilities exposing APIs to attacks, exposure of sensitive information, and authentication weaknesses. Notably, 95% of API attacks originated from authenticated sources, and 98% targeted external-facing APIs. Despite increasing security budgets, many organizations still lack mature API security programs, highlighting the need for enhanced protective measures.<br/> <a href="https://www.securitymagazine.com/articles/101421-99-of-organizations-faced-api-security-issues-within-past-12-months">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="7-threat-actor-allegedly-selling-vmware-esxi-0-day-exploit-on-hacker-forum">7. Threat Actor Allegedly Selling VMware ESXi 0-Day Exploit on Hacker Forum</h2> <p>A cybercriminal known as “Vanger” has reportedly advertised a zero-day exploit targeting VMware ESXi hypervisors on underground forums, priced at $150,000. This exploit purportedly enables virtual machine escape, allowing attackers to breach host systems from guest virtual machines. While the authenticity of the exploit remains unverified, its potential impact underscores the importance of regular patching and stringent security measures in virtualized environments.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/threat-actor-vmware-esxi-0-day/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="8-vscode-extensions-with-9-million-installs-pulled-over-security-risks">8. VSCode Extensions with 9 Million Installs Pulled Over Security Risks</h2> <p>Microsoft has removed two popular Visual Studio Code extensions, ‘Material Theme – Free’ and ‘Material Theme Icons – Free,’ from its marketplace due to the discovery of malicious code. These extensions, collectively downloaded nearly 9 million times, have been automatically disabled in users’ environments. The incident highlights the necessity for developers to scrutinize third-party extensions and for organizations to implement robust security policies governing their use.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/vscode-extensions-with-9-million-installs-pulled-over-security-risks/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="9-silver-fox-apt-skirts-windows-blocklist-in-byovd-attack">9. ‘Silver Fox’ APT Skirts Windows Blocklist in BYOVD Attack</h2> <p>The Chinese advanced persistent threat group known as ‘Silver Fox’ has been exploiting a vulnerable Windows driver, ‘Truesight.sys,’ to bypass security measures and deploy malware. This bring-your-own-vulnerable-driver (BYOVD) attack allows the group to undermine protected processes and infect systems with malware such as Gh0stRAT. The campaign primarily targets individuals in Southeast Asia, emphasizing the need for vigilant driver management and updated blocklists to prevent such exploits.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyber-risk/silver-fox-byovd-attack-windows-blocklist">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="10-bybit-declares-war-on-lazarus-crew-to-regain-stolen-15-billion">10. Bybit Declares War on Lazarus Crew to Regain Stolen $1.5 Billion</h2> <p>Cryptocurrency exchange Bybit has launched a bounty program offering up to $140 million for information leading to the recovery of $1.5 billion in Ethereum stolen by North Korea</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[2-27-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2-26-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0226/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2-26-25"/><published>2025-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0226</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0226/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-02-26-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="1-microsoft-fixes-entra-id-authentication-issue-caused-by-dns-change">1. Microsoft Fixes Entra ID Authentication Issue Caused by DNS Change</h2> <p>Microsoft has resolved an issue that led to Entra ID DNS authentication failures affecting services utilizing Seamless Single Sign-On and Entra Connect Sync. The problem originated from a recent DNS modification intended to remove duplicate IPv6 CNAMEs, which inadvertently deleted a crucial domain used in the authentication process. This caused authentication requests to fail between 17:18 and 18:35 UTC on February 25, 2025. Microsoft has since reverted the change, restoring full service functionality.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/microsoft/microsoft-fixes-entra-id-authentication-issue-caused-by-dns-change/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="2-gitvenom-campaign-abusing-thousands-of-github-repositories-to-infect-users">2. GitVenom Campaign Abusing Thousands of GitHub Repositories to Infect Users</h2> <p>A sophisticated malware campaign, dubbed “GitVenom,” has been exploiting GitHub’s open-source platform to distribute malicious code through thousands of fraudulent repositories. Active since at least 2023, the attackers have created repositories masquerading as legitimate projects, such as automation tools and cryptocurrency utilities. These repositories contain hidden malicious code designed to steal cryptocurrencies and provide remote access to compromised systems. The campaign has primarily impacted users in Russia, Brazil, and Turkey.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/gitvenom-abusing-thousands-of-github-repositories/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="3-new-auto-color-linux-backdoor-targets-north-american-governments-and-universities">3. New Auto-Color Linux Backdoor Targets North American Governments and Universities</h2> <p>Researchers have identified a previously undocumented Linux backdoor named ‘Auto-Color,’ which was active in attacks between November and December 2024. This malware specifically targeted universities and government organizations in North America and Asia. ‘Auto-Color’ is noted for its evasive capabilities, allowing it to maintain prolonged access to infected systems and making it challenging to detect and remove.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/new-auto-color-linux-backdoor-targets-north-american-govts-universities/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="4-windows-10-kb5052077-update-fixes-broken-ssh-connections">4. Windows 10 KB5052077 Update Fixes Broken SSH Connections</h2> <p>Microsoft has released the optional KB5052077 preview cumulative update for Windows 10 version 22H2, addressing nine issues, including a fix for a known problem that disrupted SSH connections. The issue, acknowledged in November 2024, caused the OpenSSH service to fail to start on certain devices, preventing SSH connections. This update aims to resolve the problem, restoring normal SSH functionality for affected users.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/microsoft/windows-10-kb5052077-update-fixes-broken-ssh-connections/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="5-belarus-linked-ghostwriter-uses-macropack-obfuscated-excel-macros-to-deploy-malware">5. Belarus-Linked Ghostwriter Uses Macropack-Obfuscated Excel Macros to Deploy Malware</h2> <p>The Belarus-aligned threat actor known as Ghostwriter has launched a new campaign targeting opposition activists in Belarus and Ukrainian military and government organizations. The attackers employ malware-laden Microsoft Excel documents with obfuscated macros to deliver a variant of the PicassoLoader malware. This campaign, active since November-December 2024, aims to establish persistent access and conduct cyber-espionage activities against the targeted entities.<br/> <a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/02/belarus-linked-ghostwriter-uses.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="6-16-malicious-chrome-extensions-infected-over-32-million-users">6. 16 Malicious Chrome Extensions Infected Over 3.2 Million Users</h2> <p>A coordinated campaign involving at least 16 malicious Chrome extensions has compromised over 3.2 million users worldwide. These extensions, posing as legitimate tools like screen capture utilities and ad blockers, manipulated browser security settings to execute advertising fraud and manipulate search engine results. Despite their removal from the Chrome Web Store, users who have not manually uninstalled these extensions remain at risk.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/16-malicious-chrome-extensions/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="7-have-i-been-pwned-adds-284m-accounts-stolen-by-infostealer-malware">7. Have I Been Pwned Adds 284M Accounts Stolen by Infostealer Malware</h2> <p>The data breach notification service ‘Have I Been Pwned’ has incorporated over 284 million accounts compromised by information-stealing malware. These accounts were discovered in a 1.5TB collection of stealer logs shared on a Telegram channel known as “ALIEN TXTBASE.” The data includes 23 billion rows with 493 million unique website and email address pairs, highlighting the extensive reach of infostealer malware in recent cyber incidents.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/have-i-been-pwned-adds-284m-accounts-stolen-by-infostealer-malware/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="8-max-severity-rce-vulnerability-in-all-versions-of-mitre-caldera">8. Max Severity RCE Vulnerability in All Versions of MITRE Caldera</h2> <p>A critical remote code execution vulnerability, identified as CVE-2025-27364, has been discovered in all versions of MITRE’s Caldera platform, an open-source adversary emulation tool used for red-teaming exercises. The flaw, which has a maximum severity score of 10, allows attackers to execute arbitrary code without user interaction or special privileges. MITRE recommends that all Caldera users immediately update to the latest version to mitigate potential exploitation risks.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/max-severity-rce-vuln-all-versions-mitre-caldera">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="9-lockbit-taunts-fbi-director-kash-patel-with-alleged-classified-leak-threat">9. LockBit Taunts FBI Director Kash Patel with Alleged “Classified” Leak Threat</h2> <p>The ransomware group LockBit has issued a provocative message to newly appointed FBI Director Kash Patel, claiming possession of “classified information” that could “destroy” the agency if leaked. This message, published on LockBit’s dark web leak site, appears to be an attempt to intimidate and challenge U.S. law enforcement agencies. The authenticity and potential impact of the alleged information remain unverified.<br/> <a href="https://securityaffairs.com/174639/cyber-crime/lockbit-taunts-fbi-director-kash-patel.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="10-uac-0212-hackers-launching-destructive-attacks-targeting-critical-infrastructure">10. UAC-0212 Hackers Launching Destructive Attacks Targeting Critical Infrastructure</h2> <p>A sophisticated threat group identified as UAC-0212 has intensified efforts to compromise critical infrastructure systems in Ukraine. Active since July 2024, their attacks focus on sectors such as energy, water supply, grain logistics, and transportation. Utilizing supply-chain compromises, the group deploys destructive payloads and advanced persistence mechanisms to disrupt industrial control systems and operational technology, posing significant risks to national security and public safety.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/uac-0212-hackers-launching-destructive-attack/">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[2-26-25]]></summary></entry></feed>