<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-03-02T04:51:55+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DJBSec, CISSP</title><subtitle>DJBSec is an IT veteran with over 25 years of experience in IT and Cyber Security </subtitle><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2-28-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0228/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2-28-25"/><published>2025-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0228</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0228/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-02-28-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h3 id="story-1-critical-microsoft-partner-center-vulnerability-under-attack-cisa-warns">Story 1. Critical Microsoft Partner Center Vulnerability Under Attack, CISA Warns</h3> <p>A critical vulnerability in Microsoft’s Partner Center is actively being exploited, prompting an urgent warning from CISA. The flaw, tracked as CVE-2024-1234, allows attackers to gain unauthorized access to accounts, potentially leading to data theft and privilege escalation. Microsoft has released a patch, but many organizations remain at risk if they have not applied the update. Security experts advise immediate mitigation to prevent compromise.<br/> <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3834674/critical-microsoft-partner-center-vulnerability-under-attack-cisa-warns.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story-2-hackers-behind-90-data-leaks-worldwide-identified">Story 2. Hackers Behind 90 Data Leaks Worldwide Identified</h3> <p>Cybersecurity researchers have linked a hacking group to over 90 data breaches worldwide, targeting various industries, including healthcare, finance, and government sectors. The threat actors used a combination of phishing, credential stuffing, and ransomware attacks to steal and expose sensitive information. Their operations have caused millions of dollars in damages and led to widespread identity theft. Authorities are working to track down and dismantle the group’s infrastructure.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/hackers-behind-90-data-leaks-worldwide/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story-3-hackers-can-crack-car-cameras-in-minutes-researchers-warn">Story 3. Hackers Can Crack Car Cameras in Minutes, Researchers Warn</h3> <p>Security researchers have discovered vulnerabilities in automotive camera systems that allow hackers to access and manipulate video feeds in minutes. These flaws could enable cybercriminals to disable security cameras, track vehicle movements, or inject fake footage. The vulnerabilities affect multiple brands and models, with some manufacturers already working on patches. Experts recommend that car owners and fleet managers update their systems as soon as fixes become available.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/vulnerabilities-threats/hackers-can-crack-car-cameras-minutes">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story-4-openssf-introduces-minimum-security-baselines-for-open-source-projects">Story 4. OpenSSF Introduces Minimum Security Baselines for Open-Source Projects</h3> <p>The Open Source Security Foundation (OpenSSF) has launched a set of minimum security baselines aimed at improving the security of open-source software projects. These guidelines focus on key areas such as secure coding practices, vulnerability management, and supply chain security. The initiative aims to reduce the growing risks associated with open-source software dependencies. Developers are encouraged to adopt these baselines to enhance the security of their projects.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/openssf-minimum-security-baselines-open-source-projects">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story-5-chinese-apt-exploiting-vpn-bug-to-target-ot-organizations-worldwide">Story 5. Chinese APT Exploiting VPN Bug to Target OT Organizations Worldwide</h3> <p>A Chinese advanced persistent threat (APT) group has been exploiting a critical VPN vulnerability to infiltrate operational technology (OT) networks worldwide. The attack campaign, ongoing since 2023, enables hackers to bypass authentication and gain persistent access to sensitive infrastructure. Affected organizations include energy, manufacturing, and transportation sectors. Security experts recommend applying patches and monitoring network activity for signs of compromise.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/ics-ot-security/chinese-apt-vpn-bug-worldwide-ot-orgs">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story-6-googles-safetycore-app-secretly-scanning-android-devices-for-security-threats">Story 6. Google’s SafetyCore App Secretly Scanning Android Devices for Security Threats</h3> <p>Google’s SafetyCore app, recently discovered running in the background on Android devices, has raised privacy concerns due to its undisclosed security scanning capabilities. The app appears to be monitoring for malware and system vulnerabilities, but its lack of transparency has drawn criticism. While Google claims the feature is meant to enhance user security, some privacy advocates worry about potential misuse. Android users are calling for more control over SafetyCore’s functionality.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/googles-safetycore-app-secretly-scans/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story-7-hackers-exploited-xss-vulnerability-in-popular-web-framework">Story 7. Hackers Exploited XSS Vulnerability in Popular Web Framework</h3> <p>A newly disclosed cross-site scripting (XSS) vulnerability in a widely used web development framework has been actively exploited by hackers. The flaw allows attackers to inject malicious scripts, leading to data theft, session hijacking, and further compromise of affected web applications. Several high-profile websites were impacted before a patch was released. Developers are urged to update their applications immediately to prevent further exploitation.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/hackers-exploited-xss-vulnerability-framework/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story-8-mitre-caldera-security-advisory-warns-of-maximum-severity-flaw">Story 8. MITRE Caldera Security Advisory Warns of Maximum Severity Flaw</h3> <p>A maximum severity vulnerability in MITRE Caldera, an open-source adversary emulation tool, has been disclosed, putting cybersecurity teams at risk. The flaw allows remote attackers to execute arbitrary code without authentication, potentially leading to full system compromise. Security researchers have urged immediate patching to prevent exploitation by threat actors. This incident highlights the risks associated with red-team tools falling into the wrong hands.<br/> <a href="https://www.securitymagazine.com/articles/101428-mitre-caldera-security-advisory-warns-of-maximum-severity-flaw">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story-9-microsofts-generative-ai-in-azure-allegedly-used-for-hacking-for-hire-operations">Story 9. Microsoft’s Generative AI in Azure Allegedly Used for Hacking-for-Hire Operations</h3> <p>Microsoft is facing allegations that its generative AI tools on Azure have been misused by hacking-for-hire groups to develop sophisticated cyberattacks. A recently amended legal complaint accuses the tech giant of failing to prevent malicious actors from leveraging its AI models to enhance phishing, malware development, and social engineering tactics. Microsoft has stated that it actively monitors AI misuse and is working to prevent further exploitation. The case underscores growing concerns about AI-driven cybercrime.<br/> <a href="https://cyberscoop.com/microsoft-generative-ai-azure-hacking-for-hire-amended-complaint/">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[2-28-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2-27-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0227/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2-27-25"/><published>2025-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0227</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0227/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-02-27-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="1-rsync-vulnerabilities-allow-full-server-control">1. Rsync Vulnerabilities Allow Full Server Control</h2> <p>Critical vulnerabilities have been discovered in the Rsync file synchronization tool, affecting versions 3.2.7 and earlier. These flaws enable attackers to execute arbitrary code on vulnerable servers, exfiltrate sensitive data, and bypass security controls. Proof-of-concept exploits have demonstrated remote code execution capabilities, emphasizing the need for immediate updates to version 3.4.0. Administrators are advised to audit server configurations and disable anonymous access to mitigate potential threats.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/rsync-vulnerabilities-full-control-servers/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="2-australian-ivf-giant-genea-breached-by-termite-ransomware-gang">2. Australian IVF Giant Genea Breached by Termite Ransomware Gang</h2> <p>Genea, one of Australia’s leading fertility service providers, has suffered a data breach orchestrated by the Termite ransomware gang. The attackers infiltrated Genea’s network, stealing sensitive patient data, which was subsequently published online. In response, Genea obtained a court-ordered injunction to prevent further dissemination of the leaked information and is collaborating with the Australian Cyber Security Centre to investigate the incident. Patients are being offered support to safeguard their personal information.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/australian-ivf-giant-genea-breached-by-termite-ransomware-gang/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="3-new-phishing-attack-targeting-amazon-prime-users">3. New Phishing Attack Targeting Amazon Prime Users</h2> <p>A sophisticated phishing campaign has emerged, targeting Amazon Prime users with counterfeit renewal notifications. These deceptive emails prompt recipients to update their payment information, leading them to fake Amazon security portals designed to harvest login credentials, payment details, and personal data. The attackers employ advanced social engineering tactics, including the use of Google Docs redirects and QR code-based payloads, to bypass security filters. Users are advised to verify communications directly through Amazon’s official website and avoid clicking on suspicious links.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/new-phishing-attack-targeting-amazon-prime-users/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="4-microsoft-entra-id-dns-resolution-failures-result-in-authentication-issues">4. Microsoft Entra ID DNS Resolution Failures Result in Authentication Issues</h2> <p>A critical DNS misconfiguration in Microsoft Entra ID (formerly Azure Active Directory) led to global authentication disruptions for nearly 90 minutes on February 25, 2025. The issue originated from an IPv6 infrastructure cleanup that inadvertently removed essential CNAME records, causing failures in Kerberos ticket validation. Services relying on Seamless Single Sign-On and Entra Connect Sync were particularly affected. Microsoft has since reverted the changes and is conducting a post-incident review to prevent future occurrences.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/microsoft-entra-id-dns-resolution-failures-results/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="5-grub2-vulnerabilities-expose-millions-of-linux-systems-to-cyber-attacks">5. GRUB2 Vulnerabilities Expose Millions of Linux Systems to Cyber Attacks</h2> <p>A set of 20 critical vulnerabilities has been identified in GRUB2, the bootloader used by most Linux distributions and Unix-like systems. These flaws expose millions of devices to potential secure boot bypasses, remote code execution, and persistent firmware-level attacks. The vulnerabilities affect various components, including filesystem drivers and cryptographic modules. Users are urged to apply the latest patches and updates to mitigate these security risks.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/grub2-vulnerabilities-exposes-millions-of-linux-systems/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="6-99-of-organizations-faced-api-security-issues-within-past-12-months">6. 99% of Organizations Faced API Security Issues Within Past 12 Months</h2> <p>A recent report reveals that 99% of organizations encountered API security issues over the past year. Common challenges include vulnerabilities exposing APIs to attacks, exposure of sensitive information, and authentication weaknesses. Notably, 95% of API attacks originated from authenticated sources, and 98% targeted external-facing APIs. Despite increasing security budgets, many organizations still lack mature API security programs, highlighting the need for enhanced protective measures.<br/> <a href="https://www.securitymagazine.com/articles/101421-99-of-organizations-faced-api-security-issues-within-past-12-months">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="7-threat-actor-allegedly-selling-vmware-esxi-0-day-exploit-on-hacker-forum">7. Threat Actor Allegedly Selling VMware ESXi 0-Day Exploit on Hacker Forum</h2> <p>A cybercriminal known as “Vanger” has reportedly advertised a zero-day exploit targeting VMware ESXi hypervisors on underground forums, priced at $150,000. This exploit purportedly enables virtual machine escape, allowing attackers to breach host systems from guest virtual machines. While the authenticity of the exploit remains unverified, its potential impact underscores the importance of regular patching and stringent security measures in virtualized environments.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/threat-actor-vmware-esxi-0-day/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="8-vscode-extensions-with-9-million-installs-pulled-over-security-risks">8. VSCode Extensions with 9 Million Installs Pulled Over Security Risks</h2> <p>Microsoft has removed two popular Visual Studio Code extensions, ‘Material Theme – Free’ and ‘Material Theme Icons – Free,’ from its marketplace due to the discovery of malicious code. These extensions, collectively downloaded nearly 9 million times, have been automatically disabled in users’ environments. The incident highlights the necessity for developers to scrutinize third-party extensions and for organizations to implement robust security policies governing their use.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/vscode-extensions-with-9-million-installs-pulled-over-security-risks/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="9-silver-fox-apt-skirts-windows-blocklist-in-byovd-attack">9. ‘Silver Fox’ APT Skirts Windows Blocklist in BYOVD Attack</h2> <p>The Chinese advanced persistent threat group known as ‘Silver Fox’ has been exploiting a vulnerable Windows driver, ‘Truesight.sys,’ to bypass security measures and deploy malware. This bring-your-own-vulnerable-driver (BYOVD) attack allows the group to undermine protected processes and infect systems with malware such as Gh0stRAT. The campaign primarily targets individuals in Southeast Asia, emphasizing the need for vigilant driver management and updated blocklists to prevent such exploits.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyber-risk/silver-fox-byovd-attack-windows-blocklist">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="10-bybit-declares-war-on-lazarus-crew-to-regain-stolen-15-billion">10. Bybit Declares War on Lazarus Crew to Regain Stolen $1.5 Billion</h2> <p>Cryptocurrency exchange Bybit has launched a bounty program offering up to $140 million for information leading to the recovery of $1.5 billion in Ethereum stolen by North Korea</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[2-27-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2-26-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0226/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2-26-25"/><published>2025-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0226</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0226/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-02-26-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="1-microsoft-fixes-entra-id-authentication-issue-caused-by-dns-change">1. Microsoft Fixes Entra ID Authentication Issue Caused by DNS Change</h2> <p>Microsoft has resolved an issue that led to Entra ID DNS authentication failures affecting services utilizing Seamless Single Sign-On and Entra Connect Sync. The problem originated from a recent DNS modification intended to remove duplicate IPv6 CNAMEs, which inadvertently deleted a crucial domain used in the authentication process. This caused authentication requests to fail between 17:18 and 18:35 UTC on February 25, 2025. Microsoft has since reverted the change, restoring full service functionality.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/microsoft/microsoft-fixes-entra-id-authentication-issue-caused-by-dns-change/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="2-gitvenom-campaign-abusing-thousands-of-github-repositories-to-infect-users">2. GitVenom Campaign Abusing Thousands of GitHub Repositories to Infect Users</h2> <p>A sophisticated malware campaign, dubbed “GitVenom,” has been exploiting GitHub’s open-source platform to distribute malicious code through thousands of fraudulent repositories. Active since at least 2023, the attackers have created repositories masquerading as legitimate projects, such as automation tools and cryptocurrency utilities. These repositories contain hidden malicious code designed to steal cryptocurrencies and provide remote access to compromised systems. The campaign has primarily impacted users in Russia, Brazil, and Turkey.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/gitvenom-abusing-thousands-of-github-repositories/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="3-new-auto-color-linux-backdoor-targets-north-american-governments-and-universities">3. New Auto-Color Linux Backdoor Targets North American Governments and Universities</h2> <p>Researchers have identified a previously undocumented Linux backdoor named ‘Auto-Color,’ which was active in attacks between November and December 2024. This malware specifically targeted universities and government organizations in North America and Asia. ‘Auto-Color’ is noted for its evasive capabilities, allowing it to maintain prolonged access to infected systems and making it challenging to detect and remove.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/new-auto-color-linux-backdoor-targets-north-american-govts-universities/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="4-windows-10-kb5052077-update-fixes-broken-ssh-connections">4. Windows 10 KB5052077 Update Fixes Broken SSH Connections</h2> <p>Microsoft has released the optional KB5052077 preview cumulative update for Windows 10 version 22H2, addressing nine issues, including a fix for a known problem that disrupted SSH connections. The issue, acknowledged in November 2024, caused the OpenSSH service to fail to start on certain devices, preventing SSH connections. This update aims to resolve the problem, restoring normal SSH functionality for affected users.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/microsoft/windows-10-kb5052077-update-fixes-broken-ssh-connections/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="5-belarus-linked-ghostwriter-uses-macropack-obfuscated-excel-macros-to-deploy-malware">5. Belarus-Linked Ghostwriter Uses Macropack-Obfuscated Excel Macros to Deploy Malware</h2> <p>The Belarus-aligned threat actor known as Ghostwriter has launched a new campaign targeting opposition activists in Belarus and Ukrainian military and government organizations. The attackers employ malware-laden Microsoft Excel documents with obfuscated macros to deliver a variant of the PicassoLoader malware. This campaign, active since November-December 2024, aims to establish persistent access and conduct cyber-espionage activities against the targeted entities.<br/> <a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/02/belarus-linked-ghostwriter-uses.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="6-16-malicious-chrome-extensions-infected-over-32-million-users">6. 16 Malicious Chrome Extensions Infected Over 3.2 Million Users</h2> <p>A coordinated campaign involving at least 16 malicious Chrome extensions has compromised over 3.2 million users worldwide. These extensions, posing as legitimate tools like screen capture utilities and ad blockers, manipulated browser security settings to execute advertising fraud and manipulate search engine results. Despite their removal from the Chrome Web Store, users who have not manually uninstalled these extensions remain at risk.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/16-malicious-chrome-extensions/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="7-have-i-been-pwned-adds-284m-accounts-stolen-by-infostealer-malware">7. Have I Been Pwned Adds 284M Accounts Stolen by Infostealer Malware</h2> <p>The data breach notification service ‘Have I Been Pwned’ has incorporated over 284 million accounts compromised by information-stealing malware. These accounts were discovered in a 1.5TB collection of stealer logs shared on a Telegram channel known as “ALIEN TXTBASE.” The data includes 23 billion rows with 493 million unique website and email address pairs, highlighting the extensive reach of infostealer malware in recent cyber incidents.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/have-i-been-pwned-adds-284m-accounts-stolen-by-infostealer-malware/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="8-max-severity-rce-vulnerability-in-all-versions-of-mitre-caldera">8. Max Severity RCE Vulnerability in All Versions of MITRE Caldera</h2> <p>A critical remote code execution vulnerability, identified as CVE-2025-27364, has been discovered in all versions of MITRE’s Caldera platform, an open-source adversary emulation tool used for red-teaming exercises. The flaw, which has a maximum severity score of 10, allows attackers to execute arbitrary code without user interaction or special privileges. MITRE recommends that all Caldera users immediately update to the latest version to mitigate potential exploitation risks.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/max-severity-rce-vuln-all-versions-mitre-caldera">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="9-lockbit-taunts-fbi-director-kash-patel-with-alleged-classified-leak-threat">9. LockBit Taunts FBI Director Kash Patel with Alleged “Classified” Leak Threat</h2> <p>The ransomware group LockBit has issued a provocative message to newly appointed FBI Director Kash Patel, claiming possession of “classified information” that could “destroy” the agency if leaked. This message, published on LockBit’s dark web leak site, appears to be an attempt to intimidate and challenge U.S. law enforcement agencies. The authenticity and potential impact of the alleged information remain unverified.<br/> <a href="https://securityaffairs.com/174639/cyber-crime/lockbit-taunts-fbi-director-kash-patel.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="10-uac-0212-hackers-launching-destructive-attacks-targeting-critical-infrastructure">10. UAC-0212 Hackers Launching Destructive Attacks Targeting Critical Infrastructure</h2> <p>A sophisticated threat group identified as UAC-0212 has intensified efforts to compromise critical infrastructure systems in Ukraine. Active since July 2024, their attacks focus on sectors such as energy, water supply, grain logistics, and transportation. Utilizing supply-chain compromises, the group deploys destructive payloads and advanced persistence mechanisms to disrupt industrial control systems and operational technology, posing significant risks to national security and public safety.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/uac-0212-hackers-launching-destructive-attack/">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[2-26-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2-25-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0225/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2-25-25"/><published>2025-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0225</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0225/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-02-25-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="story-1-openai-bans-chatgpt-accounts-used-by-north-korean-hackers">Story 1: OpenAI Bans ChatGPT Accounts Used by North Korean Hackers</h2> <p>OpenAI has blocked several accounts linked to North Korean hacking groups that were exploiting ChatGPT for malicious activities. These actors utilized the platform to research potential targets, develop hacking tools, and gather information on cryptocurrency topics. The banned accounts were associated with threat groups such as VELVET CHOLLIMA and STARDUST CHOLLIMA. OpenAI’s actions aim to prevent the misuse of its AI technologies by state-sponsored threat actors.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/openai-bans-chatgpt-accounts-used-by-north-korean-hackers/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-2-large-botnet-targets-microsoft-365-accounts-with-password-spraying-attacks">Story 2: Large Botnet Targets Microsoft 365 Accounts with Password Spraying Attacks</h2> <p>A significant botnet has been identified targeting Microsoft 365 accounts through password spraying attacks. These attacks involve attempting a few common passwords across numerous accounts to gain unauthorized access. The botnet leverages a distributed network to evade detection and has been active since May 2024. Organizations are advised to implement strong password policies and multi-factor authentication to mitigate such threats.</p> <p><a href="https://securityaffairs.com/174595/cyber-crime/large-botnet-targets-m365-password-spraying-attacks.html">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-3-deepseeks-bytedance-data-sharing-raises-security-concerns">Story 3: DeepSeek’s ByteDance Data-Sharing Raises Security Concerns</h2> <p>Investigations have revealed that the AI chatbot DeepSeek has been transmitting user data to ByteDance, the Chinese parent company of TikTok. This data-sharing practice has raised significant security and privacy concerns, leading to regulatory scrutiny in countries like South Korea. Experts warn that such practices highlight the risks associated with emerging AI technologies and the importance of robust data protection measures.</p> <p><a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyber-risk/deepseek-bytedance-data-sharing-security-concerns">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-4-threat-actors-stealing-browser-fingerprints-to-bypass-security-measures">Story 4: Threat Actors Stealing Browser Fingerprints to Bypass Security Measures</h2> <p>Cybercriminals are employing advanced techniques to steal users’ browser fingerprints, enabling them to bypass security measures and impersonate legitimate users. By harvesting unique browser and device characteristics, attackers can evade multi-factor authentication and other fraud detection systems. This method has been linked to a campaign known as ScreamedJungle, which targets outdated e-commerce platforms. Users and organizations are urged to update their systems and employ anti-fingerprinting tools to protect against such threats.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/threat-actors-stealing-users-browser-fingerprints/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-5-sec-establishes-cyber-and-emerging-technologies-unit">Story 5: SEC Establishes Cyber and Emerging Technologies Unit</h2> <p>The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) has announced the creation of the Cyber and Emerging Technologies Unit (CETU) to combat cyber-related misconduct and protect retail investors from malicious actors in the emerging technologies sector. Led by Laura D’Allaird, the unit comprises approximately 30 fraud specialists and attorneys. The CETU will focus on areas such as fraud involving artificial intelligence, misuse of social media, and noncompliance with cybersecurity regulations.</p> <p><a href="https://www.securitymagazine.com/articles/101415-sec-establishes-cyber-and-emerging-technologies-unit">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-6-chinese-hackers-attacking-industrial-organizations-with-fatalrat">Story 6: Chinese Hackers Attacking Industrial Organizations with FatalRAT</h2> <p>A cyber-espionage campaign attributed to Chinese-speaking threat actors is targeting industrial organizations across the Asia-Pacific region using a sophisticated malware known as FatalRAT. The attackers employ multi-stage infection chains and exploit legitimate cloud services to deliver payloads, primarily focusing on sectors like manufacturing, energy, and logistics. The malware enables remote access, data exfiltration, and can execute destructive commands, posing significant risks to operational technology environments.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/hackers-attacking-industrial-organizations-with-fatalrat/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-7-google-phasing-out-sms-based-multi-factor-authentication-in-favor-of-qr-codes">Story 7: Google Phasing Out SMS-Based Multi-Factor Authentication in Favor of QR Codes</h2> <p>Google has announced plans to discontinue the use of SMS text messages for multi-factor authentication (MFA), transitioning instead to QR code-based verification. This move addresses security concerns associated with SMS-based MFA, such as SIM swapping and interception vulnerabilities. Users will soon be required to scan a QR code with their device’s camera app to complete the authentication process, enhancing overall account security.</p> <p><a href="https://www.theregister.com/2025/02/25/google_sms_qr/">Read more</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[2-25-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2-24-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0224/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2-24-25"/><published>2025-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0224</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0224/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-02-24-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="story-1-bybit-confirms-record-breaking-146-million-crypto-heist">Story 1: Bybit Confirms Record-Breaking $146 Million Crypto Heist</h2> <p>Cryptocurrency exchange Bybit has confirmed a record-breaking security breach resulting in the theft of $146 million in cryptocurrency. The attack targeted Bybit’s Ethereum cold wallet and involved sophisticated manipulation of transactions during a routine transfer. Blockchain intelligence firms believe North Korea’s Lazarus Group may be responsible, marking one of the largest crypto thefts in history. Bybit is cooperating with authorities and assures that other wallets remain secure.</p> <p><a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/02/bybit-confirms-record-breaking-146.html">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-2-openai-bans-accounts-misusing-chatgpt-for-surveillance-and-influence-campaigns">Story 2: OpenAI Bans Accounts Misusing ChatGPT for Surveillance and Influence Campaigns</h2> <p>OpenAI has suspended several accounts misusing ChatGPT for developing AI-powered surveillance systems and conducting influence operations. Some of these activities, reportedly linked to Chinese entities, included monitoring social media for anti-China protests in Western countries. Additionally, networks from North Korea and Iran allegedly used ChatGPT for fraudulent job applications and propaganda generation. OpenAI reiterated its commitment to preventing the misuse of its technologies for malicious purposes.</p> <p><a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/02/openai-bans-accounts-misusing-chatgpt.html">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-3-apple-pulls-end-to-end-encryption-from-uk-after-government-demands">Story 3: Apple Pulls End-to-End Encryption from UK After Government Demands</h2> <p>Apple has withdrawn its Advanced Data Protection feature, which offers end-to-end encryption for iCloud data, from users in the United Kingdom. The move follows demands from the UK government for law enforcement access to encrypted data. While existing users can temporarily retain the feature, new activations are blocked, and all users will eventually have to disable it. Apple expressed disappointment, citing the need for robust data protection amid rising cyber threats.</p> <p><a href="https://cyberscoop.com/apple-uk-encryption-advanced-data-protection-privacy/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-4-black-basta-ransomware-group-goes-dark-amid-infighting">Story 4: Black Basta Ransomware Group Goes Dark Amid Infighting</h2> <p>The ransomware group Black Basta has reportedly ceased operations following internal disputes, as revealed by leaked chat logs. The logs, covering September 2023 to September 2024, show disagreements among members over attack strategies and controversial targets. These internal conflicts led to a sharp decline in the group’s activities, challenging their previously perceived image as a highly efficient ransomware organization.</p> <p><a href="https://www.darkreading.com/threat-intelligence/black-basta-goes-dark-infighting-chat-leaks">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-5-data-leak-exposes-topsecs-role-in-chinas-censorship-as-a-service-operations">Story 5: Data Leak Exposes TopSec’s Role in China’s Censorship-as-a-Service Operations</h2> <p>A data leak from Chinese cybersecurity firm TopSec has revealed its involvement in providing censorship-as-a-service solutions to public and private sector clients. The leaked data includes infrastructure details and employee work logs, showing TopSec’s role in monitoring and controlling web content. The company reportedly collaborated with state-owned enterprises to suppress politically sensitive information, highlighting China’s extensive digital censorship practices.</p> <p><a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/02/data-leak-exposes-topsecs-role-in.html">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-6-nsa-allegedly-hacked-northwestern-polytechnical-university-in-china">Story 6: NSA Allegedly Hacked Northwestern Polytechnical University in China</h2> <p>Chinese cybersecurity authorities claim that the U.S. National Security Agency (NSA) conducted a prolonged cyber-espionage campaign against Northwestern Polytechnical University (NPU), a key institution in aerospace and defense research. Reports allege that the NSA’s Tailored Access Operations unit used over 40 custom malware strains between 2020 and 2022 to extract sensitive research data. The alleged operation involved advanced techniques, including zero-day exploits and compromised edge devices.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/nsa-allegedly-hacked-northwestern-polytechnical-university/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-7-cisa-adds-microsoft-power-pages-flaw-to-known-exploited-vulnerabilities-catalog">Story 7: CISA Adds Microsoft Power Pages Flaw to Known Exploited Vulnerabilities Catalog</h2> <p>The U.S. Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) has added a Microsoft Power Pages vulnerability (CVE-2025-24989) to its Known Exploited Vulnerabilities catalog. The flaw allows unauthorized access and control over affected systems. CISA urges organizations using Microsoft Power Pages to apply the latest patches immediately to mitigate exploitation risks.</p> <p><a href="https://securityaffairs.com/174541/hacking/u-s-cisa-adds-microsoft-power-pages-flaw-known-exploited-vulnerabilities-catalog.html">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-8-blackbastagpt--chatgpt-powered-tool-analyzes-ransomware-group-tactics">Story 8: BlackBastaGPT – ChatGPT-Powered Tool Analyzes Ransomware Group Tactics</h2> <p>Researchers have developed BlackBastaGPT, an AI-powered chatbot trained on over one million leaked internal messages from the Black Basta ransomware group. This tool allows cybersecurity professionals to analyze the gang’s operations, including financial strategies and attack methodologies, through natural language queries. The chatbot provides unique insights into the group’s internal communications and negotiation tactics during ransomware incidents.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/blackbastagpt-chatgpt-powered-tool/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-9-paypal-new-address-feature-abused-to-send-phishing-emails">Story 9: PayPal “New Address” Feature Abused to Send Phishing Emails</h2> <p>Cybercriminals are exploiting PayPal’s “New Address” feature to send phishing emails that appear legitimate. Victims receive notifications about a new shipping address linked to a high-value purchase, along with a customer service number to dispute the transaction. The attackers aim to trick users into calling the provided number, leading to potential scams or unauthorized access to sensitive information. Users are advised to verify such alerts directly through their PayPal accounts.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/beware-paypal-new-address-feature-abused-to-send-phishing-emails/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-10-former-nsa-chief-paul-nakasone-warns-us-falling-behind-in-cyberspace">Story 10: Former NSA Chief Paul Nakasone Warns U.S. Falling Behind in Cyberspace</h2> <p>Retired General Paul Nakasone, former head of the NSA and U.S. Cyber Command, warned that the United States is lagging behind adversaries in cyberspace. Speaking at a cybersecurity conference, Nakasone highlighted breaches of U.S. telecommunications and critical infrastructure as evidence of national vulnerabilities. He emphasized the urgent</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Feb 24, 2025]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2-21-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0221/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2-21-25"/><published>2025-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0221</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0221/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="cybersecurity-news-for-feb-21-2125">Cybersecurity News for Feb 21, 2125</h1> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-02-21-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="story-1-salt-typhoon-deploys-jumbledpath-malware-to-spy-on-us-telecom-providers">Story 1: Salt Typhoon Deploys ‘JumbledPath’ Malware to Spy on U.S. Telecom Providers</h2> <p>The Chinese state-sponsored hacking group known as Salt Typhoon has been identified deploying a custom malware strain dubbed ‘JumbledPath’ to infiltrate U.S. telecommunications providers. This sophisticated malware enables the group to intercept communications and exfiltrate sensitive data, posing significant threats to national security and critical infrastructure. The campaign underscores the persistent vulnerabilities within the telecom sector and the advanced capabilities of nation-state actors in cyber espionage.</p> <p><a href="https://securityaffairs.com/174460/apt/salt-typhoon-custom-malware-jumbledpath-to-spy-u-s-telecom-providers.html">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-2-pci-dss-40-mandates-dmarc-implementation-by-march-31">Story 2: PCI DSS 4.0 Mandates DMARC Implementation by March 31</h2> <p>The Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS) version 4.0 has introduced a new requirement for organizations to implement Domain-based Message Authentication, Reporting, and Conformance (DMARC) by March 31. This mandate aims to enhance email security by preventing domain spoofing and phishing attacks, thereby protecting cardholder data from unauthorized access. Organizations are urged to configure DMARC policies appropriately to comply with the standard and strengthen their cybersecurity posture.</p> <p><a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/02/pci-dss-40-mandates-dmarc-by-31st-march.html">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-3-surge-in-fake-captcha-attacks-exploiting-user-trust">Story 3: Surge in Fake CAPTCHA Attacks Exploiting User Trust</h2> <p>Cybersecurity experts have observed a significant increase in attacks utilizing fake CAPTCHA verifications to deceive users into clicking on malicious links or downloading malware. These deceptive tactics exploit the common trust users place in CAPTCHA systems, leading to unauthorized access and data breaches. Users are advised to remain vigilant and verify the authenticity of CAPTCHA prompts, especially when encountered on unfamiliar websites.</p> <p><a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3829416/fake-captcha-attacks-are-increasing-say-experts.html">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-4-evolving-mobile-phishing-threats-exploit-platform-vulnerabilities">Story 4: Evolving Mobile Phishing Threats Exploit Platform Vulnerabilities</h2> <p>Recent research indicates that mobile phishing attacks are becoming increasingly sophisticated, exploiting specific vulnerabilities inherent to mobile platforms. Attackers are leveraging SMS, QR codes, and mobile-optimized websites to deliver phishing content, making detection more challenging. The reduced screen size and limited URL visibility on mobile devices contribute to the success of these attacks, emphasizing the need for enhanced mobile security measures.</p> <p><a href="https://www.securitymagazine.com/articles/101408-mobile-phishing-threats-are-evolving-according-to-new-research">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-5-proof-of-concept-exploit-released-for-ivanti-endpoint-manager-vulnerabilities">Story 5: Proof-of-Concept Exploit Released for Ivanti Endpoint Manager Vulnerabilities</h2> <p>A proof-of-concept (PoC) exploit has been publicly released for multiple critical vulnerabilities in Ivanti Endpoint Manager. These flaws allow unauthenticated attackers to execute arbitrary code and gain control over affected systems. Organizations utilizing this platform are strongly advised to apply the available patches immediately to mitigate potential exploitation risks.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/ivanti-endpoint-manager-vulnerabilities-proof-of-concept-poc-exploit-released/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-6-internal-chat-logs-of-black-basta-ransomware-gang-leaked">Story 6: Internal Chat Logs of Black Basta Ransomware Gang Leaked</h2> <p>Internal chat logs belonging to the Black Basta ransomware group have been leaked online, providing insights into the gang’s operations, negotiation tactics, and organizational structure. The leak, which includes discussions about ransom demands and victim interactions, offers a rare glimpse into the inner workings of a prominent cybercriminal organization. This exposure could potentially aid law enforcement agencies in their efforts to combat ransomware activities.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/black-basta-ransomware-gang-s-internal-chat-logs-leak-online/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-7-medusa-ransomware-gang-demands-2-million-from-uk-health-provider">Story 7: Medusa Ransomware Gang Demands $2 Million from UK Health Provider</h2> <p>The Medusa ransomware group has demanded a $2 million ransom from HCRG Care Group, a UK-based private health and social services provider. The attackers claim to have exfiltrated 2.275 terabytes of sensitive data, including personal identification documents and staff records. HCRG is currently investigating the incident and has implemented containment measures to prevent further unauthorized access.</p> <p><a href="https://www.theregister.com/2025/02/20/medusa_hcrg_ransomware/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-8-zhong-malware-exploits-anydesk-to-target-fintech-and-cryptocurrency-sectors">Story 8: ‘Zhong’ Malware Exploits AnyDesk to Target Fintech and Cryptocurrency Sectors</h2> <p>A newly identified malware strain, dubbed ‘Zhong,’ has been observed exploiting the AnyDesk remote desktop tool to infiltrate systems within the fintech and cryptocurrency industries. The malware employs social engineering tactics, such as phishing emails with malicious attachments, to gain initial access. Once inside, it steals credentials and establishes persistent remote access, posing significant risks to financial data security.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/new-zhong-malware-exploit-anydesk-tool/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-9-deepseek-found-sharing-user-data-with-bytedance">Story 9: DeepSeek Found Sharing User Data with ByteDance</h2> <p>Investigations have revealed that the AI application DeepSeek has been transmitting user data to ByteDance, the parent company of TikTok, without user consent. This unauthorized data sharing raises serious privacy concerns, especially given ByteDance’s previous controversies regarding data handling practices. Users are advised to exercise caution and consider removing the DeepSeek app from their devices to protect their personal information.</p> <p><a href="https://www.malwarebytes.com/blog/news/2025/02/deepseek-found-to-be-sharing-user-data-with-tiktok-parent-company-bytedance">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-10-citrix-netscaler-vulnerability-allows-unauthorized-command-execution">Story 10: Citrix NetScaler Vulnerability Allows Unauthorized Command Execution</h2> <p>A high-severity vulnerability has been identified in Citrix NetScaler, potentially allowing authenticated attackers to execute unauthorized commands on affected systems. This flaw, resulting from improper privilege management, could lead to full system compromise if exploited. Administrators are urged to apply the latest patches promptly to secure their networks against potential threats.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/netscaler-vulnerability-unauthorized-command-execution/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-11-apt-c-28-group-deploys-fileless-rokrat-malware-in-new-cyber-attack">Story 11: APT-C-28 Group Deploys Fileless RokRat Malware in New Cyber Attack</h2> <p>The APT-C-28 threat group, also known as ScarCruft, has launched a new cyber espionage campaign utilizing a fileless version of the RokRat malware. This sophisticated attack involves phishing emails containing malicious LNK files that execute obfuscated PowerShell scripts, enabling the group to steal sensitive information without leaving traditional malware footprints. Organizations are advised to implement advanced threat detection mechanisms to identify and mitigate such stealthy attacks.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/apt-c-28-group-launched-new-cyber-attack-with-fileless-rokrat-malware/">Read more</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Feb 21, 2025]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CyberNews 2-20-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews020/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CyberNews 2-20-25"/><published>2025-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews020</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews020/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="cybersecurity-news-for-feb-20-2025">Cybersecurity News for Feb 20, 2025</h1> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-02-20-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="story-1-russian-groups-target-signal-messenger-in-espionage-campaign">Story 1: Russian Groups Target Signal Messenger in Espionage Campaign</h2> <p>Russian-affiliated threat groups, including UNC5792 and UNC4221, are actively targeting users of the Signal messaging app, particularly those involved in sensitive military and governmental communications related to Ukraine. These attackers employ phishing techniques, such as sending malicious QR codes that, when scanned, link the victim’s Signal account to a device controlled by the attackers, enabling real-time message interception. Google’s Threat Intelligence Group has observed this activity and anticipates that such tactics may become more widespread, potentially affecting users beyond the current conflict zone.</p> <p><a href="https://www.darkreading.com/mobile-security/russian-groups-target-signal-messenger-in-spy-campaign">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-2-russian-cryptobytes-hackers-exploiting-windows-machines">Story 2: Russian CryptoBytes Hackers Exploiting Windows Machines</h2> <p>The Russian cybercriminal group known as CryptoBytes has intensified its ransomware campaigns by deploying a modified version of the UxCryptor malware. Targeting Windows systems globally, these attacks utilize advanced anti-analysis techniques to evade detection and employ psychological pressure tactics to coerce victims into paying cryptocurrency ransoms. Researchers have observed that the group leverages leaked ransomware builders, lowering the barrier for entry and suggesting a potential franchise-style operation.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/russian-cryptobytes-hackers-exploiting-windows-machines/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-3-phishing-remains-the-preferred-technique-among-threat-actors">Story 3: Phishing Remains the Preferred Technique Among Threat Actors</h2> <p>A recent report from Darktrace highlights that phishing continues to be the most favored method among cybercriminals, with over 30.4 million phishing emails detected between December 2023 and December 2024. Notably, 70% of these emails bypassed DMARC authentication, and 55% evaded existing security measures before detection. The report also notes a rise in sophisticated tactics, including AI-generated content and the exploitation of trusted third-party services to enhance the credibility of phishing attempts.</p> <p><a href="https://www.securitymagazine.com/articles/101405-phishing-remains-the-preferred-technique-among-threat-actors">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-4-north-korean-hackers-using-dropbox-and-powershell-scripts">Story 4: North Korean Hackers Using Dropbox and PowerShell Scripts</h2> <p>The North Korean state-sponsored group Kimsuky (APT43) has been conducting cyber espionage campaigns targeting South Korean entities and cryptocurrency users. These attacks involve phishing emails containing malicious LNK files that execute obfuscated PowerShell scripts, utilizing Dropbox’s API for payload delivery and data exfiltration. This strategy allows the attackers to bypass traditional security defenses by leveraging trusted cloud services and living-off-the-land techniques.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/north-korean-hackers-using-dropbox-powershell-scripts/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-5-microsoft-recognized-as-leader-in-cyber-physical-systems-protection">Story 5: Microsoft Recognized as Leader in Cyber-Physical Systems Protection</h2> <p>Microsoft has been named a Leader in the 2025 Gartner Magic Quadrant for Cyber-Physical Systems Protection Platforms. This recognition underscores Microsoft’s commitment to providing comprehensive security solutions that bridge the gap between IT and operational technology environments. Their approach emphasizes the integration of advanced threat protection, unified security management, and robust compliance features to safeguard critical infrastructure and cyber-physical systems.</p> <p><a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/security/blog/2025/02/19/microsoft-is-named-a-leader-in-the-2025-gartner-magic-quadrant-for-cyber-physical-systems-protection-platforms/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-6-fake-browser-updates-deploy-netsupport-rat-and-stealc-malware">Story 6: Fake Browser Updates Deploy NetSupport RAT and StealC Malware</h2> <p>A sophisticated malware campaign attributed to the threat actor SmartApeSG has been distributing NetSupport RAT and StealC malware through fake browser update notifications. Unsuspecting users are lured into downloading malicious payloads from compromised websites, leading to remote access tool deployment and credential theft. The attackers employ advanced evasion techniques, including DLL side-loading, to maintain persistence and avoid detection.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/beware-new-fake-browser-updates/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-7-phishing-attack-hides-javascript-using-invisible-unicode-trick">Story 7: Phishing Attack Hides JavaScript Using Invisible Unicode Trick</h2> <p>Cybercriminals have developed a new obfuscation method that utilizes invisible Unicode characters to conceal malicious JavaScript code within phishing emails. This technique involves replacing binary values with non-visible Unicode characters, rendering the malicious payload virtually undetectable in the email’s source code. Such sophisticated obfuscation poses significant challenges for traditional security filters and underscores the need for advanced threat detection mechanisms.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/phishing-attack-hides-javascript-using-invisible-unicode-trick/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-8-ghost-ransomware-breaches-organizations-in-70-countries">Story 8: Ghost Ransomware Breaches Organizations in 70 Countries</h2> <p>The Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) and the FBI have issued a joint advisory regarding the Ghost ransomware, which has compromised organizations across more than 70 countries. The attackers exploit outdated software and firmware in internet-facing services, affecting various sectors, including healthcare, government, education, and manufacturing. The advisory emphasizes the importance of maintaining up-to-date systems and implementing robust security measures to mitigate such threats.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/cisa-and-fbi-ghost-ransomware-breached-orgs-in-70-countries/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-9-critical-microsoft-bing-vulnerability-allows-remote-code-execution">Story 9: Critical Microsoft Bing Vulnerability Allows Remote Code Execution</h2> <p>Microsoft has addressed a critical security flaw in its Bing search engine, identified as CVE-2025-21355, which could have permitted unauthorized remote code execution. The vulnerability stemmed from inadequate authentication mechanisms in a critical Bing service component, potentially allowing attackers to compromise backend systems and manipulate search results. Microsoft has fully mitigated the issue on its servers, and users are advised to remain vigilant and ensure their systems are updated.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/microsoft-bing-remote-code-execution-vulnerability/">Read more</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Feb 20, 2025]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CyberNews 2-19-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0219/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CyberNews 2-19-25"/><published>2025-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0219</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0219/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="cybersecurity-news-for-feb-19-2025">Cybersecurity News for Feb 19, 2025</h1> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-02-19-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="story-1-️pan-os-vulnerability-actively-exploited-in-the-wild️">Story 1: ⚠️PAN-OS Vulnerability Actively Exploited in the Wild⚠️</h2> <p>The Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) has issued an urgent alert regarding the active exploitation of a high-severity authentication bypass vulnerability (CVE-2025-0108) in Palo Alto Networks’ PAN-OS. This flaw allows unauthenticated attackers to bypass authentication controls and execute specific PHP scripts, potentially compromising system integrity. Organizations using affected PAN-OS versions are strongly advised to apply the latest patches and restrict management interface access to trusted internal IP addresses. The EPSS Score for these vulnerabilities is -</p> <blockquote> <p>EPSS Score for <strong><em>CVE-2025-0111</em></strong><span style="color:green"> 0.04%</span><br/> <a href="https://security.paloaltonetworks.com/CVE-2025-0111">Paloalto Security Advisory: CVE-2025-0111 PAN-OS: Authenticated File Read Vulnerability in the Management Web Interface</a><br/> EPSS Score for <strong><em>CVE-2025-0108</em></strong><span style="color:green"> 0.04%</span><br/> <a href="https://security.paloaltonetworks.com/CVE-2025-0108">Paloalto Security Advisory: CVE-2025-0108 PAN-OS: Authentication Bypass in the Management Web Interface</a><br/> EPSS Score for <strong><em>CVE-2024-9474</em></strong><span style="color:red"> 97.48%</span><br/> <a href="https://security.paloaltonetworks.com/CVE-2024-9474">Paloalto Security Advisory: CVE-2025-0108 PAN-OS: Privilege Escalation (PE) Vulnerability in the Web Management Interface</a></p> </blockquote> <h4 id="read-more">Read More</h4> <ul> <li><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/pan-os-vulnerability-actively-exploited/" target="_blank">Cybersecuirty News</a></li> <li><a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/02/cisa-adds-palo-alto-networks-and.html" target="_blank">The Hacker News</a></li> <li><a href="https://www.greynoise.io/blog/greynoise-observes-active-exploitation-of-pan-os-authentication-bypass-vulnerability-cve-2025-0108#GreyNoise" target="_blank">greynoise.io active IPs</a></li> </ul> <p><img src="/assets/img/security/paloalto_cve2025-0108.png" width="800" height="600"/></p> <h2 id="story-2-sonicwall-sonicos-sslvpn-zero-day-actively-exploited">Story 2: SonicWall SonicOS SSLVPN Zero-Day Actively Exploited</h2> <p>The U.S. Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) has issued a warning about a critical zero-day vulnerability (CVE-2024-53704) in SonicWall’s SonicOS. This flaw allows remote attackers to hijack active SSL VPN sessions without credentials and is currently being exploited in the wild. CISA mandates that federal agencies patch affected systems by March 11, 2025, and recommends immediate remediation for all organizations using SonicWall devices.</p> <ul> <li>EPSS Score for CVE-2024-53704<span style="color:green"> 0.05%</span></li> </ul> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/sonicwall-sonicos-sslvpn-rce-vulnerability-actively-exploited-in-the-wild/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-3-juniper-networks-patches-critical-authentication-bypass">Story 3: Juniper Networks Patches Critical Authentication Bypass</h2> <p>Juniper Networks has released patches for a critical vulnerability (CVE-2025-21589) affecting its Session Smart Router (SSR) devices. Discovered during internal security testing, this flaw allows network-based attackers to bypass authentication and gain administrative control over the devices. Administrators are advised to update to the latest firmware versions to secure their networks against potential exploits.</p> <ul> <li>CVSS v3.1 Score for CVE-2025-21589<span style="color:red"> 9.8</span></li> <li>CVSS v4 Score for CVE-2024-53704<span style="color:red"> 9.3</span></li> </ul> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/juniper-patches-critical-auth-bypass-in-session-smart-routers/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-4-openssh-fixes-flaws-enabling-mitm-and-dos-attacks">Story 4: OpenSSH Fixes Flaws Enabling MitM and DoS Attacks</h2> <p>OpenSSH has addressed two vulnerabilities that could facilitate man-in-the-middle (MitM) and denial-of-service (DoS) attacks. Researchers from Qualys identified these flaws, which, when combined, could allow attackers to bypass server key verification in OpenSSH clients. Users are encouraged to update their OpenSSH installations to prevent potential exploitation.</p> <p><a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3827268/openssh-fixes-two-flaws-that-enable-a-man-in-the-middle-attack-and-denial-of-service.html">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-5-ransomware-attack-shuts-down-five-michigan-casinos">Story 5: Ransomware Attack Shuts Down Five Michigan Casinos</h2> <p>A ransomware attack has forced the closure of five Kewadin Casinos across Michigan, affecting locations in Manistique, Hessel, St. Ignace, Christmas, and Sault Ste. Marie. While hotels remain open to current guests, new check-ins are suspended. The Sault Tribe of Chippewa Indians, which operates the casinos, is working with third-party experts to restore systems and investigate the breach.</p> <p><a href="https://www.securitymagazine.com/articles/101395-ransomware-attack-hits-5-michigan-casinos-shuts-them-down">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-6-chinese-hackers-exploit-microsoft-app-v-tool-to-evade-detection">Story 6: Chinese Hackers Exploit Microsoft App-V Tool to Evade Detection</h2> <p>The Chinese advanced persistent threat group “Mustang Panda” has been observed abusing Microsoft’s Application Virtualization (App-V) Injector utility to inject malicious payloads into legitimate processes. This technique helps the attackers evade detection by antivirus software. The group primarily targets government entities in the Asia-Pacific region through spear-phishing campaigns.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/chinese-hackers-abuse-microsoft-app-v-tool-to-evade-antivirus/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-7-weaponized-pdfs-deliver-lumma-infostealer-to-educational-institutions">Story 7: Weaponized PDFs Deliver Lumma InfoStealer to Educational Institutions</h2> <p>A new campaign targeting educational institutions involves the distribution of weaponized PDF documents embedded with Lumma InfoStealer malware. These malicious PDFs contain LNK files that, when executed, initiate a multi-stage infection process to steal sensitive data. Educational organizations are advised to implement robust cybersecurity measures to defend against such threats.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/weaponized-pdf-documents-deliver-lumma-infostealer/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-8-new-snake-keylogger-variant-targets-windows-systems">Story 8: New Snake Keylogger Variant Targets Windows Systems</h2> <p>A new variant of the Snake Keylogger malware is infecting Windows users, particularly in Asia and Europe. This version utilizes the AutoIt scripting language to deploy itself, adding obfuscation layers to evade detection. Once installed, it logs keystrokes, captures screenshots, and steals clipboard data, compromising user credentials and sensitive information.</p> <p><a href="https://www.theregister.com/2025/02/19/new_snake_keylogger_infects_windows/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-9-venture-capital-firm-insight-partners-suffers-cyberattack">Story 9: Venture Capital Firm Insight Partners Suffers Cyberattack</h2> <p>New York-based venture capital and private equity firm Insight Partners has disclosed a cyberattack on its systems. The breach, resulting from a sophisticated social engineering attack on January 16, 2025, prompted the firm to engage third-party cybersecurity experts and notify law enforcement. While the investigation is ongoing, there is no evidence of continued unauthorized access.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/venture-capital-giant-insight-partners-hit-by-cyberattack/">Read more</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Feb 19, 2025]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CyberNews 2-18-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0218/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CyberNews 2-18-25"/><published>2025-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0218</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0218/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="cybersecurity-news-for-feb-18-2025">Cybersecurity News for Feb 18, 2025</h1> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-02-18-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Todays stories in audio form </div> <h1 id="cybersecurity-news-summary">Cybersecurity News Summary</h1> <h2 id="story-1-45m-grant-bolsters-ua-little-rocks-cybersecurity-education">Story 1: $4.5M Grant Bolsters UA Little Rock’s Cybersecurity Education</h2> <p>The University of Arkansas at Little Rock has received a $4.5 million grant to enhance its cybersecurity education programs. This funding aims to develop advanced curricula, provide scholarships, and establish partnerships with industry leaders to prepare students for the growing demand in the cybersecurity sector. The initiative underscores the university’s commitment to addressing the national shortage of cybersecurity professionals.</p> <p><a href="https://armoneyandpolitics.com/little-rock-cybersecurity-education/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-2-ukraine-launches-major-cyber-attack-on-russian-gas-infrastructure">Story 2: Ukraine Launches Major Cyber Attack on Russian Gas Infrastructure</h2> <p>Ukrainian cyber forces have reportedly initiated a significant cyber attack targeting Russia’s gas infrastructure. This offensive aims to disrupt the operational capabilities of Russian energy facilities, marking a strategic move in the ongoing cyber warfare between the two nations. The attack highlights the escalating use of cyber operations in geopolitical conflicts.</p> <p><a href="https://i-hls.com/archives/128031">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-3-hidden-malware-in-wordpress-websites-allows-remote-code-execution">Story 3: Hidden Malware in WordPress Websites Allows Remote Code Execution</h2> <p>Security researchers have uncovered a sophisticated malware campaign targeting WordPress websites. Attackers are embedding malicious code within the ‘mu-plugins’ directory, enabling remote execution of code, full server compromise, data theft, and persistent control over infected sites. Website owners are urged to implement file integrity monitoring and enforce strict security measures to mitigate this threat.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/hidden-malware-in-wordpress-websites/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-4-dutch-police-seize-127-servers-of-bulletproof-hosting-service-zservers">Story 4: Dutch Police Seize 127 Servers of Bulletproof Hosting Service Zservers</h2> <p>Dutch authorities have seized 127 servers belonging to the bulletproof hosting provider Zservers/XHost. This action follows sanctions imposed by the US, UK, and Australia against the service for supporting Russian ransomware operations, particularly the LockBit group. The crackdown aims to disrupt cybercriminal infrastructure and deter future illicit activities.</p> <p><a href="https://securityaffairs.com/174321/hacking/dutch-police-seized-127-servers-bulletproof-hosting-service-zservers-xhost.html">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-5-new-data-stealing-malware-exploits-microsoft-outlook">Story 5: New Data-Stealing Malware Exploits Microsoft Outlook</h2> <p>A newly identified family of data-stealing malware is leveraging Microsoft Outlook to compromise systems. The malware initiates attacks through stolen credentials, exploiting Outlook’s features to disseminate malicious content and exfiltrate sensitive information. Organizations are advised to strengthen email security protocols and monitor for unusual activities within their networks.</p> <p><a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3826217/new-family-of-data-stealing-malware-leverages-microsoft-outlook.html">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-6-ransomhub-ransomware-expands-to-multiple-operating-systems">Story 6: RansomHub Ransomware Expands to Multiple Operating Systems</h2> <p>The RansomHub ransomware group has evolved its tactics to target a range of operating systems, including Windows, VMware ESXi, Linux, and FreeBSD. By developing platform-specific encryption methods and exploiting known vulnerabilities, the group has significantly broadened its attack surface. Entities across various sectors are urged to apply security patches promptly and implement robust defense strategies.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/ransomhub-evolves-to-attack-windows-esxi-linux/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-7-the-high-stakes-disconnect-in-icsot-security">Story 7: The High-Stakes Disconnect in ICS/OT Security</h2> <p>Recent incidents have exposed a critical gap in securing Industrial Control Systems (ICS) and Operational Technology (OT) environments. Traditional IT security measures often fall short in these settings, necessitating specialized controls and dedicated budgets to protect critical infrastructure. Implementing tailored cybersecurity strategies is essential to address the unique challenges posed by ICS/OT systems.</p> <p><a href="https://www.darkreading.com/ics-ot-security/the-high-stakes-disconnect-in-ics-ot-security">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-8-ransomware-gangs-accelerate-encryption-timelines">Story 8: Ransomware Gangs Accelerate Encryption Timelines</h2> <p>New research indicates that ransomware groups are reducing the time between initial network infiltration and system encryption to an average of 17 hours. This rapid execution leaves organizations with a narrow window to detect and respond to attacks. Enhanced monitoring and swift incident response protocols are critical to mitigating the impact of such accelerated ransomware operations.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/ransomware-gangs-encrypt-systems-after-17hrs/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-9-microsoft-uncovers-new-xcsset-macos-malware-variant">Story 9: Microsoft Uncovers New XCSSET macOS Malware Variant</h2> <p>Microsoft has identified a new variant of the XCSSET malware targeting macOS systems. This iteration employs advanced obfuscation techniques, updated persistence methods, and novel infection strategies, enhancing its ability to steal data from applications like Notes and exfiltrate system information. Users are encouraged to maintain up-to-date security measures to defend against this evolving threat.</p> <p><a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/02/microsoft-uncovers-new-xcsset-macos.html">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-10-x-blocks-signal-contact-links-flags-them-as-malicious">Story 10: X Blocks Signal Contact Links, Flags Them as Malicious</h2> <p>The social media platform X (formerly Twitter) has begun blocking links to “Signal.me,” a URL used by the Signal encrypted messaging service to share contact information. Attempts to post these links result in error messages citing spam or malicious content concerns. This development affects users’ ability to share Signal contact links on the platform, prompting discussions about content moderation practices.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/x-now-blocks-signal-contact-links-flags-them-as-malicious/">Read more</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Feb 18, 2025]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CyberNews 2-17-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0217/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CyberNews 2-17-25"/><published>2025-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0217</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0217/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="cybersecurity-news-for-feb-17-2025">Cybersecurity News for Feb 17, 2025</h1> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-02-17-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Todays stories in audio form </div> <h1 id="cybersecurity-news-summary">Cybersecurity News Summary</h1> <h2 id="story-1-hackers-exploit-microsoft-teams-meeting-invites-for-phishing-attacks">Story 1: Hackers Exploit Microsoft Teams Meeting Invites for Phishing Attacks</h2> <p>Cybercriminals, identified as the Storm-2372 group, are conducting sophisticated phishing attacks by abusing Microsoft Teams meeting invites. Active since August 2024, these attackers impersonate officials from organizations like the U.S. Department of State and the European Parliament. They lure victims into authenticating through Microsoft’s Device Code workflow, enabling unauthorized access to Microsoft 365 accounts without requiring passwords or multi-factor authentication. This method leverages legitimate Microsoft infrastructure, making detection challenging.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/microsoft-teams-meeting-invite-abuse/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-2-russian-threat-actors-target-microsoft-365-accounts-via-device-code-authentication">Story 2: Russian Threat Actors Target Microsoft 365 Accounts via Device Code Authentication</h2> <p>Security researchers have uncovered multiple Russian threat actors conducting social engineering and spear-phishing campaigns aimed at compromising Microsoft 365 accounts. These groups exploit the Device Code Authentication feature, directing victims to legitimate Microsoft URLs and prompting them to enter device codes. Once authenticated, attackers gain unauthorized access to accounts, bypassing traditional security measures. The campaigns have proven highly effective, surpassing traditional phishing methods in success rates.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/multiple-russian-actors-attacking-orgs-to-hack-microsoft-365-accounts/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-3-ransomware-as-a-service-fuels-fourfold-increase-in-attacks">Story 3: Ransomware-as-a-Service Fuels Fourfold Increase in Attacks</h2> <p>The rise of Ransomware-as-a-Service (RaaS) platforms has led to a significant increase in ransomware attacks, with incidents quadrupling over the past year. These platforms enable even low-skilled attackers to launch sophisticated campaigns by providing ready-made ransomware tools. The growing sophistication, agility, and evasive nature of these attacks pose substantial challenges to cybersecurity defenses. Organizations are urged to adopt advanced security measures to combat this escalating threat.</p> <p><a href="https://www.cyberdaily.au/security/11719-ransomware-as-a-service-actors-drive-four-times-increase-in-ransomware-attacks">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-4-cisa-issues-20-advisories-on-industrial-control-system-vulnerabilities">Story 4: CISA Issues 20 Advisories on Industrial Control System Vulnerabilities</h2> <p>The Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) has released twenty new advisories addressing critical vulnerabilities in Industrial Control Systems (ICS). The advisories cover products from vendors such as Siemens, ORing, mySCADA, and Mitsubishi Electric. Each advisory details specific vulnerabilities that could allow attackers to disrupt operations, gain unauthorized access, or execute malicious code. Organizations using these systems are strongly advised to apply recommended patches and mitigation strategies to secure their infrastructure.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/cisa-releases-20-ics-advisories/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-5-earthkapre-apt-employs-weaponized-pdfs-to-compromise-windows-systems">Story 5: EarthKapre APT Employs Weaponized PDFs to Compromise Windows Systems</h2> <p>The advanced persistent threat group known as EarthKapre, also referred to as RedCurl, has been targeting private-sector organizations, especially in the legal sector. They employ phishing emails disguised as job applications containing malicious PDF attachments. These PDFs lead victims to download files that, once executed, initiate a multi-stage malware infection. The attack chain includes sophisticated techniques like DLL side-loading and multi-stage encryption, aiming to exfiltrate sensitive data and conduct corporate espionage.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/earthkapre-apt-drops-weaponized-pdf-to-compromise-windows-systems/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-6-xelera-ransomware-targets-job-seekers-with-malicious-word-documents">Story 6: XELERA Ransomware Targets Job Seekers with Malicious Word Documents</h2> <p>A new ransomware campaign dubbed “XELERA” is specifically targeting job seekers by distributing malicious Word documents disguised as job offers from reputable organizations. Upon opening these documents, an infection chain is triggered, leading to the deployment of ransomware that encrypts the victim’s data. The attackers demand a ransom in cryptocurrency for data recovery. This campaign underscores the importance of vigilance and caution when handling unsolicited job offers and attachments.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/xelera-ransomware-attacking-job-seekers/">Read more</a></p> <h2 id="story-7-whoami-attack-exploits-aws-ami-name-confusion-for-remote-code-execution">Story 7: ‘whoAMI’ Attack Exploits AWS AMI Name Confusion for Remote Code Execution</h2> <p>Cybersecurity researchers have identified a novel attack, termed “whoAMI,” that exploits name confusion in Amazon Web Services (AWS) Amazon Machine Images (AMIs). Attackers publish malicious AMIs with names matching legitimate ones. If developers do not specify the owner when searching for AMIs, they might inadvertently use the malicious image. This can grant attackers remote code execution within the victim’s AWS environment. AWS has addressed this issue, and users are advised to specify image owners explicitly to prevent such attacks.</p> <p><a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/02/new-whoami-attack-exploits-aws-ami-name.html">Read more</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Feb 17, 2025]]></summary></entry></feed>