<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-11-20T12:40:32+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DJBSec, CISSP</title><subtitle>DJBSec is an IT veteran with over 25 years of experience in IT and Cyber Security </subtitle><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2025-11-20</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews1120/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2025-11-20"/><published>2025-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews1120</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews1120/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-2025-11-20.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="1-attackers-hit-palo-alto-networks-globalprotect-vpn-portals">1. Attackers Hit Palo Alto Networks’ GlobalProtect VPN Portals</h2> <p>Hackers launched over 2.3 million malicious sessions against Palo Alto Networks’ GlobalProtect VPN portals between November 14–20, marking a 40-fold surge within 24 hours. Attackers targeted the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">/global-protect/login.esp</code> path, using brute-force attempts to gain unauthorized access to corporate networks. Telemetry shows this is the highest spike in GlobalProtect scanning seen in 90 days. Organizations are urged to harden VPN authentication, enforce MFA, and review access logs for signs of intrusion.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/palo-alto-vpn-under-attack/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="2-palo-alto-to-acquire-chronosphere-for-335-billion">2. Palo Alto to Acquire Chronosphere for $3.35 Billion</h2> <p>Palo Alto Networks announced plans to acquire observability company Chronosphere for $3.35 billion. The acquisition aims to enhance Palo Alto’s unified security and observability strategy by integrating Chronosphere’s large-scale monitoring and analytics capabilities. This move aligns with the industry trend of consolidating observability and cybersecurity into a single operational ecosystem. Analysts expect Palo Alto to offer tighter SIEM, monitoring, and automation integrations as a result.</p> <p><a href="https://cyberscoop.com/palo-alto-networks-to-acquire-observability-firm-chronosphere-for-3-35-billion/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="3-fortinet-hit-with-another-fortiweb-zero-day-flaw">3. Fortinet Hit with Another FortiWeb Zero-Day Flaw</h2> <p>Fortinet is dealing with yet another FortiWeb WAF zero-day vulnerability that allows authenticated attackers to execute OS-level commands. The flaw follows multiple recent zero-days affecting the company’s product line, raising concerns over vendor patch velocity and disclosure practices. Researchers warn that some versions may have been silently patched before public advisories. Organizations are urged to patch immediately and hunt for rogue admin accounts or suspicious system activity.</p> <p><a href="https://www.darkreading.com/vulnerabilities-threats/fortinet-woes-continue-another-waf-zero-day-flaw">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="4-ai-agentic-systems-increase-cyber-attack-surface">4. AI “Agentic Systems” Increase Cyber Attack Surface</h2> <p>New research shows that AI agents capable of autonomous decision-making and code execution significantly expand the enterprise attack surface. Attackers can exploit flaws in agent tools—such as VS Code extensions exploiting CVE-2025-53773—to run unauthorized tasks. As organizations adopt AI-driven automation, these agents become privileged entities that require stricter access controls. Security leaders are being urged to treat AI platforms like high-risk operational systems.</p> <p><a href="https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/ai-attack-surface-agents-cyber-stakes">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="5-cisa-adds-google-chromium-v8-flaw-to-kev-catalog">5. CISA Adds Google Chromium V8 Flaw to KEV Catalog</h2> <p>CISA added a Google Chromium V8 type-confusion flaw (CVE-2025-13223) to its Known Exploited Vulnerabilities catalog. The bug allows remote code execution through malicious web pages and has confirmed active exploitation in the wild. Federal agencies must patch the vulnerability by December 10, 2025, under binding operational directive rules. Enterprises using Chrome or Chromium-based browsers should prioritize updates immediately.</p> <p><a href="https://securityaffairs.com/184856/hacking/u-s-cisa-adds-a-google-chromium-v8-flaw-to-its-known-exploited-vulnerabilities-catalog.html">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="6-western-nations-sanction-bulletproof-hosting-provider-media-land">6. Western Nations Sanction “Bulletproof” Hosting Provider Media Land</h2> <p>The U.S., U.K., and Australia jointly sanctioned Russia’s Media Land LLC, an infrastructure provider accused of supporting ransomware gangs. The company allegedly supplied resilient hosting, DDoS services, and IP infrastructure to groups like LockBit and BlackSuit. Officials say the sanctions aim to disrupt the cybercrime ecosystem by targeting enablers—not just threat actors. Firms are advised to verify that none of their vendors or upstream hosts rely on Media Land infrastructure.</p> <p><a href="https://cyberscoop.com/bulletproof-hosting-providers-sanctions-mitigation-media-land/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="7-operation-wrthug-hijacks-50000-asus-routers">7. Operation WrtHug Hijacks 50,000 ASUS Routers</h2> <p>Researchers uncovered a global botnet operation—dubbed “WrtHug”—that hijacked over 50,000 ASUS routers. Attackers exploited known vulnerabilities in outdated or end-of-life firmware to conscript devices into a large anonymization and proxy infrastructure. These routers are being used to relay malicious traffic and disguise attacker origins. Security experts warn organizations to patch or replace exposed consumer-grade hardware immediately.</p> <p><a href="https://securityaffairs.com/184841/cyber-crime/operation-wrthug-hijacks-50000-asus-routers-to-build-a-global-botnet.html">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="8-amazon-warns-about-cyber-enabled-kinetic-targeting">8. Amazon Warns About Cyber-Enabled Kinetic Targeting</h2> <p>Amazon’s threat intelligence team reported that nation-state hackers are increasingly using cyber intrusions to support physical, kinetic operations. Adversaries have leveraged compromised CCTV feeds, maritime systems, and GPS tools to coordinate real-world attacks. The report highlights the blurring boundary between cyber operations and battlefield targeting. Organizations managing critical infrastructure are urged to assume their digital systems have physical-world consequences.</p> <p><a href="https://cyberscoop.com/amazon-cyber-enabled-kinetic-targeting/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="9-sysmon-to-become-a-native-windows-feature">9. Sysmon to Become a Native Windows Feature</h2> <p>Microsoft announced that Sysmon—one of the most widely used Windows telemetry tools—will become a built-in component of Windows 11 and Server 2025. This shift means enterprises will no longer need custom deployments or manual installation to collect deep process and event telemetry. Native integration is expected to significantly boost security monitoring capabilities across enterprise fleets. Administrators should prepare to update Sysmon configs and SIEM ingestion rules.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/sysmon-tool-windows/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="10-us-sanctions-russian-hosting-provider-media-land-over-ransomware-activity">10. U.S. Sanctions Russian Hosting Provider Media Land Over Ransomware Activity</h2> <p>The U.S. Treasury Department issued sanctions against Media Land, accusing the provider of enabling ransomware infrastructure. The company allegedly supported operators behind major ransomware families and sold “bulletproof” hosting designed to evade law enforcement. The sanctions block U.S. interactions with the provider and freeze any associated assets. Officials hope the move will disrupt cybercrime logistics and reduce attacker resilience.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/us-sanctions-russian-bulletproof-hosting-provider-media-land-over-ransomware-ties/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="11-hackers-actively-exploiting-7-zip-vulnerability">11. Hackers Actively Exploiting 7-Zip Vulnerability</h2> <p>A dangerous 7-Zip vulnerability (CVE-2025-11001) is under active exploitation, allowing attackers to achieve remote code execution using malicious symbolic links inside ZIP archives. Proof-of-concept exploits are public, and researchers warn threat actors are integrating it into phishing and malware campaigns. The flaw impacts all versions prior to 25.00, making patching urgent. Organizations should audit automated extraction workflows for compromise.</p> <p><a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/11/hackers-actively-exploiting-7-zip.html">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="12-cloudflare-outage-blamed-on-internal-error-not-attack">12. Cloudflare Outage Blamed on Internal Error, Not Attack</h2> <p>Cloudflare confirmed that a recent global outage was caused by an internal configuration error, not a cyberattack. The issue disrupted websites, APIs, and services dependent on Cloudflare’s global edge network. While no threat actor was involved, the incident highlights the systemic risk of third-party infrastructure failures. Organizations are being urged to assess their reliance on single-vendor cloud platforms and build redundancy into critical services.</p> <p><a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyber-risk/cloudflare-blames-outage-internal-error">Read more</a></p> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[2025-11-20]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2025-11-14</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews1114/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2025-11-14"/><published>2025-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews1114</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews1114/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-2025-11-14.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h1 id="cybersecurity-podcast-stories--november-14-2025">Cybersecurity Podcast Stories – November 14, 2025</h1> <h2 id="1-palo-alto-pan-os-vulnerability-puts-firewalls-at-risk">1. Palo Alto PAN-OS Vulnerability Puts Firewalls at Risk</h2> <p>A critical vulnerability in <strong>Palo Alto Networks PAN-OS</strong> has been identified, potentially allowing unauthenticated attackers to bypass security controls on devices with GlobalProtect enabled. This could result in remote code execution or full firewall compromise. The flaw affects specific versions of PAN-OS, and Palo Alto has released security patches with mitigation steps. Enterprises are urged to update immediately to protect perimeter defenses.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/palo-alto-pan-os-firewall-vulnerability/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="2-zero-day-exploits-hit-cisco-ise-and-citrix-in-coordinated-apt-campaign">2. Zero-Day Exploits Hit Cisco ISE and Citrix in Coordinated APT Campaign</h2> <p>Security researchers have uncovered a <strong>coordinated advanced persistent threat (APT) campaign</strong> exploiting zero-day vulnerabilities in <strong>Cisco Identity Services Engine (ISE)</strong> and <strong>Citrix NetScaler</strong> appliances. The attackers used these flaws to gain initial access, move laterally, and exfiltrate sensitive data. This campaign appears to be highly targeted, and both vendors have released advisories and patches. Organizations should monitor for unusual network activity and apply updates immediately.</p> <p><a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4089200/zero-day-exploits-hit-cisco-ise-and-citrix-systems-in-an-advanced-campaign.html">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="3-microsoft-defender-for-office-365-gets-screenshot-alert-feature">3. Microsoft Defender for Office 365 Gets Screenshot Alert Feature</h2> <p><strong>Microsoft Defender for Office 365</strong> now includes a feature that detects when users take <strong>screenshots of sensitive emails or content</strong>. This addition enhances insider threat detection and data loss prevention by monitoring behavior that might signal intentional or accidental data leakage. Admins can configure alerts tied to compliance policies. It’s another step in Microsoft’s effort to provide more granular visibility into risky end-user actions.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/microsoft-defendero365-new-feature/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="4-xworm-malware-hidden-in-png-files-via-steganography">4. XWorm Malware Hidden in PNG Files via Steganography</h2> <p>Security researchers have identified a new malware campaign using <strong>steganography</strong> to embed the <strong>XWorm remote access trojan</strong> in PNG images. The malware remains hidden within image metadata or pixels and is extracted via malicious scripts or droppers. This tactic allows attackers to bypass traditional antivirus tools and blend in with legitimate traffic. Users are advised to inspect suspicious image downloads and monitor for XWorm indicators of compromise.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/steganography-attacks-xworm-in-pngs/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="5-rce-flaw-in-imunifyav-threatens-millions-of-linux-hosted-websites">5. RCE Flaw in ImunifyAV Threatens Millions of Linux-Hosted Websites</h2> <p>A newly discovered <strong>remote code execution (RCE)</strong> flaw in <strong>ImunifyAV</strong>, a popular Linux antivirus for web hosts, could allow attackers to compromise entire servers. The vulnerability affects millions of websites hosted by providers using the software. A public proof-of-concept exploit is circulating, increasing the urgency for patching. Admins are urged to update immediately and monitor systems for unauthorized access.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/rce-flaw-in-imunifyav-puts-millions-of-linux-hosted-sites-at-risk/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="6-fbi-and-cisa-issue-joint-advisory-on-akira-ransomware">6. FBI and CISA Issue Joint Advisory on Akira Ransomware</h2> <p>The <strong>FBI and CISA</strong> have issued a joint alert about the rising threat of <strong>Akira ransomware</strong>, which has compromised over 100 organizations worldwide. Akira actors use double-extortion tactics—encrypting data and threatening public leaks. The ransomware targets a wide range of industries and includes both Windows and Linux variants. Agencies recommend strong MFA, regular patching, and segmentation to reduce risk.</p> <p><a href="https://cyberscoop.com/akira-ransomware-fbi-cisa-joint-advisory/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="7-akira-ransomware-linux-variant-targets-nutanix-environments">7. Akira Ransomware Linux Variant Targets Nutanix Environments</h2> <p>The Linux variant of <strong>Akira ransomware</strong> has evolved to specifically target <strong>Nutanix virtual machines</strong>, disrupting cloud and hybrid infrastructure. Attackers use SSH access to drop payloads and encrypt data in enterprise environments. CISA warns that Nutanix customers should review their exposure, secure credentials, and apply updated detection measures. This represents a notable shift in ransomware tactics toward virtualization platforms.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/cisa-warns-of-akira-ransomware-linux-encryptor-targeting-nutanix-vms/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="8-chinese-apt-campaign-targets-claude-ai-users-for-espionage">8. Chinese APT Campaign Targets Claude AI Users for Espionage</h2> <p>A suspected <strong>Chinese state-sponsored group</strong> is targeting users of <strong>Claude AI</strong>, a competitor to ChatGPT, in an espionage campaign. Attackers use phishing and malicious client applications to steal API tokens and session data. The goal appears to be gathering proprietary prompts, research, and corporate intelligence. Security teams are advised to validate AI platform access and monitor for API misuse.</p> <p><a href="https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/11/13/chinese_spies_claude_attacks/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="9-fortiweb-vulnerability-actively-exploited-to-create-admin-accounts">9. FortiWeb Vulnerability Actively Exploited to Create Admin Accounts</h2> <p>A critical flaw in <strong>Fortinet’s FortiWeb</strong> application firewall is being actively exploited to <strong>create rogue admin users</strong>. A public proof-of-concept exploit is available, and attackers are leveraging it to gain persistent access to web security appliances. Fortinet has released patches and mitigation guidance. Organizations should prioritize patching and restrict admin access interfaces.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/fortiweb-flaw-with-public-poc-actively-exploited-to-create-admin-users/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="10-checkoutcom-suffers-security-breach-merchant-api-keys-compromised">10. Checkout.com Suffers Security Breach, Merchant API Keys Compromised</h2> <p><strong>Checkout.com</strong>, a major payment gateway, confirmed a <strong>security breach</strong> that potentially exposed merchant API keys and sensitive integration data. While full payment details are not believed to be leaked, compromised API keys could allow fraudulent transaction attempts. Checkout.com is urging clients to rotate credentials and audit logs for anomalies. The company is working with forensic investigators to assess the breach scope.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/checkout-com-hacked/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="11-kraken-ransomware-benchmarks-devices-to-optimize-encryption">11. Kraken Ransomware Benchmarks Devices to Optimize Encryption</h2> <p><strong>Kraken ransomware</strong> has introduced a unique feature—<strong>system benchmarking</strong>—to choose the fastest encryption method for a victim’s hardware. Before encrypting data, the malware runs diagnostic routines to determine optimal performance settings, reducing execution time and evasion chances. This technique marks a new level of sophistication in ransomware tooling. Organizations should monitor for unusual benchmarking activity or processor-intensive processes on endpoints.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/kraken-ransomware-benchmarks-systems-for-optimal-encryption-choice/">Read more</a></p> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[2025-11-14]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2025-11-08</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews1108/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2025-11-08"/><published>2025-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews1108</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews1108/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-2025-11-08.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="1-texas-launches-cyber-command-and-cybersecurity-education-programs">1. Texas Launches Cyber Command and Cybersecurity Education Programs</h2> <p>Texas has launched a new <strong>Cyber Command</strong> and expanded cybersecurity education programs aimed at strengthening the state’s digital defenses. Governor Abbott emphasized the initiative as a response to rising cyber threats against critical infrastructure, schools, and local governments. The effort includes public-private partnerships and a focus on developing a skilled cybersecurity workforce. High school and college students will benefit from expanded training and certification opportunities.</p> <p><a href="https://spectrumlocalnews.com/tx/austin/news/2025/11/07/texas-cyber-command-and-education">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="2-ransomware-gangs-use-google-maps-suggest-an-edit-to-demand-ransom">2. Ransomware Gangs Use Google Maps “Suggest an Edit” to Demand Ransom</h2> <p>Ransomware groups are abusing the <strong>Google Maps “Suggest an Edit” feature</strong> to post ransom notes on victim company listings. Attackers modify business profiles with threatening messages demanding payment, leveraging the visibility of Google Maps to increase pressure on targeted organizations. This tactic allows criminals to bypass traditional communication methods and directly impact a victim’s public reputation. Google is investigating and working to prevent misuse of the platform.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/google-maps-feature-ransom-demands/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="3-chinese-buses-in-uk-equipped-with-remote-kill-switch">3. Chinese Buses in UK Equipped with Remote “Kill Switch”</h2> <p>UK authorities have raised concerns over <strong>Chinese-manufactured electric buses</strong> that include undocumented remote “kill switch” capabilities. Security officials warn that these features could be exploited to disrupt transportation services or conduct surveillance. The issue has sparked renewed debates over the national security implications of using foreign-made technology in critical infrastructure. Investigations are ongoing, and some MPs are calling for restrictions or removals.</p> <p><a href="https://www.thetimes.com/business-money/companies/article/chinese-buses-uk-kill-switch-00rhwlrsr">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="4-clickfix-attacks-now-use-weaponized-videos-to-bypass-defenses">4. ClickFix Attacks Now Use Weaponized Videos to Bypass Defenses</h2> <p>ClickFix attacks—previously known for abusing customer support workflows—have evolved to include <strong>weaponized video content</strong>. Threat actors are embedding malicious payloads within fake tech support video links, luring victims into clicking and unknowingly executing code. These attacks bypass email security filters and target corporate help desks and employees. Security teams are urged to update awareness training and block risky video content in workflows.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/clickfix-attacks-evolved-with-weaponized-videos/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="5-malicious-visual-studio-extensions-spreading-ransomvibing-malware">5. Malicious Visual Studio Extensions Spreading RansomVibing Malware</h2> <p>A new malware campaign dubbed <strong>RansomVibing</strong> is spreading through <strong>malicious Visual Studio extensions</strong> available in the official marketplace. Developers installing compromised extensions unknowingly enable ransomware execution, which encrypts files and displays intimidating audio-visual ransom messages. The campaign highlights the risk of supply chain attacks targeting development environments. Microsoft is actively removing malicious extensions and urging users to verify publisher authenticity.</p> <p><a href="https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/ransomvibing-infests-visual-studio-extension-market">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="6-landfall-spyware-exploits-samsung-zero-day-in-middle-east-espionage">6. Landfall Spyware Exploits Samsung Zero-Day in Middle East Espionage</h2> <p>Advanced spyware known as <strong>Landfall</strong> has exploited a previously unknown <strong>Samsung vulnerability (CVE-2025-21042)</strong> in targeted espionage campaigns across the Middle East. The zero-day allowed attackers to silently monitor communications and extract sensitive data from Samsung devices. Researchers attribute the campaign to a well-resourced nation-state threat actor. Samsung has since released a patch, and users are urged to update immediately.</p> <p><a href="https://securityaffairs.com/184331/security/landfall-spyware-exploited-samsung-zero-day-cve-2025-21042-in-middle-east-attacks.html">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="7-microsoft-uncovers-whisperleak-data-theft-operation">7. Microsoft Uncovers “WhisperLeak” Data Theft Operation</h2> <p>Microsoft has identified a new data theft campaign named <strong>WhisperLeak</strong>, targeting corporate environments to exfiltrate sensitive files and leak them online. The operation blends credential theft, lateral movement, and cloud misconfigurations to steal data across Microsoft 365 environments. Leaked data is used for extortion or reputational damage. Microsoft has released indicators of compromise and mitigation guidance for affected customers.</p> <p><a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/11/microsoft-uncovers-whisper-leak-attack.html">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="8-hackers-exploit-google-news-rss-feed-for-malicious-campaign">8. Hackers Exploit Google News RSS Feed for Malicious Campaign</h2> <p>Threat actors are exploiting <strong>Google News RSS feeds</strong> to inject malicious links into seemingly legitimate news stories. By abusing the news aggregation and syndication process, attackers redirect users to phishing or malware-laden pages while impersonating major media outlets. The campaign poses a risk to users who trust RSS-based summaries and clickthroughs. Security experts recommend verifying links and sources before engaging with embedded content.</p> <p><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAFBVV95cUxNQ0ZnRGp1c1I2YTF3WFVPZERlODFwZHZBM3pNcjA1LVU4UTd1S0h4Y1BUMFB0RnpmUFhQamJkOGZDa0JYSHdVQWUzcVlyREFsWjMxOXpmMkRBal9GQW9FVE9JOFM4cTZHY0tyYmViTmpqNUJwMXcwU1ByLUZQQzFDazNZV0JGRjlYUVFYT0ZqRXdRMzJmczZUV0s2c0VzMVh1YVI3Yw?oc=5">Read more</a></p> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[2025-11-08]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2025-07-11</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0711/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2025-07-11"/><published>2025-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0711</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0711/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-2025-07-11.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="1-russian-basketball-player-arrested-for-cybercrime">1. Russian Basketball Player Arrested for Cybercrime</h2> <p>A Russian professional basketball player has been arrested for involvement in cybercrime operations targeting US and European companies. Authorities allege that he participated in laundering funds stolen through phishing and business email compromise schemes. The arrest highlights the increasing crossover between cybercrime networks and unrelated public figures. Investigators are working to identify other associates involved in these schemes.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/russian-basketball-player-arrested/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="2-cisa-adds-citrixbleed-to-known-exploited-vulnerabilities-catalog">2. CISA Adds CitrixBleed to Known Exploited Vulnerabilities Catalog</h2> <p>The US Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) has added <strong>CitrixBleed</strong> vulnerabilities to its Known Exploited Vulnerabilities (KEV) catalog. The inclusion indicates active exploitation in the wild, requiring urgent patching by organizations. The flaws impact Citrix NetScaler ADC and Gateway products, potentially allowing unauthorized access. Federal agencies and critical infrastructure operators must patch by designated deadlines.</p> <p><a href="https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/07/10/cisa_citrixbleed_kev/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="3-uk-charges-four-in-scattered-spider-ransomware-case">3. UK Charges Four in Scattered Spider Ransomware Case</h2> <p>UK authorities have charged four individuals for their roles in the <strong>Scattered Spider</strong> ransomware group. The suspects allegedly conducted attacks against major corporations, stealing data and demanding multi-million dollar ransoms. This takedown follows a global effort to dismantle ransomware networks operating across borders. Prosecutors stated these arrests will disrupt operations and deter similar cybercriminal activities.</p> <p><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/uk-charges-four-in-scattered-spider-ransom-group/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="4-microsoft-exchange-online-service-outage-reported">4. Microsoft Exchange Online Service Outage Reported</h2> <p>Microsoft Exchange Online experienced a significant outage affecting email services for users worldwide. Customers reported delays in sending and receiving emails, alongside access issues through Outlook Web Access. Microsoft confirmed the incident was caused by infrastructure failures and is working on a resolution. Users are advised to monitor the Service Health Dashboard for recovery updates.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/microsoft-exchange-online-service-down/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="5-forrester-names-microsoft-leader-in-zero-trust-platforms-report">5. Forrester Names Microsoft Leader in Zero Trust Platforms Report</h2> <p>Forrester has named Microsoft a leader in its <strong>2025 Zero Trust Platforms Wave report</strong>, recognizing its comprehensive security solutions. The evaluation highlights Microsoft’s strengths in identity protection, endpoint security, and adaptive access controls. This recognition underscores Microsoft’s continued investments in zero trust frameworks to protect enterprise environments. The company pledged ongoing innovation in integrated security.</p> <p><a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/security/blog/2025/07/10/forrester-names-microsoft-a-leader-in-the-2025-zero-trust-platforms-wave-report/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="6-palo-alto-networks-globalprotect-vulnerability-discovered">6. Palo Alto Networks GlobalProtect Vulnerability Discovered</h2> <p>A critical vulnerability has been discovered in Palo Alto Networks’ GlobalProtect VPN, allowing potential privilege escalation or remote code execution. Researchers warn that exploitation could grant attackers unauthorized access to corporate networks. Palo Alto Networks has released patches addressing the issue and urges customers to update immediately. The flaw is tracked as high severity due to its potential impact on enterprise security.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/palo-alto-networks-globalprotect-vulnerability/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="7-russia-considers-legalizing-ethical-hacking">7. Russia Considers Legalizing Ethical Hacking</h2> <p>The Russian government is reviewing a bill that would legalize <strong>ethical hacking</strong> for certified professionals. The proposed law aims to formalize penetration testing and vulnerability research within Russia, preventing prosecution for authorized security assessments. Critics warn the bill could be misused to shield state-backed offensive cyber operations. Supporters argue it will boost cybersecurity expertise domestically.</p> <p><a href="https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/07/10/russia_ethical_hacking_bill/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="8-multiple-vulnerabilities-found-in-ruckus-wireless-products">8. Multiple Vulnerabilities Found in Ruckus Wireless Products</h2> <p>Researchers have disclosed multiple critical vulnerabilities in Ruckus Wireless products, including command injection and privilege escalation flaws. Attackers could exploit these to gain full administrative control over network devices. Ruckus has released security advisories, but some flaws remain unpatched as of the latest update. Organizations using affected products are urged to implement mitigations and restrict network exposure.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/ruckus-wireless-vulnerabilities/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="9-ransomware-operations-surge-following-qilin-takedown">9. Ransomware Operations Surge Following Qilin Takedown</h2> <p>Cybersecurity analysts report a surge in ransomware operations following the takedown of the <strong>Qilin</strong> ransomware group. Competing threat actors are moving to fill the void left by Qilin, increasing attacks against healthcare, manufacturing, and financial sectors. Experts warn organizations to remain vigilant amid evolving ransomware tactics and new affiliates joining the ecosystem. Enhanced detection and incident response capabilities are recommended.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/ransomware-operations-surge-following-qilin/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="10-gitphish-targets-developers-with-github-credential-theft">10. GitPhish Targets Developers with GitHub Credential Theft</h2> <p>A new phishing campaign called <strong>GitPhish</strong> is targeting software developers to steal GitHub credentials. Attackers send emails posing as GitHub security alerts, tricking recipients into entering login information on fake pages. Compromised accounts are then used to spread malware or tamper with code repositories. Developers are urged to enable multifactor authentication and verify security notification sources.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/gitphish/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="11-amd-discloses-new-cpu-flaws-allowing-data-leaks">11. AMD Discloses New CPU Flaws Allowing Data Leaks</h2> <p>AMD has disclosed new CPU vulnerabilities that could enable data leaks through timing attacks. The flaws impact multiple Ryzen and EPYC processors, potentially allowing attackers to infer sensitive data processed by the CPU. AMD is working on microcode updates to mitigate these risks. Users are advised to apply security updates when released to protect against exploitation.</p> <p><a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4020192/amd-discloses-new-cpu-flaws-that-can-enable-data-leaks-via-timing-attacks.html">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="12-critical-mcp-vulnerability-exposes-llm-clients-to-remote-attacks">12. Critical MCP Vulnerability Exposes LLM Clients to Remote Attacks</h2> <p>A critical remote code execution vulnerability has been found in MCP, exposing clients using large language models (LLMs) to remote attacks. Exploitation could allow attackers to execute arbitrary code or access sensitive data processed through LLM integrations. Researchers recommend immediate patching to secure environments deploying MCP in AI workflows. The vulnerability underscores emerging risks in AI application infrastructures.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/critical-mcp-remote-vulnerability-exposes-llm-clients/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="13-mcdonalds-ai-hiring-tool-leaked-job-seekers-data">13. McDonald’s AI Hiring Tool Leaked Job Seekers’ Data</h2> <p>McDonald’s AI-powered hiring tool <strong>McHire</strong> has reportedly leaked sensitive job seeker data due to a misconfigured database. Exposed information includes applicant names, contact details, and employment history. The company is investigating the breach and working to notify affected individuals. This incident highlights ongoing data privacy challenges with AI recruitment platforms.</p> <p><a href="https://hackread.com/mcdonalds-ai-hiring-tool-mchire-leaked-job-seekers-data/">Read more</a></p> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[2025-07-11]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2025-07-10</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0710/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2025-07-10"/><published>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0710</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0710/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-2025-07-10.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="1-windows-bitlocker-bypass-vulnerability-discovered">1. Windows BitLocker Bypass Vulnerability Discovered</h2> <p>A critical vulnerability has been discovered allowing attackers to bypass Windows BitLocker encryption protections. By exploiting this flaw, threat actors could gain unauthorized access to encrypted drives without needing recovery keys. Microsoft has released guidance and is expected to patch the issue soon. Users are urged to review physical security controls and implement additional drive protections.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/windows-bitlocker-bypass-vulnerability/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="2-ot-security-responsibility-elevating-to-executive-leadership">2. OT Security Responsibility Elevating to Executive Leadership</h2> <p>A new report shows that responsibility for operational technology (OT) security is increasingly shifting to executive leadership teams. As OT environments become more connected, cyber risks are now viewed as business risks requiring board-level oversight. Organizations are investing in governance frameworks to integrate OT security into corporate strategy. This trend is expected to drive greater resource allocation and cross-team collaboration.</p> <p><a href="https://www.securitymagazine.com/articles/101751-ot-security-responsibility-is-elevating-to-executive-leadership">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="3-attackers-exploit-weaknesses-in-multi-factor-authentication">3. Attackers Exploit Weaknesses in Multi-Factor Authentication</h2> <p>Researchers warn that attackers are exploiting weaknesses in multi-factor authentication (MFA) implementations, undermining user trust in these security controls. Techniques such as MFA fatigue attacks, token theft, and social engineering are increasingly successful. Experts stress the importance of phishing-resistant MFA solutions like hardware keys. Organizations should review MFA configurations and educate users on recognizing exploitation attempts.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/the-mfa-you-trust-is-lying-to-you-and-heres-how-attackers-exploit-it/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="4-ingram-micro-starts-restoring-systems-after-ransomware-attack">4. Ingram Micro Starts Restoring Systems After Ransomware Attack</h2> <p>Ingram Micro has begun restoring systems affected by the recent SafePay ransomware attack. The incident disrupted IT services globally, impacting ordering and supply chain operations for customers. The company is working with cybersecurity experts to strengthen defenses and prevent future breaches. Customers have been advised that some services may remain unavailable during the phased recovery.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/ingram-micro-starts-restoring-systems-after-ransomware-attack/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="5-ruckus-networks-leaves-severe-flaws-unpatched-in-management-devices">5. Ruckus Networks Leaves Severe Flaws Unpatched in Management Devices</h2> <p>Security researchers revealed that Ruckus Networks has left multiple severe vulnerabilities unpatched in its wireless management devices. These flaws could allow attackers to execute code remotely or gain administrative access to network environments. Despite public disclosure and exploit availability, no vendor patches have been released. Organizations using Ruckus devices are urged to implement mitigations or isolate vulnerable systems.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/ruckus-networks-leaves-severe-flaws-unpatched-in-management-devices/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="6-top-5-remote-access-and-rmm-tools-most-abused-by-threat-actors">6. Top 5 Remote Access and RMM Tools Most Abused by Threat Actors</h2> <p>Researchers have identified the top five remote access and RMM tools most abused by threat actors for persistence and lateral movement. Tools like AnyDesk, TeamViewer, and ConnectWise Control are commonly leveraged in attacks due to their legitimate use in IT environments. Security experts recommend monitoring for unauthorized installations and enforcing strict remote access policies. This helps reduce the risk of tool abuse during intrusions.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/top-5-remote-access-and-rmm-tools-most-abused-by-threat-actors/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="7-amd-tsa-side-channel-vulnerability-disclosed">7. AMD TSA Side-Channel Vulnerability Disclosed</h2> <p>A new side-channel vulnerability affecting AMD processors, dubbed <strong>TSA</strong>, has been disclosed by researchers. The flaw could allow attackers to leak sensitive data processed within CPU cores. AMD has acknowledged the issue and is working on microcode updates to mitigate the risk. Users are advised to stay up to date with firmware and OS security patches as they are released.</p> <p><a href="https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/07/09/amd_tsa_side_channel/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="8-us-sanctions-north-korean-it-workers-funding-missile-program">8. US Sanctions North Korean IT Workers Funding Missile Program</h2> <p>The US government has announced sanctions against North Korean IT workers accused of funding the country’s missile program through illicit cyber activities. These workers operate as freelance developers to infiltrate global companies and funnel earnings back to North Korea. The sanctions aim to disrupt these covert revenue streams and limit Pyongyang’s access to critical technologies. Businesses are advised to vet overseas contractors rigorously to avoid inadvertent compliance violations.</p> <p><a href="https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/07/09/us_sanctions_north_korean_it/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="9-ai-malware-proof-of-concept-evades-microsoft-defender">9. AI Malware Proof of Concept Evades Microsoft Defender</h2> <p>Researchers have developed a proof-of-concept AI-powered malware that successfully evades Microsoft Defender detections. The malware dynamically modifies its behavior and code signatures using AI to bypass security engines. Although not yet seen in the wild, experts warn that AI-enabled malware could soon become a significant threat. Organizations should prepare by enhancing behavioral detection and anomaly monitoring capabilities.</p> <p><a href="https://www.darkreading.com/endpoint-security/ai-malware-poc-evades-microsoft-defender">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="10-us-healthcare-cybersecurity-bill-advances-in-congress">10. US Healthcare Cybersecurity Bill Advances in Congress</h2> <p>A major cybersecurity bill aiming to strengthen healthcare sector protections has advanced in Congress. The legislation proposes funding for critical infrastructure upgrades, mandatory security frameworks, and improved incident reporting. Lawmakers highlight the growing threat of ransomware attacks against hospitals and patient data systems. If passed, the bill could reshape cybersecurity standards across the US healthcare industry.</p> <p><a href="https://cyberscoop.com/health-care-cybersecurity-big-beautiful-bill-cuts-congress/">Read more</a></p> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[2025-07-10]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2025-07-09</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0709/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2025-07-09"/><published>2025-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0709</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0709/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-2025-07-09.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="1-fortios-buffer-overflow-vulnerability-discovered">1. FortiOS Buffer Overflow Vulnerability Discovered</h2> <p>A critical buffer overflow vulnerability has been discovered in Fortinet’s FortiOS operating system. This flaw could allow attackers to execute arbitrary code or trigger a denial of service on affected devices. Fortinet has released patches to address the vulnerability and urges all customers to update immediately. Exploitation risks are high due to the widespread use of FortiOS in enterprise networks.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/fortios-buffer-overflow-vulnerability/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="2-phishing-scams-can-deceive-large-language-models">2. Phishing Scams Can Deceive Large Language Models</h2> <p>New research shows that phishing scams can successfully deceive large language models used in cybersecurity detection. Attackers craft messages with linguistic tricks and context manipulation to bypass AI-driven filters. This raises concerns over overreliance on AI for email security without human verification. Experts recommend combining AI with traditional rule-based detection and user training to reduce risks.</p> <p><a href="https://www.securitymagazine.com/articles/101738-phishing-scams-can-deceive-large-language-models">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="3-anatsa-android-banking-malware-returns-via-google-play">3. Anatsa Android Banking Malware Returns via Google Play</h2> <p>The Anatsa banking trojan has resurfaced on Google Play, targeting Android users across Europe. Disguised as legitimate apps, the malware steals banking credentials and initiates fraudulent transactions directly from infected devices. Researchers warn that Anatsa uses sophisticated techniques to bypass Google Play’s security checks. Users are urged to verify app publishers and permissions before installation.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/anatsa-android-banking-malware-from-google-play/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="4-anatsa-android-banking-trojan-hits-over-100000-devices">4. Anatsa Android Banking Trojan Hits Over 100,000 Devices</h2> <p>Further reports confirm that the Anatsa banking trojan has infected over <strong>100,000 Android devices</strong> through malicious apps on Google Play. The malware utilizes advanced overlay attacks to capture user credentials from banking apps. Its operators primarily target financial institutions in Europe to perform large-scale theft. Google has removed the apps, but users already infected remain at risk.</p> <p><a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/07/anatsa-android-banking-trojan-hits.html">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="5-defending-against-phishing-kit-attacks">5. Defending Against Phishing Kit Attacks</h2> <p>Researchers have highlighted the growing threat of phishing kits, which enable cybercriminals to launch sophisticated phishing attacks with minimal effort. These kits include pre-built templates and evasion techniques to bypass security filters. Organizations are advised to deploy advanced email security solutions and conduct regular employee training. Phishing kits continue to fuel credential theft and business email compromise campaigns.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/defend-against-phishing-kit-attacks/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="6-zoom-clients-for-windows-vulnerability-discovered">6. Zoom Clients for Windows Vulnerability Discovered</h2> <p>A newly discovered vulnerability in Zoom clients for Windows could allow attackers to escalate privileges on affected systems. The flaw impacts both desktop and VDI installations, potentially giving attackers administrative access. Zoom has released an update addressing the issue, and users are urged to update immediately. This vulnerability underscores the importance of keeping collaboration tools patched.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/zoom-clients-for-windows-vulnerability/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="7-large-scale-browser-hijacking-campaign-exposed">7. Large-Scale Browser Hijacking Campaign Exposed</h2> <p>Researchers have uncovered a large-scale browser hijacking campaign targeting Chrome and Edge users. Attackers use malicious extensions to redirect users to unwanted ads and phishing sites, generating illicit revenue. The extensions often masquerade as productivity tools to gain user trust. Users should review installed extensions and remove any unrecognized or suspicious add-ons.</p> <p><a href="https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/07/08/browser_hijacking_campaign/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="8-ms-confirms-social-engineering-led-to-ransomware-attack">8. M&amp;S Confirms Social Engineering Led to Ransomware Attack</h2> <p>UK retailer Marks &amp; Spencer has confirmed that a recent massive ransomware attack resulted from a social engineering incident. Attackers tricked an employee into providing access credentials, which were then used to infiltrate corporate networks. The ransomware deployment caused operational disruptions and data encryption. The company is working with cybersecurity experts to recover and strengthen its defenses.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/mands-confirms-social-engineering-led-to-massive-ransomware-attack/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="9-malicious-open-source-packages-spike-in-repositories">9. Malicious Open-Source Packages Spike in Repositories</h2> <p>Security researchers report a spike in malicious open-source packages uploaded to popular repositories like npm and PyPI. Attackers embed malware or credential stealers within seemingly useful packages to target developers. Organizations are urged to implement supply chain security checks and review dependencies before integration. The trend highlights ongoing threats to software supply chain integrity.</p> <p><a href="https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/malicious-open-source-packages-spike">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="10-microsoft-patches-137-cves-in-latest-update">10. Microsoft Patches 137 CVEs in Latest Update</h2> <p>Microsoft’s latest Patch Tuesday addressed <strong>137 CVEs</strong>, including critical vulnerabilities in Windows, Office, and Azure. Notably, no zero-day exploits were disclosed this cycle, but several critical flaws could enable remote code execution. Security experts recommend prioritizing updates for Windows Kernel and Microsoft Exchange vulnerabilities. Organizations should deploy patches promptly to reduce exploitation risks.</p> <p><a href="https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/microsoft-patches-137-cves-no-zero-days">Read more</a></p> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[2025-07-09]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2025-07-08</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0708/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2025-07-08"/><published>2025-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0708</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0708/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-2025-07-08.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="1-trojan-versions-of-putty-and-winscp-spread-malware">1. Trojan Versions of PuTTY and WinSCP Spread Malware</h2> <p>Researchers have discovered trojanized versions of PuTTY and WinSCP being distributed to deliver malware. These fake installers appear legitimate but install backdoors that allow attackers to steal credentials and gain remote access. The malicious software is being shared on phishing sites and compromised forums targeting IT professionals. Users are urged to download such tools only from official vendor websites to avoid infection.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/trojan-versions-of-putty-and-winscp/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="2-alleged-chinese-hacker-tied-to-silk-typhoon-arrested">2. Alleged Chinese Hacker Tied to Silk Typhoon Arrested</h2> <p>An alleged Chinese hacker linked to the <strong>Silk Typhoon</strong> cyberespionage group has been arrested for targeting US and global networks. The individual is accused of conducting operations to steal intellectual property and sensitive government data. Authorities say the arrest is a significant win against Chinese state-sponsored cyber activities. This comes amid growing efforts to curb nation-state cyber threats worldwide.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/alleged-chinese-hacker-tied-to-silk-typhoon-arrested-for-cyberespionage/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="3-microsoft-testing-windows-update-notifications-for-vulnerabilities">3. Microsoft Testing Windows Update Notifications for Vulnerabilities</h2> <p>Microsoft is testing a new feature in Windows Update that will notify users about critical security vulnerabilities affecting their systems. The notifications will appear in the Windows Update interface and prompt users to install necessary patches immediately. This aims to improve patch adoption rates and reduce exposure to known exploits. The feature is currently in preview for Windows Insider builds.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/windows-update-notifications/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="4-phishing-platforms-and-infostealers-drive-credential-theft-surge">4. Phishing Platforms and Infostealers Drive Credential Theft Surge</h2> <p>Security experts report that phishing-as-a-service platforms and infostealer malware are driving a surge in stolen credentials being sold online. These tools make it easier for low-skilled attackers to launch campaigns and harvest user data at scale. Infostealers such as RedLine and Raccoon remain popular for extracting browser and application credentials. Organizations are urged to deploy multifactor authentication to reduce the impact of compromised credentials.</p> <p><a href="https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/07/07/phishing_platforms_infostealers_blamed_for/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="5-manufacturing-security-at-risk-due-to-default-configurations">5. Manufacturing Security at Risk Due to Default Configurations</h2> <p>A new report highlights that manufacturing companies remain vulnerable to cyberattacks due to reliance on default configurations. Many operational technology systems are deployed without changing default passwords or disabling unnecessary services. Attackers exploit these weaknesses to infiltrate industrial networks and disrupt production. Experts advise manufacturers to enforce security hardening practices to mitigate these risks.</p> <p><a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/07/manufacturing-security-why-default.html">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="6-fake-domains-target-amazon-prime-day-shoppers">6. Fake Domains Target Amazon Prime Day Shoppers</h2> <p>Cybercriminals have registered numerous fake domains to exploit Amazon Prime Day shoppers with phishing scams. These websites mimic Amazon’s branding to steal login credentials and payment information. Researchers warn that such campaigns spike around major online shopping events. Users are urged to navigate directly to official Amazon URLs and avoid clicking links from promotional emails.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/fake-domains-amazon-prime-day/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="7-powershell-20-officially-deprecated-by-microsoft">7. PowerShell 2.0 Officially Deprecated by Microsoft</h2> <p>Microsoft has officially deprecated PowerShell 2.0, citing security risks and lack of modern features. The deprecated version is no longer supported, and users are urged to upgrade to PowerShell 5.1 or PowerShell 7 for improved security and functionality. Many malware strains historically exploited PowerShell 2.0’s lack of security controls. Organizations should ensure legacy scripts are updated to remain compatible with newer versions.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/powershell-2-0-deprecation/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="8-hackers-abuse-leaked-shellter-red-team-tool-for-malware-deployment">8. Hackers Abuse Leaked Shellter Red Team Tool for Malware Deployment</h2> <p>Threat actors are abusing a leaked version of Shellter, a popular red team tool, to deploy infostealer malware. Originally designed for penetration testing, Shellter enables attackers to inject malicious payloads into legitimate processes, bypassing antivirus detection. Researchers warn that the tool’s public availability increases its misuse by cybercriminals. Organizations are urged to monitor for Shellter indicators of compromise in their environments.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/hackers-abuse-leaked-shellter-red-team-tool-to-deploy-infostealers/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="9-employee-paid-920-for-credentials-used-in-140-million-bank-heist">9. Employee Paid $920 for Credentials Used in $140 Million Bank Heist</h2> <p>An employee received just <strong>$920</strong> for selling their corporate credentials, which were later used in a $140 million bank heist. Cybercriminals leveraged the access to transfer funds and launder the money through cryptocurrency exchanges. This incident highlights the severe consequences of insider threats and credential compromise. Organizations are reminded to implement strict access controls and monitor for suspicious user behavior.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/employee-gets-920-for-credentials-used-in-140-million-bank-heist/">Read more</a></p> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[2025-07-08]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2025-07-07</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0707/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2025-07-07"/><published>2025-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0707</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0707/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-2025-07-07.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="1-scattered-spider-upgrades-tactics-to-abuse-legitimate-tools">1. Scattered Spider Upgrades Tactics to Abuse Legitimate Tools</h2> <p>The Scattered Spider hacking group has upgraded its tactics by increasingly abusing legitimate IT management tools in its attacks. Researchers report they are using tools like remote management software to maintain persistence and avoid detection by security products. This approach makes their malicious activities blend in with normal administrative operations. Organizations are urged to monitor legitimate tool usage closely for signs of misuse.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/scattered-spider-upgraded-their-tactics-to-abuse-legitimate-tools/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="2-ingram-micro-outage-caused-by-safepay-ransomware-attack">2. Ingram Micro Outage Caused by SafePay Ransomware Attack</h2> <p>IT distribution giant Ingram Micro has confirmed that a recent outage was caused by a ransomware attack from the SafePay group. The attack disrupted operations, preventing customers from accessing systems and placing orders. Ingram Micro is working with cybersecurity experts to restore services and investigate the extent of the breach. This incident highlights the growing trend of ransomware attacks on supply chain companies.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/ingram-micro-outage-caused-by-safepay-ransomware-attack/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="3-citrixbleed-2-proof-of-concept-released">3. CitrixBleed 2 Proof-of-Concept Released</h2> <p>Researchers have released a proof-of-concept (PoC) exploit for <strong>CitrixBleed 2</strong>, a newly discovered vulnerability affecting Citrix appliances. The flaw could allow attackers to bypass authentication or gain elevated privileges if exploited. Security experts warn that public release of the PoC increases the likelihood of widespread attacks. Organizations using Citrix products are urged to apply patches immediately to mitigate this critical risk.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/citrixbleed-2-poc-released/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="4-instagram-starts-using-1-week-validity-tls-certificates">4. Instagram Starts Using 1-Week Validity TLS Certificates</h2> <p>Instagram has begun deploying TLS certificates with only <strong>one-week validity</strong> to enhance security and reduce risks from compromised certificates. Short-lived certificates minimize the impact of private key leaks and align with modern security best practices. However, this approach requires robust automated certificate renewal processes to avoid service disruptions. Other major platforms may adopt similar strategies in the future.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/instagram-started-using-1-week-validity-tls-certificates/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="5-surge-in-phishing-attacks-using-es-spanish-domains">5. Surge in Phishing Attacks Using .es Spanish Domains</h2> <p>Security researchers report a surge in phishing attacks using Spanish (.es) domains to target European users. The campaigns often impersonate banks and government services to steal credentials and financial information. Attackers register legitimate-looking .es domains to evade detection and build user trust. Users are urged to verify domain authenticity before entering sensitive information.</p> <p><a href="https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/07/05/spain_domains_phishing/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="6-writable-file-found-in-lenovos-windows-directory">6. Writable File Found in Lenovo’s Windows Directory</h2> <p>A security researcher has discovered a writable file in Lenovo’s Windows directory that could allow privilege escalation. Malicious actors could replace the file with a trojanized version to execute code with higher privileges. Lenovo has been notified and is working on a fix to address this vulnerability. Users are advised to monitor for security updates to protect their systems.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/writable-file-in-lenovos-windows-directory/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="7-xworm-becomes-most-active-rat-with-new-stagers">7. XWorm Becomes Most Active RAT with New Stagers</h2> <p>XWorm has become the most active remote access trojan (RAT) in recent campaigns, leveraging new stager payloads for stealthy deployment. The malware is being used to steal credentials, monitor user activity, and deploy additional tools in compromised environments. Its modular design allows threat actors to adapt tactics based on victim environments. Security experts recommend monitoring for XWorm indicators of compromise in enterprise networks.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/xworm-the-most-active-rat-uses-new-stagers/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="8-threat-actors-abusing-av-and-edr-evasion-frameworks">8. Threat Actors Abusing AV and EDR Evasion Frameworks</h2> <p>Researchers have observed threat actors widely abusing security evasion frameworks designed to bypass antivirus (AV) and endpoint detection and response (EDR) solutions. These frameworks allow attackers to package and deliver malware without triggering security alerts. The increasing use of such tools lowers the barrier for less sophisticated attackers to conduct successful intrusions. Organizations are urged to implement behavioral detection techniques to counter these threats.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/threat-actors-abused-av-edr-evasion-framework/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="9-hackers-exploit-legitimate-inno-setup-installer-for-malware-delivery">9. Hackers Exploit Legitimate Inno Setup Installer for Malware Delivery</h2> <p>Cybercriminals are exploiting the <strong>Inno Setup installer</strong>, a legitimate software packaging tool, to deliver malware. By embedding malicious payloads within seemingly legitimate installers, attackers evade detection and gain initial access to victim systems. Security experts warn that such attacks often bypass antivirus scans due to the trust placed in known installer frameworks. Users should verify software sources before installation to mitigate these risks.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/hackers-exploit-legitimate-inno-setup-installer/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="10-taiwan-nsb-alerts-public-on-data-risks-from-chinese-apps">10. Taiwan NSB Alerts Public on Data Risks from Chinese Apps</h2> <p>Taiwan’s National Security Bureau (NSB) has issued a public alert warning about data security risks posed by Chinese-developed applications. Officials highlight that apps developed in China may collect sensitive personal data accessible by Chinese authorities under national security laws. The NSB urges citizens to avoid installing such apps to protect personal and national security. This warning comes amid rising geopolitical tensions in the region.</p> <p><a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/07/taiwan-nsb-alerts-public-on-data-risks.html">Read more</a></p> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[2025-07-07]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2025-07-04</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0704/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2025-07-04"/><published>2025-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0704</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0704/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-2025-07-04.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h1 id="cybersecurity-podcast-stories--july-4-2025">Cybersecurity Podcast Stories – July 4, 2025</h1> <h2 id="1-hackers-use-fake-cloudflare-verification-screens-for-phishing">1. Hackers Use Fake Cloudflare Verification Screens for Phishing</h2> <p>Hackers are deploying phishing attacks that use fake Cloudflare verification screens to trick users into entering their credentials. These deceptive pages mimic the Cloudflare browser check interface but secretly harvest login information. Security researchers warn that the tactic is effective because users often trust Cloudflare branding. Organizations are urged to educate employees to verify URLs carefully before entering credentials.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/hackers-use-fake-cloudflare-verification-screen/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="2-google-ordered-to-pay-314m-for-misusing-android-data">2. Google Ordered to Pay $314M for Misusing Android Data</h2> <p>Google has been ordered to pay <strong>$314 million</strong> after being found guilty of misusing Android user data for targeted advertising. The ruling stated that Google failed to obtain proper user consent for collecting and processing personal data. This case highlights ongoing global scrutiny over big tech’s privacy practices. Google has not yet commented on whether it plans to appeal the decision.</p> <p><a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/07/google-ordered-to-pay-314m-for-misusing.html">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="3-123-stealer-malware-advertised-on-underground-hacking-forums">3. 123 Stealer Malware Advertised on Underground Hacking Forums</h2> <p>A new infostealer malware named <strong>123 Stealer</strong> is being actively advertised on underground hacking forums. This malware is designed to steal browser passwords, cookies, cryptocurrency wallet data, and credentials from FTP clients. Its low cost and ease of deployment make it attractive to cybercriminals targeting individuals and small businesses. Security experts recommend endpoint protection and user awareness to mitigate risks.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/123-stealer-on-underground-hacking-forums/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="4-content-security-policy-bypass-vulnerability-discovered">4. Content Security Policy Bypass Vulnerability Discovered</h2> <p>Researchers have discovered a method to bypass Content Security Policy (CSP) protections implemented by websites. CSP is used to prevent cross-site scripting attacks by restricting resource loading, but this bypass could allow attackers to inject malicious scripts. Websites relying solely on CSP may be vulnerable until patches or alternative mitigations are applied. Organizations are advised to review their CSP configurations urgently.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/content-security-policy-bypass/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="5-multiple-vulnerabilities-found-in-php">5. Multiple Vulnerabilities Found in PHP</h2> <p>Several vulnerabilities have been discovered in PHP, including flaws that could lead to denial of service or remote code execution. These issues affect multiple PHP versions used widely in web development environments. Security experts urge administrators to update PHP installations immediately to mitigate exploitation risks. The vulnerabilities were disclosed as part of routine security audits.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/multiple-php-vulnerabilities/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="6-malicious-extensions-exploit-ide-trust-badges">6. Malicious Extensions Exploit IDE Trust Badges</h2> <p>New research shows attackers are publishing malicious extensions that exploit integrated development environment (IDE) trust badges to gain developer confidence. These verified-looking extensions contain hidden malware capable of stealing credentials and injecting malicious code into projects. Security experts warn that developers often install extensions based on trust badges without deeper inspection. Organizations are urged to audit installed extensions and enforce strict approval processes.</p> <p><a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4017474/verified-but-vulnerable-malicious-extensions-exploit-ide-trust-badges.html">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="7-nighteagle-apt-exploits-microsoft-exchange-vulnerabilities">7. Nighteagle APT Exploits Microsoft Exchange Vulnerabilities</h2> <p>The Nighteagle advanced persistent threat (APT) group is exploiting Microsoft Exchange vulnerabilities to gain footholds in targeted networks. These attacks focus on stealing sensitive data and maintaining long-term persistence for espionage operations. Researchers warn that Nighteagle uses sophisticated evasion techniques to avoid detection. Organizations are urged to apply Microsoft’s security patches immediately to block these intrusion attempts.</p> <p><a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/07/nighteagle-apt-exploits-microsoft.html">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="8-hacker-leaks-telefónica-data-after-alleged-new-breach">8. Hacker Leaks Telefónica Data After Alleged New Breach</h2> <p>A hacker has leaked sensitive data allegedly stolen from Spanish telecom giant Telefónica in a new breach. The leaked information includes customer data and internal documents, raising concerns about potential identity theft and corporate espionage. Telefónica is investigating the claims to confirm the extent of the breach. Customers are advised to monitor their accounts for suspicious activity.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/hacker-leaks-telef-nica-data-allegedly-stolen-in-a-new-breach/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="9-chatgpt-deep-research-tests-new-connectors-for-more-context">9. ChatGPT Deep Research Tests New Connectors for More Context</h2> <p>OpenAI is testing new connectors for ChatGPT under its Deep Research program to improve contextual understanding across data sources. The feature aims to integrate information from different platforms seamlessly, enhancing ChatGPT’s utility for research and professional workflows. Early testers report improved relevance and accuracy in outputs using these connectors. OpenAI plans broader rollout after completing performance and security reviews.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/artificial-intelligence/chatgpt-deep-research-tests-new-connectors-for-more-context/">Read more</a></p> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[2025-07-04]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2025-07-03</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0703/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2025-07-03"/><published>2025-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0703</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0703/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-2025-07-03.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <p>Story 1. Microsoft Asks Users to Ignore Windows Firewall Config Errors</p> <p>Microsoft has asked users to ignore Windows Firewall configuration errors that appeared after the recent security updates. The company confirmed these errors are due to a bug in the update process and do not impact actual firewall functionality. A fix is being developed and will be rolled out in upcoming patches. Users are advised not to make manual changes as these warnings are cosmetic.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/microsoft/microsoft-asks-users-to-ignore-windows-firewall-config-errors/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 2. Let’s Encrypt Rolls Out Free ECDSA Certificates</p> <p>Let’s Encrypt has started issuing free ECDSA certificates to improve website performance and security. These certificates use elliptic curve cryptography, offering better efficiency and stronger security compared to traditional RSA certificates. Website owners can now choose ECDSA certificates when generating new SSL certificates through Let’s Encrypt. This move aims to enhance encryption standards across the internet at no additional cost.</p> <p><a href="https://www.theregister.com/2025/07/03/lets_encrypt_rolls_out_free/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 3. Threat Actors Weaponize PDFs to Impersonate Microsoft, DocuSign, Dropbox</p> <p>Cybercriminals are increasingly using weaponized PDF files to impersonate brands like Microsoft, DocuSign, and Dropbox. These PDFs contain phishing links or malware designed to steal user credentials or install malicious payloads. Security researchers warn that these documents often bypass email security filters due to their legitimate appearance. Users are urged to verify PDF senders and avoid opening unexpected attachments.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/threat-actors-weaponize-pdfs-to-impersonate-microsoft-docusign-dropbox/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 4. AI-Generated Phishing Websites Becoming More Sophisticated</p> <p>New research reveals cybercriminals are using AI to generate highly convincing phishing websites. These sites mimic legitimate brands with improved design, language accuracy, and realistic layouts, making them harder to detect. Security experts warn that AI lowers the barrier for attackers to create targeted phishing campaigns at scale. Organizations are advised to enhance user awareness training and detection capabilities against this evolving threat.</p> <p><a href="https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/07/03/ai_phishing_websites/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 5. Hackers Actively Attacking Linux SSH Servers</p> <p>Security researchers report that hackers are actively targeting Linux SSH servers using brute force and credential stuffing attacks. Once inside, attackers deploy malware to maintain persistence and pivot within networks. The attacks primarily target exposed servers with weak credentials or default configurations. System administrators are urged to enforce strong passwords, disable root login over SSH, and implement multi-factor authentication.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/hackers-actively-attacking-linux-ssh-servers/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 6. FBI: Salt Typhoon Campaign Largely Contained in Telecom Networks</p> <p>A top FBI cyber official stated that the Salt Typhoon hacking campaign targeting US telecom networks has been largely contained. The Chinese state-backed group was attempting to exploit vulnerabilities in network infrastructure to conduct espionage activities. Collaborative efforts between telecom companies and government agencies led to detection and mitigation. However, officials warn that vigilance remains critical against similar nation-state threats.</p> <p><a href="https://cyberscoop.com/top-fbi-cyber-official-salt-typhoon-largely-contained-in-telecom-networks/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 7. Cisco Removes Unified CM CallManager Backdoor Root Account</p> <p>Cisco has released an update removing a backdoor root account in its Unified Communications Manager (CallManager) software. The hardcoded credentials could allow attackers to gain root access to the system if exploited. Cisco advises all customers to apply the security update immediately to mitigate potential threats. This discovery highlights the risks of embedded default accounts in enterprise systems.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/cisco-removes-unified-cm-callManager-backdoor-root-account/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 8. Surge of ClickFix Attacks Threatens Corporate Defenses</p> <p>Researchers have observed a sixfold increase in ClickFix attacks, where threat actors exploit web-based support tools to gain unauthorized access. These attacks target organizations’ customer service portals and exploit automated workflows to deploy malicious payloads. Security experts warn that these methods bypass traditional email security defenses. Companies are urged to review web support tool configurations and implement stricter security controls.</p> <p><a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4016208/sixfold-surge-of-clickfix-attacks-threatens-corporate-defenses.html">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 9. DCrat Malware Attacks Windows for Keylogging and Remote Control</p> <p>A new campaign deploying DCrat malware is targeting Windows systems to enable keylogging and full remote control capabilities. Attackers deliver the malware through phishing emails containing malicious attachments or links. Once installed, DCrat allows threat actors to monitor user activity, steal credentials, and execute further commands. Users are advised to remain vigilant against suspicious emails and keep endpoint protection updated.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/dcrat-attack-windows-to-remotely-control-keylogging/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 10. Microsoft Links DNS Issue to Exchange Online OTP Delivery Failures</p> <p>Microsoft has linked recent OTP delivery failures in Exchange Online to an internal DNS issue. The problem caused delays or failures in sending one-time passcodes used for user authentication. Microsoft has implemented a fix and confirmed that the service is now operating normally. Users experiencing lingering issues are advised to retry their operations.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/microsoft/microsoft-links-dns-issue-to-exchange-online-otp-delivery-failures/">Read more</a></p> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[2025-07-03]]></summary></entry></feed>