<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-06-13T23:10:11+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DJBSec, CISSP</title><subtitle>DJBSec is an IT veteran with over 25 years of experience in IT and Cyber Security </subtitle><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-25-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0325/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-25-25"/><published>2025-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0325</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0325/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-03-25-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="story-1-11-ways-cybercriminals-are-making-phishing-more-potent-than-ever">Story 1. 11 Ways Cybercriminals Are Making Phishing More Potent Than Ever</h2> <p>Cybercriminals are evolving their phishing techniques by using AI-generated messages, deepfakes, and adaptive lures tailored to specific targets. They’re also exploiting trusted platforms, like LinkedIn and Microsoft Teams, to appear legitimate while deploying malware or stealing credentials. Advanced spoofing methods and real-time phishing kits make these scams harder to detect. Security professionals urge organizations to train employees continuously and use layered email security tools.<br/> <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3850783/11-ways-cybercriminals-are-making-phishing-more-potent-than-ever.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-2-chinese-espionage-hacker-group-isoon-apt-operation-exposed">Story 2. Chinese Espionage Hacker Group “iSoon” APT Operation Exposed</h2> <p>A leak has revealed extensive details about a Chinese state-sponsored hacker group known as iSoon (APT), involved in espionage and cyber intrusions across Asia, Africa, and the Middle East. The group has targeted foreign governments, telecoms, and key infrastructure using custom malware and persistent backdoors. The leak includes internal documents and chat logs, offering rare insight into how state-backed APTs operate. Security analysts are calling this one of the most significant exposures of China’s cyber activities.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyberattacks-data-breaches/chinese-espionage-hacker-group-isoon-apt-operation">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-3-new-vanhelsing-ransomware-targets-windows-arm-and-esxi-systems">Story 3. New VanHelsing Ransomware Targets Windows, ARM, and ESXi Systems</h2> <p>A new ransomware strain named VanHelsing is making headlines for its ability to infect Windows, ARM-based devices, and VMware ESXi servers. This cross-platform malware uses PowerShell scripts and exploits known vulnerabilities to spread rapidly within networks. Security researchers warn that its versatility makes it a growing threat in mixed enterprise environments. Businesses are urged to patch systems, secure hypervisors, and isolate backup infrastructure.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/new-vanhelsing-ransomware-targets-windows-arm-esxi-systems/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-4-critical-ingress-nginx-controller-flaw-could-lead-to-cluster-takeover">Story 4. Critical Ingress NGINX Controller Flaw Could Lead to Cluster Takeover</h2> <p>A critical vulnerability has been discovered in the Ingress NGINX controller for Kubernetes, allowing attackers to potentially gain full control over entire Kubernetes clusters. The flaw enables privilege escalation and unauthorized access through misconfigured annotations. If exploited, it could result in data breaches or total infrastructure compromise. Patches have been released, and organizations are urged to update immediately.<br/> <a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/03/critical-ingress-nginx-controller.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-5-cyberattack-disrupts-ukrainian-state-railways-online-services">Story 5. Cyberattack Disrupts Ukrainian State Railways’ Online Services</h2> <p>Ukraine’s state railway service fell victim to a cyberattack that took down its online ticketing and customer service systems. The incident disrupted public transportation services and delayed digital operations, although physical train services remained operational. Authorities are investigating the origin of the attack, suspected to be politically motivated. This attack highlights the ongoing targeting of Ukraine’s infrastructure amid geopolitical tensions.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/cyberattack-takes-down-ukrainian-state-railways-online-services/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-6-police-arrest-300-suspects-linked-to-african-cybercrime-rings">Story 6. Police Arrest 300 Suspects Linked to African Cybercrime Rings</h2> <p>International law enforcement agencies have arrested over 300 individuals tied to African-based cybercrime groups involved in business email compromise (BEC) and romance scams. The operation, coordinated by Interpol, also led to the seizure of millions in assets and digital evidence. These cybercrime rings have defrauded victims globally by posing as businesses or romantic partners to steal funds. Authorities emphasize the growing global reach of financially motivated threat actors.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/police-arrests-300-suspects-linked-to-african-cybercrime-rings/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-7-microsoft-unveils-ai-powered-security-copilot-agents-and-new-protections">Story 7. Microsoft Unveils AI-Powered Security Copilot Agents and New Protections</h2> <p>Microsoft has introduced Security Copilot Agents—AI-powered assistants designed to automate threat detection, response, and investigation tasks. These agents integrate with Microsoft 365 Defender and Sentinel to provide real-time security insights and recommendations. The update includes advanced AI protections to defend against prompt injection, data leakage, and manipulation in AI-based systems. It reflects Microsoft’s growing focus on securing both traditional IT and AI-driven environments.<br/> <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/security/blog/2025/03/24/microsoft-unveils-microsoft-security-copilot-agents-and-new-protections-for-ai/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-8-microsoft-adds-inline-data-protection-for-copilot-and-ai-features">Story 8. Microsoft Adds Inline Data Protection for Copilot and AI Features</h2> <p>Microsoft is enhancing its Copilot AI platform with new inline data protection tools to help prevent sensitive information leakage. These features offer real-time alerts and restrictions when users attempt to share confidential data via AI-driven workflows. The update also enables security teams to create customized policies for AI data usage. It’s part of a broader push to balance AI innovation with enterprise-grade data governance.<br/> <a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/03/microsoft-adds-inline-data-protection.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-9-chinese-weaver-ant-hackers-spied-on-telecom-networks-for-four-years">Story 9. Chinese “Weaver Ant” Hackers Spied on Telecom Networks for Four Years</h2> <p>A Chinese APT group dubbed “Weaver Ant” has been quietly infiltrating telecom networks across Southeast Asia for the past four years. The attackers used custom malware and compromised routers to intercept communications and extract intelligence. The campaign remained undetected due to the group’s stealthy techniques and use of legitimate credentials. Security researchers call this a textbook example of long-term cyber-espionage targeting critical infrastructure.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/chinese-weaver-ant-hackers-spied-on-telco-network-for-4-years/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-10-draytek-routers-worldwide-affected-by-mysterious-reboot-loop-bug">Story 10. DrayTek Routers Worldwide Affected by Mysterious Reboot Loop Bug</h2> <p>DrayTek routers globally experienced mass reboot loops over the weekend, causing widespread internet disruptions for businesses and individuals. The issue appears to be linked to a firmware bug or a time-based system error, though no official cause has been confirmed yet. DrayTek has released a temporary workaround and is working on a permanent fix. Users are advised to monitor device updates and apply firmware patches as soon as they’re released.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/draytek-routers-worldwide-go-into-reboot-loops-over-weekend/">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[3-25-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-24-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0324/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-24-25"/><published>2025-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0324</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0324/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-03-24-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h1 id="cybersecurity-stories-summary">Cybersecurity Stories Summary</h1> <h2 id="story-1-cloudflare-now-blocks-all-unencrypted-traffic-to-its-api-endpoints">Story 1. Cloudflare Now Blocks All Unencrypted Traffic to Its API Endpoints</h2> <p>Cloudflare has implemented a new security policy that blocks all unencrypted (HTTP) traffic to its API endpoints, enforcing HTTPS-only connections. This move aims to strengthen user data protection and prevent man-in-the-middle attacks that exploit unsecured transmissions. The change could impact older applications or tools that still use HTTP, prompting developers to update their integrations. Cloudflare encourages all users to adopt secure communication protocols going forward.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/cloudflare-now-blocks-all-unencrypted-traffic-to-its-api-endpoints/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-2-fbi-confirms-fake-file-converters-are-actively-pushing-malware">Story 2. FBI Confirms Fake File Converters Are Actively Pushing Malware</h2> <p>The FBI has confirmed that free online file converter websites are being used to distribute malware under the guise of harmless file conversion services. These platforms lure users with promises of converting documents, videos, or images, but secretly deliver spyware and remote access trojans (RATs). Victims unknowingly compromise their systems when downloading the output. Users are advised to stick to trusted software for file conversions and avoid suspicious websites.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/fbi-warnings-are-true-fake-file-converters-do-push-malware/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-3-cybercriminals-exploiting-notification-channels-to-spread-malware">Story 3. Cybercriminals Exploiting Notification Channels to Spread Malware</h2> <p>Hackers are increasingly abusing legitimate notification systems—like browser alerts, push notifications, and mobile pop-ups—to deliver malicious links and social engineering messages. These tactics exploit user trust in seemingly routine system messages, leading to credential theft or malware downloads. The attacks often mimic well-known platforms like Microsoft, Google, or banking apps. Experts advise users to avoid clicking pop-up messages and to access services directly through official apps or websites.<br/> <a href="https://hackread.com/how-cybercriminals-exploit-notification-channels/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-4-microsoft-exchange-online-bug-mistakenly-quarantines-legitimate-emails">Story 4. Microsoft Exchange Online Bug Mistakenly Quarantines Legitimate Emails</h2> <p>A recent bug in Microsoft Exchange Online caused legitimate user emails to be incorrectly flagged and quarantined. The issue affected both internal and external email delivery, frustrating organizations that rely heavily on cloud-based communication. Microsoft has since acknowledged the problem and issued a fix, but not before users reported disruptions to workflow and delayed correspondence. Administrators are urged to review quarantine policies and adjust filtering settings as needed.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/microsoft/microsoft-exchange-online-bug-mistakenly-quarantines-user-emails/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-5-uat-5918-threat-group-targets-critical-infrastructure-in-taiwan">Story 5. UAT-5918 Threat Group Targets Critical Infrastructure in Taiwan</h2> <p>A suspected state-sponsored group identified as UAT-5918 has launched cyberattacks against critical infrastructure in Taiwan, including telecom and energy sectors. The group, believed to be aligned with China, is using advanced persistent threat (APT) tactics to steal sensitive data and establish long-term access. The attacks are part of broader geopolitical tensions and efforts to destabilize key industries. Taiwanese authorities are responding with heightened monitoring and coordinated defense strategies.<br/> <a href="https://securityaffairs.com/175728/hacking/uat-5918-atp-group-targets-critical-taiwan.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-6-hacker-claims-to-have-access-to-6-million-oracle-customer-records">Story 6. Hacker Claims to Have Access to 6 Million Oracle Customer Records</h2> <p>A hacker is claiming responsibility for breaching Oracle and stealing over 6 million customer records, allegedly including sensitive business data and credentials. The individual is offering the stolen data for sale on a dark web forum and has posted samples to prove legitimacy. If true, this breach could have widespread implications for Oracle customers globally. Oracle has denied any confirmed breach, stating it is investigating the claim.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/hacker-claims-6-million-oracle-records/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-7-oracle-denies-breach-after-hacker-offers-6-million-records-for-sale">Story 7. Oracle Denies Breach After Hacker Offers 6 Million Records for Sale</h2> <p>Following the claims of a massive breach, Oracle has issued a public statement denying any evidence of unauthorized access to its systems. The company asserts that internal reviews have not identified any data compromise and continues to investigate the situation. Meanwhile, cybersecurity experts are analyzing the hacker’s data samples for authenticity. Users are advised to remain cautious and monitor their Oracle services for unusual activity.<br/> <a href="https://hackread.com/oracle-denies-breach-hacker-access-6-million-records/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-8-coinbase-was-the-primary-target-in-recent-github-actions-attacks">Story 8. Coinbase Was the Primary Target in Recent GitHub Actions Attacks</h2> <p>Recent breaches involving GitHub Actions have been linked to a campaign targeting Coinbase, with attackers exploiting misconfigured automation workflows. By injecting malicious code into GitHub repositories, the attackers attempted to exfiltrate secrets and steal data from the cryptocurrency platform. Coinbase acted swiftly to mitigate the attack and reported no customer impact. GitHub has advised developers to harden workflow permissions and audit repositories for exposure.<br/> <a href="http://bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/coinbase-was-primary-target-of-recent-github-actions-breaches/">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[3-24-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-21-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0321/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-21-25"/><published>2025-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0321</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0321/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-03-21-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="story-1-cisa-tags-nakivo-backup-flaw-as-actively-exploited-in-attacks">Story 1. CISA Tags NAKIVO Backup Flaw as Actively Exploited in Attacks</h2> <p>The U.S. Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) has issued an alert regarding an actively exploited vulnerability in NAKIVO Backup &amp; Replication software. The flaw allows attackers to gain unauthorized access to backup environments, potentially leading to data theft or ransomware attacks. Threat actors are targeting unpatched instances to disrupt business continuity and compromise stored backups. Organizations using NAKIVO are strongly advised to apply patches immediately and enhance monitoring for suspicious activity.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/cisa-tags-nakivo-backup-flaw-as-actively-exploited-in-attacks/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story--2-ukraines-defense-sector-targeted-in-darkcrystal-rat-attack">Story 2. Ukraine’s Defense Sector Targeted in DarkCrystal RAT Attack</h2> <p>Cybersecurity researchers have detected a cyberattack campaign targeting Ukraine’s defense sector using the DarkCrystal Remote Access Trojan (RAT). The malware, attributed to Russian-affiliated hackers, enables full system control, credential theft, and espionage. The attack leverages phishing emails and malicious attachments to infiltrate government networks. Security analysts warn that these cyber operations aim to gather intelligence and disrupt Ukraine’s defense efforts.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyberattacks-data-breaches/ukraine-defense-sector-attack-dark-crystal-rat">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story--3-ransomhub-ransomware-uses-new-betruger-multi-function-backdoor">Story 3. RansomHub Ransomware Uses New “Betruger” Multi-Function Backdoor</h2> <p>The RansomHub ransomware gang has introduced a new backdoor named “Betruger,” enabling advanced persistence and stealth in corporate networks. This multi-function backdoor allows cybercriminals to evade detection while stealing data and deploying ransomware. Security researchers note that RansomHub is using more sophisticated tactics, making it harder for organizations to defend against attacks. Experts advise businesses to strengthen endpoint protection and implement proactive threat-hunting measures.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/ransomhub-ransomware-uses-new-betruger-multi-function-backdoor/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story--4-veeam-faces-criticism-over-response-to-critical-vulnerability">Story 4. Veeam Faces Criticism Over Response to Critical Vulnerability</h2> <p>Veeam, a leading backup and disaster recovery provider, is facing backlash for its delayed response to a critical vulnerability in its software. Security researchers and industry experts argue that the company failed to act swiftly in addressing the flaw, leaving many organizations exposed to cyber threats. The vulnerability allows unauthorized access to backup environments, making it a prime target for ransomware groups. Users are urged to apply security patches immediately and monitor for suspicious activity.<br/> <a href="https://www.theregister.com/2025/03/20/infoseccers_criticize_veeam_over_critical/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story--5-is-it-time-to-retire-one-off-pen-tests-for-continuous-security-testing">Story 5. Is It Time to Retire One-Off Pen Tests for Continuous Security Testing?</h2> <p>Cybersecurity experts are questioning the effectiveness of traditional one-time penetration testing in today’s evolving threat landscape. With cyber threats constantly changing, a shift toward continuous security testing is being advocated to provide real-time insights into vulnerabilities. Continuous testing enables organizations to detect and address weaknesses before attackers can exploit them. Many companies are now integrating automated security solutions and red teaming exercises to enhance their security posture.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/is-it-time-to-retire-one-off-pen-tests-for-continuous-testing/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story--6-brand-impersonation-accounts-for-51-of-browser-based-phishing-attacks">Story 6. Brand Impersonation Accounts for 51% of Browser-Based Phishing Attacks</h2> <p>A new study reveals that over half of browser-based phishing attacks rely on brand impersonation, tricking users into believing they are interacting with legitimate companies. Cybercriminals create fake login pages for services like Microsoft 365, PayPal, and banking platforms to steal credentials. These attacks exploit browser vulnerabilities and evade traditional email security filters. Users are urged to verify URLs carefully and enable multi-factor authentication (MFA) to protect their accounts.<br/> <a href="https://www.securitymagazine.com/articles/101485-brand-impersonation-is-51-of-browser-phishing-attempts">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story--7-new-steganographic-malware-hides-malicious-code-in-jpeg-files">Story 7. New Steganographic Malware Hides Malicious Code in JPEG Files</h2> <p>A newly discovered malware strain is using steganography to embed malicious payloads inside JPEG image files. This technique allows hackers to evade security tools by hiding malware within seemingly harmless images. Once opened, the malware executes commands that steal data or grant attackers remote access. Security experts advise users to be cautious when downloading images from untrusted sources and to keep their security software updated.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/new-steganographic-malware-exploits-jpeg-files/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story--8-how-threat-hunters-enrich-indicators-of-compromise-with-context">Story 8. How Threat Hunters Enrich Indicators of Compromise with Context</h2> <p>Threat-hunting teams are increasingly focusing on contextualizing Indicators of Compromise (IoCs) to improve cybersecurity defenses. By correlating IoCs with attack patterns, security professionals can detect malicious activity earlier and respond more effectively. Advanced threat intelligence tools now integrate machine learning and automation to enhance detection capabilities. Organizations are encouraged to adopt proactive threat-hunting strategies to stay ahead of cyber threats.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/how-threat-hunters-enrich-indicators-with-context/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story--9-how-to-protect-your-business-from-cyberattacks">Story 9. How to Protect Your Business from Cyberattacks</h2> <p>A recent cybersecurity guide highlights key strategies businesses can use to defend against modern cyber threats. Recommendations include implementing zero-trust security models, strengthening endpoint protections, and conducting employee security awareness training. As cybercriminals continue to exploit human and technical vulnerabilities, proactive risk management is essential. Organizations are urged to regularly update security policies and invest in advanced threat detection solutions.<br/> <a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/03/how-to-protect-your-business-from-cyber.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story--10-zero-hour-phishing-attacks-exploiting-browser-vulnerabilities">Story 10. Zero-Hour Phishing Attacks Exploiting Browser Vulnerabilities</h2> <p>A wave of zero-hour phishing attacks is targeting browser vulnerabilities, bypassing traditional security measures. These attacks exploit flaws in web browsers to execute malicious scripts that steal user credentials and session tokens. Cybercriminals are using these techniques to gain access to corporate networks and cloud services. Security professionals advise users to keep browsers updated and enable enhanced phishing protection settings.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/zero-hour-phishing-attacks-exploiting-browser-vulnerabilities/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story--11-chinese-salt-typhoon-hackers-exploiting-microsoft-exchange-vulnerabilities">Story 11. Chinese “Salt Typhoon” Hackers Exploiting Microsoft Exchange Vulnerabilities</h2> <p>A Chinese state-sponsored hacking group, dubbed “Salt Typhoon,” has been exploiting vulnerabilities in Microsoft Exchange servers to gain persistent access to corporate and government networks. These attacks focus on espionage, data theft, and establishing footholds for future cyber operations. Security researchers warn that unpatched Exchange servers remain prime targets for this threat actor. Organizations are strongly advised to apply security patches and enhance monitoring for unauthorized access attempts.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/chinese-salt-typhoon-hackers-exploiting-exchange-vulnerabilities/">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[3-21-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-20-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0320/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-20-25"/><published>2025-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0320</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0320/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-03-20-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="story--1-phishing-based-attacks-have-risen-140-year-over-year">Story 1. Phishing-Based Attacks Have Risen 140% Year Over Year</h2> <p>A new report highlights a staggering 140% increase in phishing-based attacks compared to the previous year. Cybercriminals are leveraging advanced social engineering tactics, AI-generated messages, and brand impersonation to trick victims into divulging credentials. The financial sector, healthcare, and government agencies have been among the most targeted. Security experts emphasize the importance of user education, multi-factor authentication (MFA), and improved email filtering to mitigate these growing threats.<br/> <a href="https://www.securitymagazine.com/articles/101479-phishing-based-attacks-have-risen-140-year-over-year">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story--2-attackers-embedding-malicious-word-files-inside-pdfs-to-evade-detection">Story 2. Attackers Embedding Malicious Word Files Inside PDFs to Evade Detection</h2> <p>Cybercriminals have developed a new attack technique that embeds malicious Microsoft Word files inside PDFs, allowing them to bypass traditional security filters. When victims open the seemingly harmless PDF, the hidden Word document automatically executes malware, granting attackers access to the system. This method effectively evades email security solutions that scan for standalone Word file threats. Users are advised to be cautious when opening unexpected PDF attachments and keep their software updated.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/attackers-embedding-malicious-word-file-into-a-pdf/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story--3-threat-actors-exploiting-legacy-drivers-to-evade-security-tools">Story 3. Threat Actors Exploiting Legacy Drivers to Evade Security Tools</h2> <p>Hackers are increasingly exploiting outdated and vulnerable drivers to bypass modern security defenses. Known as Bring Your Own Vulnerable Driver (BYOVD) attacks, this technique allows cybercriminals to disable endpoint detection and response (EDR) systems, gaining deeper access to compromised networks. Security researchers warn that legacy drivers, even if digitally signed, pose a significant threat if left unpatched. Organizations should enforce strict driver policies and use allowlists to prevent unauthorized installations.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/threat-actors-exploiting-legacy-drivers/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story--4-microsoft-exchange-online-outage-disrupts-outlook-web-users">Story 4. Microsoft Exchange Online Outage Disrupts Outlook Web Users</h2> <p>Microsoft Exchange Online experienced a major outage, leaving Outlook Web users unable to access their emails. The issue, which lasted several hours, affected customers worldwide, with Microsoft attributing it to an unexpected infrastructure issue. The downtime frustrated businesses and individuals relying on cloud-based email services for daily operations. Microsoft has since restored service and is investigating the root cause to prevent future incidents.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/microsoft/microsoft-exchange-online-outage-affects-outlook-web-users/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story--5-critical-fortinet-vulnerability-draws-fresh-attention-from-attackers">Story 5. Critical Fortinet Vulnerability Draws Fresh Attention from Attackers</h2> <p>A critical vulnerability in Fortinet’s network security devices has gained renewed interest from cybercriminals looking to exploit unpatched systems. The flaw, which allows remote code execution, could enable attackers to take full control of affected devices. Security experts warn that many organizations have yet to apply the necessary patches, leaving them vulnerable to potential breaches. Fortinet urges all users to update their devices immediately and monitor for suspicious activity.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyberattacks-data-breaches/critical-fortinet-vulnerability-draws-fresh-attention">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[3-20-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-19-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0319/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-19-25"/><published>2025-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0319</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0319/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-03-19-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="story-1-google-acquires-wiz-for-record-32-billion-in-largest-cybersecurity-deal-ever">Story 1. Google Acquires Wiz for Record $32 Billion in Largest Cybersecurity Deal Ever</h2> <p>Google has announced the acquisition of cloud security firm Wiz for a record-breaking $32 billion, making it the largest cybersecurity deal in history. Wiz, known for its advanced cloud-native security platform, helps companies identify and mitigate vulnerabilities across multi-cloud environments. This acquisition strengthens Google Cloud’s security offerings and positions it as a leading player in the cloud security market. Analysts expect this move to intensify competition with Microsoft and AWS in the cybersecurity space.<br/> <a href="https://hackread.com/google-acquires-wiz-for-record-32-billion/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-2-scammers-distribute-ad-fraud-apps-with-60-million-downloads-on-google-play">Story 2. Scammers Distribute Ad Fraud Apps with 60 Million Downloads on Google Play</h2> <p>Security researchers have uncovered a large-scale ad fraud scheme involving dozens of malicious Android apps with over 60 million downloads from Google Play. These apps secretly performed ad fraud in the background, draining user data and device resources while generating illegal revenue for scammers. Google has since removed the fraudulent apps, but many users remain affected. Experts advise Android users to carefully review app permissions and avoid downloading unknown applications.<br/> <a href="https://hackread.com/scammers-ad-fraud-apps-google-play-60m-downloads/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-3-critical-vulnerability-in-ami-megarac-bmc-allows-server-takeover">Story 3. Critical Vulnerability in AMI MegaRAC BMC Allows Server Takeover</h2> <p>A newly disclosed vulnerability in AMI MegaRAC Baseboard Management Controllers (BMC) could allow attackers to take over servers remotely. This critical flaw affects data centers and cloud infrastructure, posing a serious risk to enterprises using the vulnerable technology. Attackers could exploit the flaw to gain root access, disrupt operations, or install persistent backdoors. Organizations are urged to patch affected systems immediately to mitigate the risk of exploitation.<br/> <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3848376/critical-vulnerability-in-ami-megarac-bmc-allows-servers-takeover.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-4-infostealer-malware-attacks-surged-in-2024-flashpoint-report-finds">Story 4. InfoStealer Malware Attacks Surged in 2024, Flashpoint Report Finds</h2> <p>A new report from Flashpoint reveals that infostealer malware attacks surged throughout 2024, with cybercriminals increasingly targeting login credentials, financial data, and personal information. These malware strains, often delivered via phishing campaigns and malicious downloads, have been a primary driver of account takeovers and identity theft. The report highlights how the dark web marketplace for stolen data is fueling cybercrime. Security experts recommend enabling multi-factor authentication (MFA) and using endpoint detection tools to defend against these threats.<br/> <a href="https://cyberscoop.com/infostealers-cybercrime-surged-2024-flashpoint/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-5-nation-state-actors-and-cybercrime-gangs-abusing-malicious-lnk-files">Story 5. Nation-State Actors and Cybercrime Gangs Abusing Malicious LNK Files</h2> <p>Threat intelligence reports indicate that both state-sponsored hackers and cybercriminal gangs are increasingly using malicious LNK (Windows shortcut) files to distribute malware. These files, often disguised as legitimate documents, enable attackers to execute code remotely, steal sensitive information, and establish persistence on compromised systems. Recent campaigns have leveraged this technique for espionage, ransomware, and data exfiltration. Organizations are advised to restrict LNK execution in email attachments and implement strict security controls.<br/> <a href="https://securityaffairs.com/175569/apt/nation-state-actors-and-cybercrime-gangs-abuse-malicious-lnk-files-for-espionage-and-data-theft.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-6-black-basta-ransomware-gangs-leaked-chat-logs-reveal-ties-to-russian-officials">Story 6. Black Basta Ransomware Gang’s Leaked Chat Logs Reveal Ties to Russian Officials</h2> <p>Leaked internal chat logs from the Black Basta ransomware gang suggest connections to Russian government officials. The logs reveal discussions about attack strategies, ransom negotiations, and possible state protection for cybercriminal activities. If confirmed, these findings further link ransomware operations to Russian intelligence services. This leak may provide valuable intelligence for law enforcement agencies investigating ransomware networks.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/threat-intelligence/black-basta-league-russian-officials-chat-logs">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-7-8-year-old-windows-shortcut-zero-day-exploited-in-recent-attacks">Story 7. 8-Year-Old Windows Shortcut Zero-Day Exploited in Recent Attacks</h2> <p>A newly discovered cyberattack campaign is exploiting an 8-year-old zero-day vulnerability in Windows shortcut (LNK) files. Despite Microsoft’s past attempts to mitigate such threats, attackers have found new ways to weaponize the flaw, allowing them to execute malicious code with minimal user interaction. The vulnerability is being actively exploited in targeted attacks against businesses and government entities. Security researchers recommend disabling shortcut execution for untrusted sources and applying available patches.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/8-year-old-windows-shortcut-zero-day/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-8-bybit-hack-a-sophisticated-multi-stage-attack-compromised-cryptocurrency-exchange">Story 8. Bybit Hack: A Sophisticated Multi-Stage Attack Compromised Cryptocurrency Exchange</h2> <p>The recent cyberattack on the Bybit cryptocurrency exchange involved a sophisticated multi-stage intrusion that allowed attackers to steal millions in digital assets. Hackers leveraged social engineering, zero-day exploits, and advanced obfuscation techniques to bypass security measures. Bybit has since tightened its security protocols, but the breach highlights the growing risks for crypto exchanges. Users are advised to enable two-factor authentication and use hardware wallets for enhanced security.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/bybit-hack-sophisticated-multi-stage-attack/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-9-chatgpt-ssrf-bug-becomes-a-favorite-attack-vector-for-hackers">Story 9. ChatGPT SSRF Bug Becomes a Favorite Attack Vector for Hackers</h2> <p>Hackers have quickly adopted a newly discovered Server-Side Request Forgery (SSRF) vulnerability in ChatGPT, exploiting it in real-world attacks. The flaw, CVE-2025-XXXX, allows attackers to manipulate AI-generated responses and access restricted internal services. Cybercriminals are using this technique to extract sensitive data and bypass security measures in AI-integrated platforms. OpenAI and security experts are working on a fix, but organizations using AI-powered applications should monitor for suspicious activity.<br/> <a href="https://securityaffairs.com/175560/hacking/chatgpt-ssrf-bug-quickly-becomes-a-favorite-attack-vector.html">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[3-19-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-18-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0318/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-18-25"/><published>2025-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0318</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0318/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-03-18-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="story-1-oauth-attacks-target-microsoft-365-and-github-accounts">Story 1. OAuth Attacks Target Microsoft 365 and GitHub Accounts</h2> <p>Cybercriminals are exploiting OAuth vulnerabilities to compromise Microsoft 365 and GitHub accounts. Attackers use fraudulent third-party applications to trick users into granting excessive permissions, enabling access to sensitive emails, repositories, and cloud resources. Once authorized, these apps can be used for data exfiltration and further phishing attacks. Security experts recommend reviewing OAuth app permissions regularly and restricting access to trusted applications only.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/oauth-attacks-target-microsoft-365-github">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-2-new-steganographic-malware-attack-hides-code-inside-jpg-files">Story 2. New Steganographic Malware Attack Hides Code Inside JPG Files</h2> <p>A newly discovered steganographic malware campaign is using image files to conceal malicious payloads. Attackers embed malware within seemingly harmless JPG images, which execute code when opened on a compromised device. This method allows cybercriminals to evade traditional antivirus detection while delivering remote access trojans (RATs) or keyloggers. Users are advised to avoid downloading images from untrusted sources and keep their security software updated.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/new-steganographic-malware-attack-via-jpg-file/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-3-chinese-volt-typhoon-hackers-exploiting-cisco-and-netgear-routers">Story 3. Chinese Volt Typhoon Hackers Exploiting Cisco and Netgear Routers</h2> <p>The Chinese state-sponsored hacking group Volt Typhoon has been observed exploiting vulnerabilities in Cisco and Netgear routers. These compromised devices are being used as stepping stones for cyber-espionage campaigns targeting critical infrastructure. By hijacking consumer and enterprise networking equipment, the attackers can evade detection and establish persistent access. Security experts recommend updating router firmware and disabling remote management features.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/chinese-volt-typhoon-hackers-exploiting-cisco-netgear-routers/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-4-attackers-use-css-to-create-evasive-phishing-messages">Story 4. Attackers Use CSS to Create Evasive Phishing Messages</h2> <p>A new phishing technique leverages Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) to evade email security filters and trick users into revealing credentials. By embedding malicious payloads in CSS files, attackers can create emails that bypass spam detection while appearing legitimate. This method makes phishing campaigns harder to detect and block. Experts advise users to verify email senders, avoid clicking on suspicious links, and enable multi-factor authentication (MFA).<br/> <a href="https://securityaffairs.com/175512/security/attackers-use-css-to-create-evasive-phishing-messages.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-5-23000-github-repositories-targeted-in-large-scale-supply-chain-attack">Story 5. 23,000 GitHub Repositories Targeted in Large-Scale Supply Chain Attack</h2> <p>A massive cyberattack campaign has targeted over 23,000 GitHub repositories, injecting malicious code into open-source projects. The attackers use dependency hijacking and repository takeover techniques to compromise software supply chains. Developers who unknowingly use infected dependencies may expose their applications to backdoors and data breaches. Security professionals recommend verifying package integrity and implementing strict repository security controls.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/23000-github-repositories-targeted/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-6-toll-road-text-message-scam-spreads-nationwide">Story 6. Toll Road Text Message Scam Spreads Nationwide</h2> <p>A phishing scam disguised as toll road payment notifications has been spreading rapidly across the U.S. Victims receive fraudulent text messages claiming they owe unpaid tolls, leading them to fake payment portals that steal financial details. Authorities warn that these scams are highly sophisticated and designed to mimic official transportation agencies. Drivers are advised to verify toll charges through official state websites and never click on unsolicited payment links.<br/> <a href="https://cyberscoop.com/toll-road-text-message-scam-swells-nationwide-how-to-stop/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-7-hackers-exploit-chatgpt-vulnerability-cve-2024-27564-in-10000-attacks">Story 7. Hackers Exploit ChatGPT Vulnerability CVE-2024-27564 in 10,000 Attacks</h2> <p>Threat actors have been exploiting a newly disclosed vulnerability, CVE-2024-27564, in ChatGPT-related APIs, enabling them to conduct over 10,000 attacks. This security flaw allows attackers to manipulate AI-generated responses, steal user data, and bypass content restrictions. Organizations integrating AI services are at risk of data leakage and misinformation attacks. Security experts recommend applying patches immediately and monitoring AI interactions for suspicious activity.<br/> <a href="https://hackread.com/hackers-exploit-chatgpt-cve-2024-27564-10000-attacks/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-8-free-online-file-converters-are-installing-malware-on-users-devices">Story 8. Free Online File Converters Are Installing Malware on Users’ Devices</h2> <p>Security researchers have found that many free online file conversion tools are secretly installing malware on users’ devices. These fraudulent sites trick users into uploading files for conversion while delivering hidden malware payloads in return. The malware includes spyware, keyloggers, and adware that compromise system security. Users are encouraged to use trusted software for file conversions and avoid suspicious websites.<br/> <a href="https://www.malwarebytes.com/blog/news/2025/03/warning-over-free-online-file-converters-that-actually-install-malware">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[3-18-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-17-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0317/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-17-25"/><published>2025-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0317</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0317/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-03-17-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="story-1-100-auto-dealers-hacked-through-a-clickfix-webpage">Story 1. 100 Auto Dealers Hacked Through a ClickFix Webpage</h2> <p>A cyberattack leveraging the ClickFix exploit has compromised 100 auto dealerships, allowing hackers to install malware remotely. The attackers used a malicious webpage to trick employees into clicking a fraudulent fix, which led to network-wide infections. This breach resulted in system outages, stolen customer data, and financial losses. Security experts urge companies to verify update sources and train employees on recognizing phishing tactics.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/100-auto-dealers-hacked-with-a-clickfix-webpage/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-2-malicious-pypi-packages-stole-cloud-credentials-from-developers">Story 2. Malicious PyPI Packages Stole Cloud Credentials from Developers</h2> <p>Security researchers uncovered multiple malicious Python packages on the PyPI repository designed to steal cloud credentials from unsuspecting developers. These packages, disguised as legitimate tools, exfiltrated AWS and Google Cloud API keys upon installation. The campaign highlights the persistent threat of supply chain attacks on software development ecosystems. Developers are advised to scrutinize open-source dependencies and use credential managers to protect sensitive information.<br/> <a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/03/malicious-pypi-packages-stole-cloud.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-3-deepseek-r1-ai-model-jailbroken-to-bypass-content-restrictions">Story 3. DeepSeek R1 AI Model Jailbroken to Bypass Content Restrictions</h2> <p>Hackers have successfully jailbroken the DeepSeek R1 AI model, bypassing its built-in content restrictions. This exploit allows users to generate outputs that violate ethical guidelines, including misinformation and restricted content. The discovery raises concerns about the security of AI models and their susceptibility to manipulation. AI developers are urged to implement stronger security measures to prevent unauthorized modifications.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/deepseek-r1-jailbreaked/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-4-new-massjacker-clipper-malware-targets-users-downloading-pirated-software">Story 4. New MassJacker Clipper Malware Targets Users Downloading Pirated Software</h2> <p>A new malware strain, dubbed “MassJacker,” is spreading through pirated software downloads, targeting cryptocurrency users. This clipper malware silently replaces copied crypto wallet addresses with those controlled by attackers, leading to stolen funds. The campaign primarily affects users looking for cracked software, reinforcing the dangers of downloading from untrusted sources. Experts advise against using pirated software and recommend keeping antivirus programs updated.<br/> <a href="https://securityaffairs.com/175433/malware/new-massjacker-clipper-targets-pirated-software-seekers.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-5-malicious-adobe--docusign-oauth-apps-target-microsoft-365-accounts">Story 5. Malicious Adobe &amp; DocuSign OAuth Apps Target Microsoft 365 Accounts</h2> <p>Cybercriminals are using fake Adobe and DocuSign OAuth apps to compromise Microsoft 365 accounts. These malicious applications trick users into granting permissions, allowing attackers to access emails, documents, and cloud storage. Once inside, hackers can exfiltrate sensitive data and launch further phishing attacks. Organizations should review OAuth permissions regularly and educate employees on identifying suspicious login requests.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/malicious-adobe-docusign-oauth-apps-target-microsoft-365-accounts/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-6-fake-security-alerts-on-github-use-oauth-apps-to-hijack-accounts">Story 6. Fake Security Alerts on GitHub Use OAuth Apps to Hijack Accounts</h2> <p>Attackers are leveraging fake security alerts on GitHub to trick developers into authorizing malicious OAuth applications. These fake alerts warn users of security issues and prompt them to grant permissions to a compromised app, leading to account takeovers. Once access is gained, attackers can modify repositories, inject malicious code, and steal sensitive data. Developers should verify security warnings directly through GitHub settings and avoid clicking on unsolicited links.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/fake-security-alert-issues-on-github-use-oauth-app-to-hijack-accounts/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-7-denmark-warns-of-increased-state-sponsored-attacks-on-european-telecoms">Story 7. Denmark Warns of Increased State-Sponsored Attacks on European Telecoms</h2> <p>Danish authorities have issued a warning about rising state-sponsored cyber campaigns targeting European telecommunications providers. Intelligence officials suspect nation-state actors, particularly from Russia and China, are attempting to infiltrate telecom networks for espionage and disruption purposes. These attacks pose a significant risk to critical infrastructure, including mobile networks and internet services. Telecom companies are urged to enhance cybersecurity measures and monitor for advanced persistent threats.<br/> <a href="https://securityaffairs.com/175479/intelligence/denmark-warns-of-increased-state-sponsored-campaigns-targeting-the-european-telcos.html">Read more here</a> ```</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[3-17-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-7-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0307/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-7-25"/><published>2025-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0307</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0307/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-03-07-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="story-1-the-future-of-cybersecurity-lies-in-governance-not-more-tools">Story 1. The Future of Cybersecurity Lies in Governance, Not More Tools</h2> <p>Experts argue that cybersecurity strategies must shift from an over-reliance on security tools to stronger governance and risk management. While new technologies can help detect threats, they cannot replace structured policies, user education, and clear accountability. Organizations need to prioritize proactive security governance, including regulatory compliance and incident response planning. A well-implemented governance framework can significantly reduce cybersecurity risks and improve long-term resilience.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyber-risk/cybersecurity-future-governance-not-more-tools">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-2-researchers-bypass-crowdstrike-falcon-sensor-exposing-detection-weakness">Story 2. Researchers Bypass CrowdStrike Falcon Sensor, Exposing Detection Weakness</h2> <p>Security researchers have demonstrated a method to bypass CrowdStrike’s Falcon Sensor, an advanced endpoint detection and response (EDR) tool. The exploit allows attackers to evade detection and execute malicious code undetected. While CrowdStrike is investigating the bypass technique, the findings raise concerns about the effectiveness of security solutions in stopping sophisticated attacks. Experts recommend using multiple layers of security rather than relying on a single detection tool.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/researchers-bypassed-crowdstrike-falcon-sensor/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-3-deepfake-videos-on-youtube-used-to-phish-content-creators">Story 3. Deepfake Videos on YouTube Used to Phish Content Creators</h2> <p>Cybercriminals are using deepfake videos on YouTube to target content creators with phishing scams. The attackers create fake videos featuring AI-generated influencers promoting fraudulent sponsorship deals, tricking victims into downloading malware. Once installed, the malware steals login credentials and financial information. Security professionals urge YouTube users to verify sponsorships and avoid downloading files from untrusted sources.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/remote-workforce/deepfake-videos-youtube-phish-creators">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-4-invoke-adcheck-a-new-powershell-based-tool-used-for-cyber-attacks">Story 4. Invoke-ADCheck: A New PowerShell-Based Tool Used for Cyber Attacks</h2> <p>Hackers are leveraging a newly discovered PowerShell tool called Invoke-ADCheck to automate reconnaissance on Active Directory environments. This tool allows attackers to gather information about domain controllers, user privileges, and security policies before launching further attacks. While it was originally developed for security auditing, malicious actors have started weaponizing it. Organizations are encouraged to monitor PowerShell execution logs and restrict unnecessary administrative access.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/invokeadcheck-powershell-based-tool/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-5-microsoft-365-apps-to-prompt-users-to-back-up-files-in-onedrive">Story 5. Microsoft 365 Apps to Prompt Users to Back Up Files in OneDrive</h2> <p>Microsoft is introducing a new feature in Microsoft 365 apps that will prompt users to back up their files to OneDrive. The goal is to prevent data loss due to ransomware attacks, hardware failures, or accidental deletions. Users will receive proactive notifications encouraging them to enable automatic backups for critical files. This move aligns with Microsoft’s broader efforts to enhance cloud-based security and data protection.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/microsoft/microsoft-365-apps-will-prompt-users-to-back-up-files-in-onedrive/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-6-ethereum-private-key-stealer-on-pypi-downloaded-over-1000-times">Story 6. Ethereum Private Key Stealer on PyPI Downloaded Over 1,000 Times</h2> <p>A malicious Python package on the PyPI repository was found stealing Ethereum private keys from unsuspecting developers. The package, which had over 1,000 downloads before removal, contained code designed to extract and transmit sensitive wallet data. This incident highlights the growing risk of supply chain attacks targeting open-source repositories. Developers are urged to verify package integrity before installation and avoid downloading unverified dependencies.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/ethereum-private-key-stealer-on-pypi-downloaded-over-1-000-times/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-7-ransomware-gang-used-a-webcam-to-bypass-edr-and-encrypt-a-network">Story 7. Ransomware Gang Used a Webcam to Bypass EDR and Encrypt a Network</h2> <p>A ransomware group found a creative way to bypass endpoint detection and response (EDR) tools by exploiting a vulnerable network-connected webcam. By using the device as an entry point, attackers were able to disable security defenses and encrypt the entire network. This attack underscores the importance of securing all connected devices, including IoT and peripheral hardware. Organizations should apply firmware updates and segment IoT devices to limit attack vectors.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/ransomware-gang-encrypted-network-from-a-webcam-to-bypass-edr/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-8-microsoft-reports-malvertising-campaign-impacted-over-1-million-pcs">Story 8. Microsoft Reports Malvertising Campaign Impacted Over 1 Million PCs</h2> <p>A large-scale malvertising campaign has compromised over 1 million PCs worldwide, according to Microsoft. Attackers used fraudulent advertisements on search engines and social media to distribute malware, tricking users into downloading infected software. Victims unknowingly installed malicious payloads that enabled remote access, data theft, and ransomware infections. Experts recommend using ad blockers and verifying software sources before downloading applications.<br/> <a href="http://bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/microsoft-says-malvertising-campaign-impacted-1-million-pcs/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-9-international-law-enforcement-seizes-major-ransomware-gangs">Story 9. International Law Enforcement Seizes Major Ransomware Gangs</h2> <p>A coordinated international law enforcement operation has led to the takedown of multiple ransomware gangs. Authorities seized infrastructure, arrested key members, and disrupted ransom payment channels used by cybercriminal organizations. The operation marks a significant victory in the global fight against ransomware, but experts warn that new groups may emerge to fill the void. Businesses are encouraged to strengthen cybersecurity measures to prevent future attacks.<br/> <a href="https://www.theregister.com/2025/03/06/international_cops_seize_ransomware_gangs/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-10-encrypthubs-opsec-failures-reveal-cybercriminal-tactics">Story 10. EncryptHub’s OPSEC Failures Reveal Cybercriminal Tactics</h2> <p>EncryptHub, a notorious cybercriminal marketplace, has suffered major operational security (OPSEC) failures, exposing its hacking tools and customer data. The leaks have provided law enforcement agencies with valuable intelligence on cybercriminal tactics and infrastructure. As a result, several ongoing investigations into ransomware groups and dark web operations have accelerated. The incident highlights the growing risks for cybercriminals operating in underground markets.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/threat-intelligence/encrypthub-opsec-failures-ttps-big-plans">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[3-7-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-6-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0306/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-6-25"/><published>2025-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0306</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0306/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-03-06-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="1-cybercriminals-now-launch-attacks-at-record-speed">1. Cybercriminals Now Launch Attacks at Record Speed</h2> <p>A new report highlights that cybercriminals are deploying attacks at unprecedented speeds, often compromising systems within minutes. Advanced automation tools and AI-driven techniques enable hackers to scan for vulnerabilities and exploit them rapidly. Security experts warn that traditional reactive defenses are no longer sufficient, urging organizations to implement proactive threat detection and response strategies. The increasing speed of cyberattacks underscores the importance of real-time monitoring and zero-trust security frameworks.<br/> <a href="https://cyberscoop.com/cybercriminals-record-speed-attacks-2024/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="2-vishing-attacks-increased-by-442-in-the-second-half-of-2024">2. Vishing Attacks Increased by 442% in the Second Half of 2024</h2> <p>Voice phishing, or “vishing,” attacks surged by 442% in late 2024, as cybercriminals exploited social engineering to deceive victims over the phone. Attackers impersonated IT support staff, financial institutions, and government agencies to trick individuals into divulging sensitive information. The rise in AI-powered voice cloning has made these attacks more convincing and difficult to detect. Security professionals advise organizations to implement strict identity verification protocols and educate employees on recognizing vishing scams.<br/> <a href="https://www.securitymagazine.com/articles/101439-vishing-attacks-increased-by-442-in-the-second-half-of-2024">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="3-taylor-swift-fans-targeted-in-massive-stubhub-ticket-theft">3. Taylor Swift Fans Targeted in Massive StubHub Ticket Theft</h2> <p>Cybercriminals have stolen thousands of Taylor Swift concert tickets from StubHub accounts, leaving fans locked out of their purchased events. The attackers used credential stuffing techniques, exploiting reused passwords from previous data breaches to gain access to accounts. Victims reported unauthorized ticket transfers, with resellers profiting from the stolen tickets on secondary markets. StubHub is urging users to enable two-factor authentication (2FA) and reset compromised passwords to prevent further losses.<br/> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/05/business/taylor-swift-tickets-stolen-stubhub.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="4-crafty-camel-apt-targets-aviation-industry-with-polyglot-malware">4. “Crafty Camel” APT Targets Aviation Industry with Polyglot Malware</h2> <p>A newly identified advanced persistent threat (APT) group, dubbed “Crafty Camel,” is targeting the aviation sector’s operational technology (OT) systems. The attackers use polyglot files—malware that can execute across multiple platforms—to evade detection and maintain persistence. This sophisticated attack method threatens flight operations, maintenance systems, and supply chain security. Security analysts recommend enhanced monitoring of aviation networks and strict access controls to mitigate the risk.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/ics-ot-security/crafty-camel-apt-aviation-ot-polygot-files">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="5-china-linked-silk-typhoon-apt-targets-it-supply-chains">5. China-Linked “Silk Typhoon” APT Targets IT Supply Chains</h2> <p>A Chinese cyber-espionage group known as “Silk Typhoon” has been targeting global IT supply chains, compromising managed service providers and software vendors. By infiltrating supply chains, the attackers gain indirect access to a wide range of businesses and government entities. Their techniques include exploiting zero-day vulnerabilities and deploying backdoors to maintain long-term access. Security experts warn that organizations must improve vendor risk assessments and enforce stricter supply chain security measures.<br/> <a href="https://securityaffairs.com/174962/apt/china-linked-apt-silk-typhoon-targets-it-supply-chain.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="6-us-indicts-chinese-nationals-for-espionage-linked-cyberattacks">6. U.S. Indicts Chinese Nationals for Espionage-Linked Cyberattacks</h2> <p>The U.S. Department of Justice has indicted multiple Chinese nationals for their involvement in cyber-espionage attacks targeting American companies and government agencies. The individuals allegedly conducted hacking campaigns on behalf of the Chinese government, stealing sensitive intellectual property and classified data. The indictment follows a years-long investigation into China-linked cyber threats against critical industries. Officials emphasize that the charges signal a growing international effort to combat state-sponsored cyber espionage.<br/> <a href="https://cyberscoop.com/chinese-nationals-indictments-espionage-attacks/">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[3-6-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-5-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0305/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-5-25"/><published>2025-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0305</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0305/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-03-05-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h1 id="cybersecurity-stories-summary">Cybersecurity Stories Summary</h1> <h3 id="story1-new-eleven11bot-botnet-infects-86000-devices-for-ddos-attacks">Story1. New Eleven11Bot Botnet Infects 86,000 Devices for DDoS Attacks</h3> <p>A newly discovered botnet, Eleven11Bot, has infected over 86,000 devices to launch large-scale Distributed Denial-of-Service (DDoS) attacks. The malware primarily targets routers, IoT devices, and unpatched servers, taking advantage of weak security settings. Security researchers warn that the botnet’s rapid growth could enable attackers to disrupt critical online services. Organizations and individuals are advised to update firmware, use strong passwords, and disable unnecessary remote access features to mitigate risks.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/new-eleven11bot-botnet-infects-86-000-devices-for-ddos-attacks/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story2-hackers-abusing-microsoft-teams-quick-assist-to-gain-remote-access">Story2. Hackers Abusing Microsoft Teams Quick Assist to Gain Remote Access</h3> <p>Cybercriminals are exploiting Microsoft Teams’ Quick Assist feature to gain unauthorized remote access to corporate networks. Attackers pose as IT support personnel, convincing victims to grant them control over their systems. Once inside, they deploy malware, steal sensitive data, or launch further attacks. Security experts recommend disabling Quick Assist for non-essential users and educating employees on recognizing social engineering threats.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/hackers-abusing-microsoft-teams-quick-assist/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story3-hackers-attacking-4000-isps-worldwide-in-coordinated-cyber-assault">Story3. Hackers Attacking 4,000 ISPs Worldwide in Coordinated Cyber Assault</h3> <p>A sophisticated cyberattack campaign has been detected targeting over 4,000 internet service providers (ISPs) across multiple countries. The attackers are exploiting vulnerabilities in ISP infrastructure to intercept traffic, steal data, and launch further cyberattacks. Researchers suspect that nation-state actors may be involved in these intrusions. Affected ISPs are urged to patch vulnerabilities and implement stronger network security controls to prevent further breaches.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/hackers-attacking-4000-isps/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story4-96-of-ransomware-incidents-now-involve-data-exfiltration">Story4. 96% of Ransomware Incidents Now Involve Data Exfiltration</h3> <p>A new study reveals that 96% of ransomware attacks now include data exfiltration, meaning cybercriminals steal sensitive data before encrypting files. This tactic increases pressure on victims to pay ransom, as attackers threaten to leak stolen data if demands are not met. The shift in ransomware tactics highlights the need for organizations to strengthen both data protection and incident response strategies. Security experts recommend regular backups, network segmentation, and endpoint detection solutions.<br/> <a href="https://www.securitymagazine.com/articles/101435-96-of-ransomware-incidents-involve-data-exfiltration">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story5-us-seizes-31-million-stolen-in-cryptocurrency-cybercrime-operations">Story5. U.S. Seizes $31 Million Stolen in Cryptocurrency Cybercrime Operations</h3> <p>The U.S. government has successfully recovered $31 million in stolen cryptocurrency linked to cybercriminal activities. The funds were originally stolen through sophisticated phishing scams and ransomware operations targeting individuals and businesses. Authorities worked with blockchain analysis firms to track and seize the assets. The seizure is part of a broader effort to crack down on illicit cryptocurrency transactions.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/u-s-seizes-31-million-funds-drained/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story6-vmware-security-flaws-exploited-in-active-cyberattacks">Story6. VMware Security Flaws Exploited in Active Cyberattacks</h3> <p>Security researchers have identified multiple VMware vulnerabilities that are being actively exploited in cyberattacks. These flaws allow attackers to gain remote access, execute arbitrary code, and compromise virtualized environments. Organizations using VMware products are strongly urged to apply patches and implement security best practices. The incident underscores the critical need for timely software updates to prevent exploitation.<br/> <a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/03/vmware-security-flaws-exploited-in.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story7-hackers-deliver-xworm-malware-via-malicious-windows-registry-files">Story7. Hackers Deliver XWorm Malware via Malicious Windows Registry Files</h3> <p>A new cyberattack campaign is using malicious Windows registry files to distribute the XWorm malware. This sophisticated technique allows attackers to execute the malware without triggering traditional antivirus alerts. Once deployed, XWorm can steal credentials, exfiltrate sensitive data, and enable remote access for further exploitation. Users are advised to avoid running untrusted registry files and implement endpoint security solutions.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/hackers-deliver-xworm-via-malicious-registry-files/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story8-threat-actor-javaghost-targets-aws-environments-with-phishing-scheme">Story8. Threat Actor “JavaGhost” Targets AWS Environments with Phishing Scheme</h3> <p>A newly identified cyber threat, dubbed “JavaGhost,” is targeting AWS cloud environments through sophisticated phishing campaigns. Attackers trick victims into installing malicious Java-based payloads that allow unauthorized access to cloud resources. The malware enables credential theft, privilege escalation, and data exfiltration. Security professionals recommend implementing multi-factor authentication (MFA) and regularly reviewing cloud security policies to defend against such attacks.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cloud-security/threat-actor-javaghost-targets-aws-environments-phishing-scheme">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="story9-microsoft-teams-being-used-to-deploy-black-basta-and-cactus-ransomware">Story9. Microsoft Teams Being Used to Deploy Black Basta and Cactus Ransomware</h3> <p>Cybercriminals are using Microsoft Teams as a delivery mechanism to spread the Black Basta and Cactus ransomware strains. Attackers infiltrate Teams environments and send malicious files to unsuspecting users, leading to system encryption and data theft. The technique bypasses traditional email security controls, making it a highly effective attack vector. Organizations are urged to restrict external file-sharing in Teams and educate employees on recognizing suspicious messages.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/microsoft-teams-tactics-malware-connect-black-basta-cactus-ransomware/">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[3-5-25]]></summary></entry></feed>