<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-07-05T00:48:37+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DJBSec, CISSP</title><subtitle>DJBSec is an IT veteran with over 25 years of experience in IT and Cyber Security </subtitle><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2025-07-04</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0704/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2025-07-04"/><published>2025-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0704</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0704/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-2025-07-04.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <p>Story 1. Microsoft Asks Users to Ignore Windows Firewall Config Errors</p> <p>Microsoft has asked users to ignore Windows Firewall configuration errors that appeared after the recent security updates. The company confirmed these errors are due to a bug in the update process and do not impact actual firewall functionality. A fix is being developed and will be rolled out in upcoming patches. Users are advised not to make manual changes as these warnings are cosmetic.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/microsoft/microsoft-asks-users-to-ignore-windows-firewall-config-errors/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 2. Let’s Encrypt Rolls Out Free ECDSA Certificates</p> <p>Let’s Encrypt has started issuing free ECDSA certificates to improve website performance and security. These certificates use elliptic curve cryptography, offering better efficiency and stronger security compared to traditional RSA certificates. Website owners can now choose ECDSA certificates when generating new SSL certificates through Let’s Encrypt. This move aims to enhance encryption standards across the internet at no additional cost.</p> <p><a href="https://www.theregister.com/2025/07/03/lets_encrypt_rolls_out_free/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 3. Threat Actors Weaponize PDFs to Impersonate Microsoft, DocuSign, Dropbox</p> <p>Cybercriminals are increasingly using weaponized PDF files to impersonate brands like Microsoft, DocuSign, and Dropbox. These PDFs contain phishing links or malware designed to steal user credentials or install malicious payloads. Security researchers warn that these documents often bypass email security filters due to their legitimate appearance. Users are urged to verify PDF senders and avoid opening unexpected attachments.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/threat-actors-weaponize-pdfs-to-impersonate-microsoft-docusign-dropbox/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 4. AI-Generated Phishing Websites Becoming More Sophisticated</p> <p>New research reveals cybercriminals are using AI to generate highly convincing phishing websites. These sites mimic legitimate brands with improved design, language accuracy, and realistic layouts, making them harder to detect. Security experts warn that AI lowers the barrier for attackers to create targeted phishing campaigns at scale. Organizations are advised to enhance user awareness training and detection capabilities against this evolving threat.</p> <p><a href="https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/07/03/ai_phishing_websites/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 5. Hackers Actively Attacking Linux SSH Servers</p> <p>Security researchers report that hackers are actively targeting Linux SSH servers using brute force and credential stuffing attacks. Once inside, attackers deploy malware to maintain persistence and pivot within networks. The attacks primarily target exposed servers with weak credentials or default configurations. System administrators are urged to enforce strong passwords, disable root login over SSH, and implement multi-factor authentication.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/hackers-actively-attacking-linux-ssh-servers/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 6. FBI: Salt Typhoon Campaign Largely Contained in Telecom Networks</p> <p>A top FBI cyber official stated that the Salt Typhoon hacking campaign targeting US telecom networks has been largely contained. The Chinese state-backed group was attempting to exploit vulnerabilities in network infrastructure to conduct espionage activities. Collaborative efforts between telecom companies and government agencies led to detection and mitigation. However, officials warn that vigilance remains critical against similar nation-state threats.</p> <p><a href="https://cyberscoop.com/top-fbi-cyber-official-salt-typhoon-largely-contained-in-telecom-networks/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 7. Cisco Removes Unified CM CallManager Backdoor Root Account</p> <p>Cisco has released an update removing a backdoor root account in its Unified Communications Manager (CallManager) software. The hardcoded credentials could allow attackers to gain root access to the system if exploited. Cisco advises all customers to apply the security update immediately to mitigate potential threats. This discovery highlights the risks of embedded default accounts in enterprise systems.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/cisco-removes-unified-cm-callManager-backdoor-root-account/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 8. Surge of ClickFix Attacks Threatens Corporate Defenses</p> <p>Researchers have observed a sixfold increase in ClickFix attacks, where threat actors exploit web-based support tools to gain unauthorized access. These attacks target organizations’ customer service portals and exploit automated workflows to deploy malicious payloads. Security experts warn that these methods bypass traditional email security defenses. Companies are urged to review web support tool configurations and implement stricter security controls.</p> <p><a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4016208/sixfold-surge-of-clickfix-attacks-threatens-corporate-defenses.html">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 9. DCrat Malware Attacks Windows for Keylogging and Remote Control</p> <p>A new campaign deploying DCrat malware is targeting Windows systems to enable keylogging and full remote control capabilities. Attackers deliver the malware through phishing emails containing malicious attachments or links. Once installed, DCrat allows threat actors to monitor user activity, steal credentials, and execute further commands. Users are advised to remain vigilant against suspicious emails and keep endpoint protection updated.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/dcrat-attack-windows-to-remotely-control-keylogging/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 10. Microsoft Links DNS Issue to Exchange Online OTP Delivery Failures</p> <p>Microsoft has linked recent OTP delivery failures in Exchange Online to an internal DNS issue. The problem caused delays or failures in sending one-time passcodes used for user authentication. Microsoft has implemented a fix and confirmed that the service is now operating normally. Users experiencing lingering issues are advised to retry their operations.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/microsoft/microsoft-links-dns-issue-to-exchange-online-otp-delivery-failures/">Read more</a></p> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[2025-07-04]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2025-07-03</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0703/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 2025-07-03"/><published>2025-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0703</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0703/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-2025-07-03.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <p>Story 1. Microsoft Asks Users to Ignore Windows Firewall Config Errors</p> <p>Microsoft has asked users to ignore Windows Firewall configuration errors that appeared after the recent security updates. The company confirmed these errors are due to a bug in the update process and do not impact actual firewall functionality. A fix is being developed and will be rolled out in upcoming patches. Users are advised not to make manual changes as these warnings are cosmetic.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/microsoft/microsoft-asks-users-to-ignore-windows-firewall-config-errors/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 2. Let’s Encrypt Rolls Out Free ECDSA Certificates</p> <p>Let’s Encrypt has started issuing free ECDSA certificates to improve website performance and security. These certificates use elliptic curve cryptography, offering better efficiency and stronger security compared to traditional RSA certificates. Website owners can now choose ECDSA certificates when generating new SSL certificates through Let’s Encrypt. This move aims to enhance encryption standards across the internet at no additional cost.</p> <p><a href="https://www.theregister.com/2025/07/03/lets_encrypt_rolls_out_free/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 3. Threat Actors Weaponize PDFs to Impersonate Microsoft, DocuSign, Dropbox</p> <p>Cybercriminals are increasingly using weaponized PDF files to impersonate brands like Microsoft, DocuSign, and Dropbox. These PDFs contain phishing links or malware designed to steal user credentials or install malicious payloads. Security researchers warn that these documents often bypass email security filters due to their legitimate appearance. Users are urged to verify PDF senders and avoid opening unexpected attachments.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/threat-actors-weaponize-pdfs-to-impersonate-microsoft-docusign-dropbox/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 4. AI-Generated Phishing Websites Becoming More Sophisticated</p> <p>New research reveals cybercriminals are using AI to generate highly convincing phishing websites. These sites mimic legitimate brands with improved design, language accuracy, and realistic layouts, making them harder to detect. Security experts warn that AI lowers the barrier for attackers to create targeted phishing campaigns at scale. Organizations are advised to enhance user awareness training and detection capabilities against this evolving threat.</p> <p><a href="https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/07/03/ai_phishing_websites/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 5. Hackers Actively Attacking Linux SSH Servers</p> <p>Security researchers report that hackers are actively targeting Linux SSH servers using brute force and credential stuffing attacks. Once inside, attackers deploy malware to maintain persistence and pivot within networks. The attacks primarily target exposed servers with weak credentials or default configurations. System administrators are urged to enforce strong passwords, disable root login over SSH, and implement multi-factor authentication.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/hackers-actively-attacking-linux-ssh-servers/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 6. FBI: Salt Typhoon Campaign Largely Contained in Telecom Networks</p> <p>A top FBI cyber official stated that the Salt Typhoon hacking campaign targeting US telecom networks has been largely contained. The Chinese state-backed group was attempting to exploit vulnerabilities in network infrastructure to conduct espionage activities. Collaborative efforts between telecom companies and government agencies led to detection and mitigation. However, officials warn that vigilance remains critical against similar nation-state threats.</p> <p><a href="https://cyberscoop.com/top-fbi-cyber-official-salt-typhoon-largely-contained-in-telecom-networks/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 7. Cisco Removes Unified CM CallManager Backdoor Root Account</p> <p>Cisco has released an update removing a backdoor root account in its Unified Communications Manager (CallManager) software. The hardcoded credentials could allow attackers to gain root access to the system if exploited. Cisco advises all customers to apply the security update immediately to mitigate potential threats. This discovery highlights the risks of embedded default accounts in enterprise systems.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/cisco-removes-unified-cm-callManager-backdoor-root-account/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 8. Surge of ClickFix Attacks Threatens Corporate Defenses</p> <p>Researchers have observed a sixfold increase in ClickFix attacks, where threat actors exploit web-based support tools to gain unauthorized access. These attacks target organizations’ customer service portals and exploit automated workflows to deploy malicious payloads. Security experts warn that these methods bypass traditional email security defenses. Companies are urged to review web support tool configurations and implement stricter security controls.</p> <p><a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4016208/sixfold-surge-of-clickfix-attacks-threatens-corporate-defenses.html">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 9. DCrat Malware Attacks Windows for Keylogging and Remote Control</p> <p>A new campaign deploying DCrat malware is targeting Windows systems to enable keylogging and full remote control capabilities. Attackers deliver the malware through phishing emails containing malicious attachments or links. Once installed, DCrat allows threat actors to monitor user activity, steal credentials, and execute further commands. Users are advised to remain vigilant against suspicious emails and keep endpoint protection updated.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/dcrat-attack-windows-to-remotely-control-keylogging/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <p>Story 10. Microsoft Links DNS Issue to Exchange Online OTP Delivery Failures</p> <p>Microsoft has linked recent OTP delivery failures in Exchange Online to an internal DNS issue. The problem caused delays or failures in sending one-time passcodes used for user authentication. Microsoft has implemented a fix and confirmed that the service is now operating normally. Users experiencing lingering issues are advised to retry their operations.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/microsoft/microsoft-links-dns-issue-to-exchange-online-otp-delivery-failures/">Read more</a></p> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[2025-07-03]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 7-2-2025</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0702/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 7-2-2025"/><published>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0702</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0702/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-07-02-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="1-qantas-airlines-hit-by-cyberattack">1. Qantas Airlines Hit by Cyberattack</h2> <p>Qantas Airlines has suffered a cyberattack leading to the exposure of sensitive customer data. Hackers reportedly accessed booking details, personal information, and frequent flyer data, raising concerns over potential identity theft. The airline has begun notifying affected customers and is working with cybersecurity experts to investigate the breach. This incident adds to the growing number of attacks targeting the global airline sector in recent months.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/qantas-airlines-cyberattack/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="2-critical-rce-flaw-in-anthropics-mcp-inspector">2. Critical RCE Flaw in Anthropic’s MCP Inspector</h2> <p>A critical remote code execution (RCE) vulnerability has been discovered in Anthropic’s MCP Inspector tool, exposing developer machines to potential attacks. The flaw allows attackers to execute arbitrary commands on affected systems without authentication. Security researchers urge developers using the tool to apply patches immediately to prevent exploitation. This vulnerability highlights the risks associated with widely used development tools when security practices are overlooked.</p> <p><a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4016090/critical-rce-flaw-in-anthropics-mcp-inspector-exposes-developer-machines-to-remote-attacks.html">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="3-vulnerability-in-forminator-wordpress-plugin">3. Vulnerability in Forminator WordPress Plugin</h2> <p>A high-severity vulnerability has been found in the popular Forminator WordPress plugin used for creating forms and quizzes. The flaw allows unauthenticated attackers to upload malicious files, potentially leading to full site compromise. Over 300,000 websites using the plugin are at risk if they do not update to the latest patched version. Security experts recommend immediate updates to prevent exploitation by threat actors scanning for vulnerable WordPress sites.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/forminator-wordpress-plugin-vulnerability/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="4-cl0p-ransomware-exploits-rce-vulnerability-in-moveit">4. Cl0p Ransomware Exploits RCE Vulnerability in MOVEit</h2> <p>Researchers have uncovered that the Cl0p ransomware group is exploiting a remote code execution vulnerability in MOVEit file transfer software. This flaw enables attackers to steal data from targeted organizations and deploy ransomware to encrypt critical files. The vulnerability has been assigned a critical severity score, and organizations using MOVEit are urged to apply patches immediately. This marks another major exploitation campaign by Cl0p targeting enterprise software.</p> <p><a href="https://www.theregister.com/2025/07/02/cl0p_rce_vulnerability/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="5-hacktivist-group-claims-attacks-across-20-critical-sectors">5. Hacktivist Group Claims Attacks Across 20 Critical Sectors</h2> <p>A hacktivist group has claimed responsibility for cyberattacks targeting 20 critical sectors including healthcare, finance, and energy. The group states their motivation is political and aims to disrupt essential services to push their agenda. Security agencies are investigating these claims to assess the validity and scale of the attacks. This campaign highlights the persistent threat of politically motivated cyberattacks against national infrastructure.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/hacktivist-group-claimed-attacks-across-20-critical-sectors/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="6-aeza-group-sanctioned-for-hosting-ransomware-and-infostealer-servers">6. Aeza Group Sanctioned for Hosting Ransomware and Infostealer Servers</h2> <p>The US government has sanctioned Russian internet provider Aeza Group for hosting infrastructure used by ransomware gangs and infostealer operations. Aeza allegedly provided services to cybercriminals distributing malware such as RedLine and Raccoon Stealer. The sanctions aim to disrupt the company’s operations and cut off cybercriminals from reliable hosting services. This move underscores continued efforts to dismantle cybercrime ecosystems by targeting their supporting infrastructure.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/aeza-group-sanctioned-for-hosting-ransomware-infostealer-servers/">Read more</a></p> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[7-02-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 7-1-2025</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0701/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 7-1-2025"/><published>2025-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0701</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0701/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-07-01-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="1-chrome-0-day-vulnerability-exploited">1. Chrome 0-Day Vulnerability Exploited</h2> <p>Google has released an emergency security update for Chrome after discovering a zero-day vulnerability being actively exploited in the wild. The flaw, tracked as <strong>CVE-2025-1234</strong>, is a type confusion bug in the V8 JavaScript engine, allowing attackers to potentially execute arbitrary code. Users are urged to update to the latest version immediately to mitigate this risk. This marks the fifth Chrome zero-day vulnerability patched by Google in 2025 so far.</p> <p><a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/chrome-0-day-vulnerability-exploited/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="2-us-warns-companies-about-north-korean-it-workers">2. US Warns Companies About North Korean IT Workers</h2> <p>The US government has issued a warning about North Korean IT workers infiltrating US companies by posing as freelance developers. These workers aim to generate revenue for North Korea’s weapons programs by securing remote IT contracts under false identities. Authorities caution businesses to thoroughly vet applicants to prevent inadvertent funding of sanctioned entities. This comes as part of broader efforts to counter North Korea’s cyber-enabled revenue generation strategies.</p> <p><a href="https://www.theregister.com/2025/06/30/us_north_korea_workers/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="3-us-warns-of-iranian-cyber-threats-on-critical-infrastructure">3. US Warns of Iranian Cyber Threats on Critical Infrastructure</h2> <p>CISA and the FBI have issued a joint advisory warning US critical infrastructure sectors of increased cyber threats from Iranian hacking groups. These groups are known to exploit publicly exposed vulnerabilities to gain initial access and deploy destructive wiper malware. Organizations are urged to patch systems promptly and enhance their detection capabilities against potential intrusions. The warning highlights the ongoing geopolitical tensions translating into cyber operations against Western infrastructure.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/us-warns-of-iranian-cyber-threats-on-critical-infrastructure/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="4-scattered-spider-targets-airline-sector-in-hacking-spree">4. Scattered Spider Targets Airline Sector in Hacking Spree</h2> <p>The threat group <strong>Scattered Spider</strong> has launched a hacking spree targeting multiple major airlines in the US. Using phishing and social engineering, they gained access to corporate systems, exfiltrating sensitive data including employee information. Security researchers note the group’s advanced social engineering tactics make them particularly dangerous. Airlines are working with law enforcement to contain the breaches and strengthen defenses against further attacks.</p> <p><a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyberattacks-data-breaches/scattered-spider-hacking-spree-airline-sector">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="5-microsoft-defender-now-blocks-email-bombing-attacks">5. Microsoft Defender Now Blocks Email Bombing Attacks</h2> <p>Microsoft has upgraded Defender for Office 365 to block email bombing attacks that flood inboxes with thousands of automated messages. These attacks are used to hide important emails, such as password reset links, under a barrage of junk emails. The new protection automatically detects and filters such bombing campaigns, ensuring legitimate emails remain visible. This feature is part of Microsoft’s efforts to enhance email security and user safety.</p> <p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/microsoft-defender-for-office-365-now-blocks-email-bombing-attacks/">Read more</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="6-europol-dismantles-540-million-online-fraud-network">6. Europol Dismantles $540 Million Online Fraud Network</h2> <p>Europol has dismantled a massive online fraud operation that stole over <strong>540 million euros</strong> from victims across Europe. The criminal network conducted large-scale investment frauds, convincing victims to invest in fake platforms promising high returns. Authorities arrested 37 suspects, froze hundreds of bank accounts, and seized assets including luxury cars and properties. This operation is one of the largest anti-fraud takedowns in recent years.</p> <p><a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/06/europol-dismantles-540-million.html">Read more</a></p> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[7-01-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-25-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0325/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-25-25"/><published>2025-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0325</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0325/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-03-25-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="story-1-11-ways-cybercriminals-are-making-phishing-more-potent-than-ever">Story 1. 11 Ways Cybercriminals Are Making Phishing More Potent Than Ever</h2> <p>Cybercriminals are evolving their phishing techniques by using AI-generated messages, deepfakes, and adaptive lures tailored to specific targets. They’re also exploiting trusted platforms, like LinkedIn and Microsoft Teams, to appear legitimate while deploying malware or stealing credentials. Advanced spoofing methods and real-time phishing kits make these scams harder to detect. Security professionals urge organizations to train employees continuously and use layered email security tools.<br/> <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3850783/11-ways-cybercriminals-are-making-phishing-more-potent-than-ever.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-2-chinese-espionage-hacker-group-isoon-apt-operation-exposed">Story 2. Chinese Espionage Hacker Group “iSoon” APT Operation Exposed</h2> <p>A leak has revealed extensive details about a Chinese state-sponsored hacker group known as iSoon (APT), involved in espionage and cyber intrusions across Asia, Africa, and the Middle East. The group has targeted foreign governments, telecoms, and key infrastructure using custom malware and persistent backdoors. The leak includes internal documents and chat logs, offering rare insight into how state-backed APTs operate. Security analysts are calling this one of the most significant exposures of China’s cyber activities.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyberattacks-data-breaches/chinese-espionage-hacker-group-isoon-apt-operation">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-3-new-vanhelsing-ransomware-targets-windows-arm-and-esxi-systems">Story 3. New VanHelsing Ransomware Targets Windows, ARM, and ESXi Systems</h2> <p>A new ransomware strain named VanHelsing is making headlines for its ability to infect Windows, ARM-based devices, and VMware ESXi servers. This cross-platform malware uses PowerShell scripts and exploits known vulnerabilities to spread rapidly within networks. Security researchers warn that its versatility makes it a growing threat in mixed enterprise environments. Businesses are urged to patch systems, secure hypervisors, and isolate backup infrastructure.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/new-vanhelsing-ransomware-targets-windows-arm-esxi-systems/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-4-critical-ingress-nginx-controller-flaw-could-lead-to-cluster-takeover">Story 4. Critical Ingress NGINX Controller Flaw Could Lead to Cluster Takeover</h2> <p>A critical vulnerability has been discovered in the Ingress NGINX controller for Kubernetes, allowing attackers to potentially gain full control over entire Kubernetes clusters. The flaw enables privilege escalation and unauthorized access through misconfigured annotations. If exploited, it could result in data breaches or total infrastructure compromise. Patches have been released, and organizations are urged to update immediately.<br/> <a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/03/critical-ingress-nginx-controller.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-5-cyberattack-disrupts-ukrainian-state-railways-online-services">Story 5. Cyberattack Disrupts Ukrainian State Railways’ Online Services</h2> <p>Ukraine’s state railway service fell victim to a cyberattack that took down its online ticketing and customer service systems. The incident disrupted public transportation services and delayed digital operations, although physical train services remained operational. Authorities are investigating the origin of the attack, suspected to be politically motivated. This attack highlights the ongoing targeting of Ukraine’s infrastructure amid geopolitical tensions.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/cyberattack-takes-down-ukrainian-state-railways-online-services/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-6-police-arrest-300-suspects-linked-to-african-cybercrime-rings">Story 6. Police Arrest 300 Suspects Linked to African Cybercrime Rings</h2> <p>International law enforcement agencies have arrested over 300 individuals tied to African-based cybercrime groups involved in business email compromise (BEC) and romance scams. The operation, coordinated by Interpol, also led to the seizure of millions in assets and digital evidence. These cybercrime rings have defrauded victims globally by posing as businesses or romantic partners to steal funds. Authorities emphasize the growing global reach of financially motivated threat actors.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/police-arrests-300-suspects-linked-to-african-cybercrime-rings/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-7-microsoft-unveils-ai-powered-security-copilot-agents-and-new-protections">Story 7. Microsoft Unveils AI-Powered Security Copilot Agents and New Protections</h2> <p>Microsoft has introduced Security Copilot Agents—AI-powered assistants designed to automate threat detection, response, and investigation tasks. These agents integrate with Microsoft 365 Defender and Sentinel to provide real-time security insights and recommendations. The update includes advanced AI protections to defend against prompt injection, data leakage, and manipulation in AI-based systems. It reflects Microsoft’s growing focus on securing both traditional IT and AI-driven environments.<br/> <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/security/blog/2025/03/24/microsoft-unveils-microsoft-security-copilot-agents-and-new-protections-for-ai/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-8-microsoft-adds-inline-data-protection-for-copilot-and-ai-features">Story 8. Microsoft Adds Inline Data Protection for Copilot and AI Features</h2> <p>Microsoft is enhancing its Copilot AI platform with new inline data protection tools to help prevent sensitive information leakage. These features offer real-time alerts and restrictions when users attempt to share confidential data via AI-driven workflows. The update also enables security teams to create customized policies for AI data usage. It’s part of a broader push to balance AI innovation with enterprise-grade data governance.<br/> <a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/03/microsoft-adds-inline-data-protection.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-9-chinese-weaver-ant-hackers-spied-on-telecom-networks-for-four-years">Story 9. Chinese “Weaver Ant” Hackers Spied on Telecom Networks for Four Years</h2> <p>A Chinese APT group dubbed “Weaver Ant” has been quietly infiltrating telecom networks across Southeast Asia for the past four years. The attackers used custom malware and compromised routers to intercept communications and extract intelligence. The campaign remained undetected due to the group’s stealthy techniques and use of legitimate credentials. Security researchers call this a textbook example of long-term cyber-espionage targeting critical infrastructure.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/chinese-weaver-ant-hackers-spied-on-telco-network-for-4-years/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-10-draytek-routers-worldwide-affected-by-mysterious-reboot-loop-bug">Story 10. DrayTek Routers Worldwide Affected by Mysterious Reboot Loop Bug</h2> <p>DrayTek routers globally experienced mass reboot loops over the weekend, causing widespread internet disruptions for businesses and individuals. The issue appears to be linked to a firmware bug or a time-based system error, though no official cause has been confirmed yet. DrayTek has released a temporary workaround and is working on a permanent fix. Users are advised to monitor device updates and apply firmware patches as soon as they’re released.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/draytek-routers-worldwide-go-into-reboot-loops-over-weekend/">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[3-25-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-24-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0324/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-24-25"/><published>2025-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0324</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0324/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-03-24-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h1 id="cybersecurity-stories-summary">Cybersecurity Stories Summary</h1> <h2 id="story-1-cloudflare-now-blocks-all-unencrypted-traffic-to-its-api-endpoints">Story 1. Cloudflare Now Blocks All Unencrypted Traffic to Its API Endpoints</h2> <p>Cloudflare has implemented a new security policy that blocks all unencrypted (HTTP) traffic to its API endpoints, enforcing HTTPS-only connections. This move aims to strengthen user data protection and prevent man-in-the-middle attacks that exploit unsecured transmissions. The change could impact older applications or tools that still use HTTP, prompting developers to update their integrations. Cloudflare encourages all users to adopt secure communication protocols going forward.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/cloudflare-now-blocks-all-unencrypted-traffic-to-its-api-endpoints/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-2-fbi-confirms-fake-file-converters-are-actively-pushing-malware">Story 2. FBI Confirms Fake File Converters Are Actively Pushing Malware</h2> <p>The FBI has confirmed that free online file converter websites are being used to distribute malware under the guise of harmless file conversion services. These platforms lure users with promises of converting documents, videos, or images, but secretly deliver spyware and remote access trojans (RATs). Victims unknowingly compromise their systems when downloading the output. Users are advised to stick to trusted software for file conversions and avoid suspicious websites.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/fbi-warnings-are-true-fake-file-converters-do-push-malware/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-3-cybercriminals-exploiting-notification-channels-to-spread-malware">Story 3. Cybercriminals Exploiting Notification Channels to Spread Malware</h2> <p>Hackers are increasingly abusing legitimate notification systems—like browser alerts, push notifications, and mobile pop-ups—to deliver malicious links and social engineering messages. These tactics exploit user trust in seemingly routine system messages, leading to credential theft or malware downloads. The attacks often mimic well-known platforms like Microsoft, Google, or banking apps. Experts advise users to avoid clicking pop-up messages and to access services directly through official apps or websites.<br/> <a href="https://hackread.com/how-cybercriminals-exploit-notification-channels/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-4-microsoft-exchange-online-bug-mistakenly-quarantines-legitimate-emails">Story 4. Microsoft Exchange Online Bug Mistakenly Quarantines Legitimate Emails</h2> <p>A recent bug in Microsoft Exchange Online caused legitimate user emails to be incorrectly flagged and quarantined. The issue affected both internal and external email delivery, frustrating organizations that rely heavily on cloud-based communication. Microsoft has since acknowledged the problem and issued a fix, but not before users reported disruptions to workflow and delayed correspondence. Administrators are urged to review quarantine policies and adjust filtering settings as needed.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/microsoft/microsoft-exchange-online-bug-mistakenly-quarantines-user-emails/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-5-uat-5918-threat-group-targets-critical-infrastructure-in-taiwan">Story 5. UAT-5918 Threat Group Targets Critical Infrastructure in Taiwan</h2> <p>A suspected state-sponsored group identified as UAT-5918 has launched cyberattacks against critical infrastructure in Taiwan, including telecom and energy sectors. The group, believed to be aligned with China, is using advanced persistent threat (APT) tactics to steal sensitive data and establish long-term access. The attacks are part of broader geopolitical tensions and efforts to destabilize key industries. Taiwanese authorities are responding with heightened monitoring and coordinated defense strategies.<br/> <a href="https://securityaffairs.com/175728/hacking/uat-5918-atp-group-targets-critical-taiwan.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-6-hacker-claims-to-have-access-to-6-million-oracle-customer-records">Story 6. Hacker Claims to Have Access to 6 Million Oracle Customer Records</h2> <p>A hacker is claiming responsibility for breaching Oracle and stealing over 6 million customer records, allegedly including sensitive business data and credentials. The individual is offering the stolen data for sale on a dark web forum and has posted samples to prove legitimacy. If true, this breach could have widespread implications for Oracle customers globally. Oracle has denied any confirmed breach, stating it is investigating the claim.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/hacker-claims-6-million-oracle-records/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-7-oracle-denies-breach-after-hacker-offers-6-million-records-for-sale">Story 7. Oracle Denies Breach After Hacker Offers 6 Million Records for Sale</h2> <p>Following the claims of a massive breach, Oracle has issued a public statement denying any evidence of unauthorized access to its systems. The company asserts that internal reviews have not identified any data compromise and continues to investigate the situation. Meanwhile, cybersecurity experts are analyzing the hacker’s data samples for authenticity. Users are advised to remain cautious and monitor their Oracle services for unusual activity.<br/> <a href="https://hackread.com/oracle-denies-breach-hacker-access-6-million-records/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-8-coinbase-was-the-primary-target-in-recent-github-actions-attacks">Story 8. Coinbase Was the Primary Target in Recent GitHub Actions Attacks</h2> <p>Recent breaches involving GitHub Actions have been linked to a campaign targeting Coinbase, with attackers exploiting misconfigured automation workflows. By injecting malicious code into GitHub repositories, the attackers attempted to exfiltrate secrets and steal data from the cryptocurrency platform. Coinbase acted swiftly to mitigate the attack and reported no customer impact. GitHub has advised developers to harden workflow permissions and audit repositories for exposure.<br/> <a href="http://bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/coinbase-was-primary-target-of-recent-github-actions-breaches/">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[3-24-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-21-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0321/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-21-25"/><published>2025-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0321</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0321/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-03-21-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="story-1-cisa-tags-nakivo-backup-flaw-as-actively-exploited-in-attacks">Story 1. CISA Tags NAKIVO Backup Flaw as Actively Exploited in Attacks</h2> <p>The U.S. Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) has issued an alert regarding an actively exploited vulnerability in NAKIVO Backup &amp; Replication software. The flaw allows attackers to gain unauthorized access to backup environments, potentially leading to data theft or ransomware attacks. Threat actors are targeting unpatched instances to disrupt business continuity and compromise stored backups. Organizations using NAKIVO are strongly advised to apply patches immediately and enhance monitoring for suspicious activity.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/cisa-tags-nakivo-backup-flaw-as-actively-exploited-in-attacks/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-2-ukraines-defense-sector-targeted-in-darkcrystal-rat-attack">Story 2. Ukraine’s Defense Sector Targeted in DarkCrystal RAT Attack</h2> <p>Cybersecurity researchers have detected a cyberattack campaign targeting Ukraine’s defense sector using the DarkCrystal Remote Access Trojan (RAT). The malware, attributed to Russian-affiliated hackers, enables full system control, credential theft, and espionage. The attack leverages phishing emails and malicious attachments to infiltrate government networks. Security analysts warn that these cyber operations aim to gather intelligence and disrupt Ukraine’s defense efforts.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyberattacks-data-breaches/ukraine-defense-sector-attack-dark-crystal-rat">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-3-ransomhub-ransomware-uses-new-betruger-multi-function-backdoor">Story 3. RansomHub Ransomware Uses New “Betruger” Multi-Function Backdoor</h2> <p>The RansomHub ransomware gang has introduced a new backdoor named “Betruger,” enabling advanced persistence and stealth in corporate networks. This multi-function backdoor allows cybercriminals to evade detection while stealing data and deploying ransomware. Security researchers note that RansomHub is using more sophisticated tactics, making it harder for organizations to defend against attacks. Experts advise businesses to strengthen endpoint protection and implement proactive threat-hunting measures.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/ransomhub-ransomware-uses-new-betruger-multi-function-backdoor/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-4-veeam-faces-criticism-over-response-to-critical-vulnerability">Story 4. Veeam Faces Criticism Over Response to Critical Vulnerability</h2> <p>Veeam, a leading backup and disaster recovery provider, is facing backlash for its delayed response to a critical vulnerability in its software. Security researchers and industry experts argue that the company failed to act swiftly in addressing the flaw, leaving many organizations exposed to cyber threats. The vulnerability allows unauthorized access to backup environments, making it a prime target for ransomware groups. Users are urged to apply security patches immediately and monitor for suspicious activity.<br/> <a href="https://www.theregister.com/2025/03/20/infoseccers_criticize_veeam_over_critical/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-5-is-it-time-to-retire-one-off-pen-tests-for-continuous-security-testing">Story 5. Is It Time to Retire One-Off Pen Tests for Continuous Security Testing?</h2> <p>Cybersecurity experts are questioning the effectiveness of traditional one-time penetration testing in today’s evolving threat landscape. With cyber threats constantly changing, a shift toward continuous security testing is being advocated to provide real-time insights into vulnerabilities. Continuous testing enables organizations to detect and address weaknesses before attackers can exploit them. Many companies are now integrating automated security solutions and red teaming exercises to enhance their security posture.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/is-it-time-to-retire-one-off-pen-tests-for-continuous-testing/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-6-brand-impersonation-accounts-for-51-of-browser-based-phishing-attacks">Story 6. Brand Impersonation Accounts for 51% of Browser-Based Phishing Attacks</h2> <p>A new study reveals that over half of browser-based phishing attacks rely on brand impersonation, tricking users into believing they are interacting with legitimate companies. Cybercriminals create fake login pages for services like Microsoft 365, PayPal, and banking platforms to steal credentials. These attacks exploit browser vulnerabilities and evade traditional email security filters. Users are urged to verify URLs carefully and enable multi-factor authentication (MFA) to protect their accounts.<br/> <a href="https://www.securitymagazine.com/articles/101485-brand-impersonation-is-51-of-browser-phishing-attempts">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-7-new-steganographic-malware-hides-malicious-code-in-jpeg-files">Story 7. New Steganographic Malware Hides Malicious Code in JPEG Files</h2> <p>A newly discovered malware strain is using steganography to embed malicious payloads inside JPEG image files. This technique allows hackers to evade security tools by hiding malware within seemingly harmless images. Once opened, the malware executes commands that steal data or grant attackers remote access. Security experts advise users to be cautious when downloading images from untrusted sources and to keep their security software updated.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/new-steganographic-malware-exploits-jpeg-files/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-8-how-threat-hunters-enrich-indicators-of-compromise-with-context">Story 8. How Threat Hunters Enrich Indicators of Compromise with Context</h2> <p>Threat-hunting teams are increasingly focusing on contextualizing Indicators of Compromise (IoCs) to improve cybersecurity defenses. By correlating IoCs with attack patterns, security professionals can detect malicious activity earlier and respond more effectively. Advanced threat intelligence tools now integrate machine learning and automation to enhance detection capabilities. Organizations are encouraged to adopt proactive threat-hunting strategies to stay ahead of cyber threats.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/how-threat-hunters-enrich-indicators-with-context/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-9-how-to-protect-your-business-from-cyberattacks">Story 9. How to Protect Your Business from Cyberattacks</h2> <p>A recent cybersecurity guide highlights key strategies businesses can use to defend against modern cyber threats. Recommendations include implementing zero-trust security models, strengthening endpoint protections, and conducting employee security awareness training. As cybercriminals continue to exploit human and technical vulnerabilities, proactive risk management is essential. Organizations are urged to regularly update security policies and invest in advanced threat detection solutions.<br/> <a href="https://thehackernews.com/2025/03/how-to-protect-your-business-from-cyber.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-10-zero-hour-phishing-attacks-exploiting-browser-vulnerabilities">Story 10. Zero-Hour Phishing Attacks Exploiting Browser Vulnerabilities</h2> <p>A wave of zero-hour phishing attacks is targeting browser vulnerabilities, bypassing traditional security measures. These attacks exploit flaws in web browsers to execute malicious scripts that steal user credentials and session tokens. Cybercriminals are using these techniques to gain access to corporate networks and cloud services. Security professionals advise users to keep browsers updated and enable enhanced phishing protection settings.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/zero-hour-phishing-attacks-exploiting-browser-vulnerabilities/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-11-chinese-salt-typhoon-hackers-exploiting-microsoft-exchange-vulnerabilities">Story 11. Chinese “Salt Typhoon” Hackers Exploiting Microsoft Exchange Vulnerabilities</h2> <p>A Chinese state-sponsored hacking group, dubbed “Salt Typhoon,” has been exploiting vulnerabilities in Microsoft Exchange servers to gain persistent access to corporate and government networks. These attacks focus on espionage, data theft, and establishing footholds for future cyber operations. Security researchers warn that unpatched Exchange servers remain prime targets for this threat actor. Organizations are strongly advised to apply security patches and enhance monitoring for unauthorized access attempts.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/chinese-salt-typhoon-hackers-exploiting-exchange-vulnerabilities/">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[3-21-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-20-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0320/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-20-25"/><published>2025-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0320</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0320/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-03-20-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="story-1-phishing-based-attacks-have-risen-140-year-over-year">Story 1. Phishing-Based Attacks Have Risen 140% Year Over Year</h2> <p>A new report highlights a staggering 140% increase in phishing-based attacks compared to the previous year. Cybercriminals are leveraging advanced social engineering tactics, AI-generated messages, and brand impersonation to trick victims into divulging credentials. The financial sector, healthcare, and government agencies have been among the most targeted. Security experts emphasize the importance of user education, multi-factor authentication (MFA), and improved email filtering to mitigate these growing threats.<br/> <a href="https://www.securitymagazine.com/articles/101479-phishing-based-attacks-have-risen-140-year-over-year">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-2-attackers-embedding-malicious-word-files-inside-pdfs-to-evade-detection">Story 2. Attackers Embedding Malicious Word Files Inside PDFs to Evade Detection</h2> <p>Cybercriminals have developed a new attack technique that embeds malicious Microsoft Word files inside PDFs, allowing them to bypass traditional security filters. When victims open the seemingly harmless PDF, the hidden Word document automatically executes malware, granting attackers access to the system. This method effectively evades email security solutions that scan for standalone Word file threats. Users are advised to be cautious when opening unexpected PDF attachments and keep their software updated.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/attackers-embedding-malicious-word-file-into-a-pdf/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-3-threat-actors-exploiting-legacy-drivers-to-evade-security-tools">Story 3. Threat Actors Exploiting Legacy Drivers to Evade Security Tools</h2> <p>Hackers are increasingly exploiting outdated and vulnerable drivers to bypass modern security defenses. Known as Bring Your Own Vulnerable Driver (BYOVD) attacks, this technique allows cybercriminals to disable endpoint detection and response (EDR) systems, gaining deeper access to compromised networks. Security researchers warn that legacy drivers, even if digitally signed, pose a significant threat if left unpatched. Organizations should enforce strict driver policies and use allowlists to prevent unauthorized installations.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/threat-actors-exploiting-legacy-drivers/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-4-microsoft-exchange-online-outage-disrupts-outlook-web-users">Story 4. Microsoft Exchange Online Outage Disrupts Outlook Web Users</h2> <p>Microsoft Exchange Online experienced a major outage, leaving Outlook Web users unable to access their emails. The issue, which lasted several hours, affected customers worldwide, with Microsoft attributing it to an unexpected infrastructure issue. The downtime frustrated businesses and individuals relying on cloud-based email services for daily operations. Microsoft has since restored service and is investigating the root cause to prevent future incidents.<br/> <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/microsoft/microsoft-exchange-online-outage-affects-outlook-web-users/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-5-critical-fortinet-vulnerability-draws-fresh-attention-from-attackers">Story 5. Critical Fortinet Vulnerability Draws Fresh Attention from Attackers</h2> <p>A critical vulnerability in Fortinet’s network security devices has gained renewed interest from cybercriminals looking to exploit unpatched systems. The flaw, which allows remote code execution, could enable attackers to take full control of affected devices. Security experts warn that many organizations have yet to apply the necessary patches, leaving them vulnerable to potential breaches. Fortinet urges all users to update their devices immediately and monitor for suspicious activity.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyberattacks-data-breaches/critical-fortinet-vulnerability-draws-fresh-attention">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[3-20-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-19-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0319/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-19-25"/><published>2025-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0319</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0319/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-03-19-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="story-1-google-acquires-wiz-for-record-32-billion-in-largest-cybersecurity-deal-ever">Story 1. Google Acquires Wiz for Record $32 Billion in Largest Cybersecurity Deal Ever</h2> <p>Google has announced the acquisition of cloud security firm Wiz for a record-breaking $32 billion, making it the largest cybersecurity deal in history. Wiz, known for its advanced cloud-native security platform, helps companies identify and mitigate vulnerabilities across multi-cloud environments. This acquisition strengthens Google Cloud’s security offerings and positions it as a leading player in the cloud security market. Analysts expect this move to intensify competition with Microsoft and AWS in the cybersecurity space.<br/> <a href="https://hackread.com/google-acquires-wiz-for-record-32-billion/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-2-scammers-distribute-ad-fraud-apps-with-60-million-downloads-on-google-play">Story 2. Scammers Distribute Ad Fraud Apps with 60 Million Downloads on Google Play</h2> <p>Security researchers have uncovered a large-scale ad fraud scheme involving dozens of malicious Android apps with over 60 million downloads from Google Play. These apps secretly performed ad fraud in the background, draining user data and device resources while generating illegal revenue for scammers. Google has since removed the fraudulent apps, but many users remain affected. Experts advise Android users to carefully review app permissions and avoid downloading unknown applications.<br/> <a href="https://hackread.com/scammers-ad-fraud-apps-google-play-60m-downloads/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-3-critical-vulnerability-in-ami-megarac-bmc-allows-server-takeover">Story 3. Critical Vulnerability in AMI MegaRAC BMC Allows Server Takeover</h2> <p>A newly disclosed vulnerability in AMI MegaRAC Baseboard Management Controllers (BMC) could allow attackers to take over servers remotely. This critical flaw affects data centers and cloud infrastructure, posing a serious risk to enterprises using the vulnerable technology. Attackers could exploit the flaw to gain root access, disrupt operations, or install persistent backdoors. Organizations are urged to patch affected systems immediately to mitigate the risk of exploitation.<br/> <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3848376/critical-vulnerability-in-ami-megarac-bmc-allows-servers-takeover.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-4-infostealer-malware-attacks-surged-in-2024-flashpoint-report-finds">Story 4. InfoStealer Malware Attacks Surged in 2024, Flashpoint Report Finds</h2> <p>A new report from Flashpoint reveals that infostealer malware attacks surged throughout 2024, with cybercriminals increasingly targeting login credentials, financial data, and personal information. These malware strains, often delivered via phishing campaigns and malicious downloads, have been a primary driver of account takeovers and identity theft. The report highlights how the dark web marketplace for stolen data is fueling cybercrime. Security experts recommend enabling multi-factor authentication (MFA) and using endpoint detection tools to defend against these threats.<br/> <a href="https://cyberscoop.com/infostealers-cybercrime-surged-2024-flashpoint/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-5-nation-state-actors-and-cybercrime-gangs-abusing-malicious-lnk-files">Story 5. Nation-State Actors and Cybercrime Gangs Abusing Malicious LNK Files</h2> <p>Threat intelligence reports indicate that both state-sponsored hackers and cybercriminal gangs are increasingly using malicious LNK (Windows shortcut) files to distribute malware. These files, often disguised as legitimate documents, enable attackers to execute code remotely, steal sensitive information, and establish persistence on compromised systems. Recent campaigns have leveraged this technique for espionage, ransomware, and data exfiltration. Organizations are advised to restrict LNK execution in email attachments and implement strict security controls.<br/> <a href="https://securityaffairs.com/175569/apt/nation-state-actors-and-cybercrime-gangs-abuse-malicious-lnk-files-for-espionage-and-data-theft.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-6-black-basta-ransomware-gangs-leaked-chat-logs-reveal-ties-to-russian-officials">Story 6. Black Basta Ransomware Gang’s Leaked Chat Logs Reveal Ties to Russian Officials</h2> <p>Leaked internal chat logs from the Black Basta ransomware gang suggest connections to Russian government officials. The logs reveal discussions about attack strategies, ransom negotiations, and possible state protection for cybercriminal activities. If confirmed, these findings further link ransomware operations to Russian intelligence services. This leak may provide valuable intelligence for law enforcement agencies investigating ransomware networks.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/threat-intelligence/black-basta-league-russian-officials-chat-logs">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-7-8-year-old-windows-shortcut-zero-day-exploited-in-recent-attacks">Story 7. 8-Year-Old Windows Shortcut Zero-Day Exploited in Recent Attacks</h2> <p>A newly discovered cyberattack campaign is exploiting an 8-year-old zero-day vulnerability in Windows shortcut (LNK) files. Despite Microsoft’s past attempts to mitigate such threats, attackers have found new ways to weaponize the flaw, allowing them to execute malicious code with minimal user interaction. The vulnerability is being actively exploited in targeted attacks against businesses and government entities. Security researchers recommend disabling shortcut execution for untrusted sources and applying available patches.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/8-year-old-windows-shortcut-zero-day/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-8-bybit-hack-a-sophisticated-multi-stage-attack-compromised-cryptocurrency-exchange">Story 8. Bybit Hack: A Sophisticated Multi-Stage Attack Compromised Cryptocurrency Exchange</h2> <p>The recent cyberattack on the Bybit cryptocurrency exchange involved a sophisticated multi-stage intrusion that allowed attackers to steal millions in digital assets. Hackers leveraged social engineering, zero-day exploits, and advanced obfuscation techniques to bypass security measures. Bybit has since tightened its security protocols, but the breach highlights the growing risks for crypto exchanges. Users are advised to enable two-factor authentication and use hardware wallets for enhanced security.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/bybit-hack-sophisticated-multi-stage-attack/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-9-chatgpt-ssrf-bug-becomes-a-favorite-attack-vector-for-hackers">Story 9. ChatGPT SSRF Bug Becomes a Favorite Attack Vector for Hackers</h2> <p>Hackers have quickly adopted a newly discovered Server-Side Request Forgery (SSRF) vulnerability in ChatGPT, exploiting it in real-world attacks. The flaw, CVE-2025-XXXX, allows attackers to manipulate AI-generated responses and access restricted internal services. Cybercriminals are using this technique to extract sensitive data and bypass security measures in AI-integrated platforms. OpenAI and security experts are working on a fix, but organizations using AI-powered applications should monitor for suspicious activity.<br/> <a href="https://securityaffairs.com/175560/hacking/chatgpt-ssrf-bug-quickly-becomes-a-favorite-attack-vector.html">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[3-19-25]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-18-25</title><link href="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0318/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DJBSEC’s CyberNews 3-18-25"/><published>2025-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0318</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://djbsec.github.io/blog/2025/cybernews0318/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <audio src="/assets/audio/news/CyberSecurityNews-03-18-2025.mp3" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="story-1-oauth-attacks-target-microsoft-365-and-github-accounts">Story 1. OAuth Attacks Target Microsoft 365 and GitHub Accounts</h2> <p>Cybercriminals are exploiting OAuth vulnerabilities to compromise Microsoft 365 and GitHub accounts. Attackers use fraudulent third-party applications to trick users into granting excessive permissions, enabling access to sensitive emails, repositories, and cloud resources. Once authorized, these apps can be used for data exfiltration and further phishing attacks. Security experts recommend reviewing OAuth app permissions regularly and restricting access to trusted applications only.<br/> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/oauth-attacks-target-microsoft-365-github">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-2-new-steganographic-malware-attack-hides-code-inside-jpg-files">Story 2. New Steganographic Malware Attack Hides Code Inside JPG Files</h2> <p>A newly discovered steganographic malware campaign is using image files to conceal malicious payloads. Attackers embed malware within seemingly harmless JPG images, which execute code when opened on a compromised device. This method allows cybercriminals to evade traditional antivirus detection while delivering remote access trojans (RATs) or keyloggers. Users are advised to avoid downloading images from untrusted sources and keep their security software updated.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/new-steganographic-malware-attack-via-jpg-file/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-3-chinese-volt-typhoon-hackers-exploiting-cisco-and-netgear-routers">Story 3. Chinese Volt Typhoon Hackers Exploiting Cisco and Netgear Routers</h2> <p>The Chinese state-sponsored hacking group Volt Typhoon has been observed exploiting vulnerabilities in Cisco and Netgear routers. These compromised devices are being used as stepping stones for cyber-espionage campaigns targeting critical infrastructure. By hijacking consumer and enterprise networking equipment, the attackers can evade detection and establish persistent access. Security experts recommend updating router firmware and disabling remote management features.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/chinese-volt-typhoon-hackers-exploiting-cisco-netgear-routers/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-4-attackers-use-css-to-create-evasive-phishing-messages">Story 4. Attackers Use CSS to Create Evasive Phishing Messages</h2> <p>A new phishing technique leverages Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) to evade email security filters and trick users into revealing credentials. By embedding malicious payloads in CSS files, attackers can create emails that bypass spam detection while appearing legitimate. This method makes phishing campaigns harder to detect and block. Experts advise users to verify email senders, avoid clicking on suspicious links, and enable multi-factor authentication (MFA).<br/> <a href="https://securityaffairs.com/175512/security/attackers-use-css-to-create-evasive-phishing-messages.html">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-5-23000-github-repositories-targeted-in-large-scale-supply-chain-attack">Story 5. 23,000 GitHub Repositories Targeted in Large-Scale Supply Chain Attack</h2> <p>A massive cyberattack campaign has targeted over 23,000 GitHub repositories, injecting malicious code into open-source projects. The attackers use dependency hijacking and repository takeover techniques to compromise software supply chains. Developers who unknowingly use infected dependencies may expose their applications to backdoors and data breaches. Security professionals recommend verifying package integrity and implementing strict repository security controls.<br/> <a href="https://cybersecuritynews.com/23000-github-repositories-targeted/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-6-toll-road-text-message-scam-spreads-nationwide">Story 6. Toll Road Text Message Scam Spreads Nationwide</h2> <p>A phishing scam disguised as toll road payment notifications has been spreading rapidly across the U.S. Victims receive fraudulent text messages claiming they owe unpaid tolls, leading them to fake payment portals that steal financial details. Authorities warn that these scams are highly sophisticated and designed to mimic official transportation agencies. Drivers are advised to verify toll charges through official state websites and never click on unsolicited payment links.<br/> <a href="https://cyberscoop.com/toll-road-text-message-scam-swells-nationwide-how-to-stop/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-7-hackers-exploit-chatgpt-vulnerability-cve-2024-27564-in-10000-attacks">Story 7. Hackers Exploit ChatGPT Vulnerability CVE-2024-27564 in 10,000 Attacks</h2> <p>Threat actors have been exploiting a newly disclosed vulnerability, CVE-2024-27564, in ChatGPT-related APIs, enabling them to conduct over 10,000 attacks. This security flaw allows attackers to manipulate AI-generated responses, steal user data, and bypass content restrictions. Organizations integrating AI services are at risk of data leakage and misinformation attacks. Security experts recommend applying patches immediately and monitoring AI interactions for suspicious activity.<br/> <a href="https://hackread.com/hackers-exploit-chatgpt-cve-2024-27564-10000-attacks/">Read more here</a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="story-8-free-online-file-converters-are-installing-malware-on-users-devices">Story 8. Free Online File Converters Are Installing Malware on Users’ Devices</h2> <p>Security researchers have found that many free online file conversion tools are secretly installing malware on users’ devices. These fraudulent sites trick users into uploading files for conversion while delivering hidden malware payloads in return. The malware includes spyware, keyloggers, and adware that compromise system security. Users are encouraged to use trusted software for file conversions and avoid suspicious websites.<br/> <a href="https://www.malwarebytes.com/blog/news/2025/03/warning-over-free-online-file-converters-that-actually-install-malware">Read more here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><category term="CyberNews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[3-18-25]]></summary></entry></feed>